[{"content":"The SFC announced today that it had suspended the registration of Mr Cheung Sai Leung (Cheung), a securities dealing director and Ms Mak Yuen Yee, Selina (Mak), a dealer's representative of TIS Taiwan International Securities (HK) Limited (TIS) for 8 months and 2 months respectively under section 56 of the Securities Ordinance. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[69,85,"PERSON"],[87,93,"PERSON"],[133,153,"PERSON"],[155,158,"PERSON"],[190,238,"ORG"],[240,243,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The suspensions stemmed from an investigation in which it was found that during 16 December 1998 and 31 March 1999, Cheung and Mak had knowingly facilitated two former staff members of another registered intermediary (Intermediary \"A\"] in conducting improper trading activities in 10 derivative warrants listed on the Stock Exchange of Kong Kong Limited. Cheung had provided accounts of nine of Mak's clients at TIS to the two staff members of Intermediary \"A\" to trade the warrants. The orders placed to Cheung and Mak and executed by them involved the selling and repurchase of warrants to and from these accounts and wash sales through TIS and other Hong Kong brokers and resulted in there being few trades in these warrants other than those generated by the two staff members of Intermediary \"A\". Such activities had also led to a distortion of the interest in these warrants as they created an impression that there was a greater interest in these warrants than there actually was.","entities":[[116,122,"PERSON"],[127,130,"PERSON"],[318,353,"ORG"],[355,361,"PERSON"],[395,398,"PERSON"],[505,511,"PERSON"],[516,519,"PERSON"],[639,642,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concluded that the above findings impugned the fitness and properness of Cheung and Mak as registered persons. In deciding on this action, the SFC took into account that:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[81,87,"PERSON"],[92,95,"PERSON"],[151,154,"ORG"]]},{"content":"both Cheung and Mak have admitted their involvement in these matters and have fully co-operated and assisted with the SFC's investigation;","entities":[[5,11,"PERSON"],[16,19,"PERSON"],[118,121,"ORG"]]},{"content":"neither Cheung nor Mak profited from their actions; and","entities":[[8,14,"PERSON"],[19,22,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mak was under Cheung's supervision at TIS and reported to him.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[14,20,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has revoked the licence of Mr Edmond Leung Chi Keung and banned him from re-entering the industry for 10 years from 11 July 2012 to 10 July 2022 (Note 1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[74,96,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC’s disciplinary action follows a finding by the Market Misconduct Tribunal (MMT) that Leung, together with Mr David Tsien, a former equity salesman of JP Morgan Securities (Asia Pacific) Ltd (JP Morgan) and Mr Steve Luk, a former fund manager of JF Asset Management Ltd, had engaged in insider dealing in the shares of China Overseas Land and Investment Ltd (COLI) (Note 2 and 3).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[55,81,"ORG"],[83,86,"ORG"],[93,98,"PERSON"],[117,128,"PERSON"],[158,197,"ORG"],[199,208,"ORG"],[217,226,"PERSON"],[253,276,"ORG"],[326,364,"ORG"],[366,370,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Subsequent to the commencement of the SFC’s disciplinary action, Leung obtained leave to appeal to the Court of Appeal against the finding made against him by the MMT. In April 2012, the Court of Appeal dismissed Leung’s appeal and reaffirmed the MMT’s finding. The SFC’s disciplinary action, which was put on hold pending the outcome of Leung’s appeal, was reactivated following the judgment handed down by the Court of Appeal (Note 4).","entities":[[38,41,"ORG"],[65,70,"PERSON"],[103,118,"ORG"],[163,166,"ORG"],[187,202,"ORG"],[213,218,"PERSON"],[247,250,"ORG"],[266,269,"ORG"],[338,343,"PERSON"],[412,427,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had successfully prosecuted Mr. Lo Yiu Man (Lo) for manipulating the turnover of Process Automation (Holdings) Limited (PAL) which is now known as Asia Tele-Net and Technology Corporation Limited. Lo pleaded guilty before Ms. Polly Lo at Western Magistracy in relation to creating a false and misleading appearance of active trading in the shares of PAL between 25 August 1999 and 2 September 1999 (the relevant period). Lo was fined $45,000 and ordered to pay costs of $31,343 to the SFC. ","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[100,110,"PERSON"],[112,114,"PERSON"],[149,186,"ORG"],[188,191,"ORG"],[215,263,"ORG"],[265,267,"PERSON"],[294,302,"PERSON"],[418,421,"ORG"],[489,491,"PERSON"],[553,556,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC investigation identified that during the relevant period Lo had sold tranches of PAL shares at discounted prices on 9 occasions only to immediately commence buying back similar quantities at prices higher than his disposal prices. This “sell-low-buy-high” strategy was designed to push up the price of PAL shares. However, although Lo’s activity had little effect on the price of PAL shares it did have the effect of creating a false and misleading appearance of active trading in the shares of PAL during the relevant period, in contravention of S.135[1)(a) of the Securities Ordinance.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[65,67,"PERSON"],[89,92,"ORG"],[310,313,"ORG"],[340,342,"PERSON"],[388,391,"ORG"],[503,506,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced that on 16 September 1999 it had publicly reprimanded {X}, a registered dealer under the Securities Ordinance (SO), in respect of his conduct whilst a dealing director of Pacific Foundation Securities Limited, a company with which he is no longer associated.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[225,262,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC conducted an inquiry under S56 of the SO which revealed that between 1 April 1995 to 22 February 1996, {X} was negligent in his duties in that he allowed a share trading account to be opened but failed to take reasonable steps to establish the full and true identity of the client contrary to Clause 5.1 of the Commission’s \"Code of Conduct for Persons Registered with the Securities and Futures Commission\". In addition, {X} had allowed unauthorised persons to operate this account, thereby both exposing the account holder to risks and liabilities it may not have chosen to assume and the company to potential liabilities in the event of dispute or default.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[319,329,"ORG"],[381,414,"ORG"]]},{"content":"A SFC spokesman said that {X}’s misconduct impugned his fitness and properness as a registered dealer and a public reprimand was appropriate.","entities":[[2,5,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has severely reprimanded Phillip Securities (HK) Limited. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[33,64,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has noted a substantial number of incidents involving representatives of Phillip in the past three years, including client complaints and matters Phillip itself reported to the SFC. As a result of our investigation into those incidents, we have taken no fewer than 11 separate disciplinary actions against Phillip’s representatives resulting in sanctions ranging from revocations, suspensions to reprimands. In July 2000, the SFC also conducted a review of Phillip’s operations. Afterwards, Phillip agreed to engage an independent accounting firm to conduct a comprehensive review of its internal control systems.     ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[81,88,"ORG"],[185,188,"ORG"],[314,321,"ORG"],[465,472,"ORG"],[499,506,"ORG"],[434,437,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The reviews found that substantial deficiencies had existed in Phillip’s internal control systems for a long period of time. This had made it easier for Phillip’s staff to commit misconduct to the detriment of its clients’ interests. These deficiencies included:","entities":[[63,70,"ORG"],[153,160,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concludes that the fitness and properness of Phillip has been seriously called into question.   ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[53,60,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In deciding the penalty, the SFC has taken into account that Phillip has rectified the internal control weaknesses identified during the reviews and devoted a considerable amount of resources to doing so. It therefore decides that a severe public reprimand is appropriate in the circumstances. ","entities":[[29,32,"ORG"],[61,68,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Weak internal controls in a brokerage put the broker’s clients and the broker itself at risk. They may facilitate employees’ misconduct that prejudices clients’ interests. We will not tolerate firms with poor internal controls. If this case were to be dealt with under the Securities and Futures Ordinance, we would have considered imposing a fine and other new sanctions.” ","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Phillip is a licensed corporation under the Securities and Futures Ordinance.","entities":[[0,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Appeal Committee of the Court of Final Appeal (CFA) today dismissed the application of Mr Andrew Left of Citron Research for leave to further appeal to the CFA against the February 2019 judgment of the Court of Appeal (CA) that ruled against him.","entities":[[28,49,"ORG"],[51,54,"ORG"],[94,105,"PERSON"],[109,124,"ORG"],[160,163,"ORG"],[206,221,"ORG"],[223,225,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In August 2016, the Market Misconduct Tribunal (MMT) found that Left was culpable of market misconduct in the publication of a report on Evergrande Real Estate Group Limited in June 2012.  The MMT imposed several orders on Left, including a “cold shoulder” order banning him from trading securities in Hong Kong for five years (Note 2).","entities":[[20,46,"ORG"],[48,51,"ORG"],[64,68,"PERSON"],[137,173,"ORG"],[193,196,"ORG"],[223,227,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Left’s appeal against the determinations of the MMT on points of law was dismissed by the CA in February 2019 (Note 3).  His application to the CA for leave to appeal to the CFA was also dismissed on 24 May 2019 (Note 4).","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[48,51,"ORG"],[90,92,"ORG"],[144,146,"ORG"],[174,177,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded GC Capital under the Securities and Futures Ordinance.  ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,34,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The public reprimand is made according to a settlement agreement. Parties to the agreement include the SFC, GC Capital and its responsible officer, Mr Lau Wang Yip, Derrick (Note 1).","entities":[[103,106,"ORG"],[108,118,"ORG"],[151,172,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The reprimand stems from SFC’s investigation into irregularities in the listing of the shares of Codebank Limited on the Growth Enterprise Market of the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited in December 2001. GC Capital was one of the underwriters to the Codebank listing.","entities":[[25,28,"ORG"],[97,113,"ORG"],[153,188,"ORG"],[207,217,"ORG"],[253,261,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC investigation revealed that an oral agreement had been made which was subsequently confirmed in writing by GC Capital, Codebank and the Lead Manager  to vary the payment arrangement specified under the underwriting agreement. Instead of paying the subscription proceeds to GC Capital, the placees procured by GC Capital were instructed to pay Codebank directly.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[115,125,"ORG"],[127,135,"ORG"],[281,291,"ORG"],[317,327,"ORG"],[351,359,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC found that, by changing the payment arrangement, GC Capital was not able to discharge its duty to identify potentially suspicious transactions under paragraph 4.4 of the Money Laundering Guidance Notes Issued By The SFC. GC Capital also failed to recognise that it had a duty to know its clients and permitted a placee who earned about $5,000 a month to subscribe for $10 million worth of Codebank shares.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[57,67,"ORG"],[224,227,"ORG"],[229,239,"ORG"],[397,405,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Lau was GC Capital’s dealing director at the relevant time. Lau entered into the settlement agreement with the SFC with no admission of liability. Lau has agreed to refrain from carrying out any regulated functions and acting as a responsible officer for a period of one month, effective from 15 November 2004 to 14 December 2004 (both dates inclusive).","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[8,18,"ORG"],[60,63,"PERSON"],[111,114,"ORG"],[147,150,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Eastern Magistrates’ Court today convicted DBA Telecommunication (Asia) Holdings Limited (DBA) after it pleaded guilty to making a false or misleading statement in a prosecution brought by the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) (Notes 1 & 2).","entities":[[47,92,"ORG"],[94,97,"ORG"],[197,230,"ORG"],[232,235,"ORG"]]},{"content":"DBA was fined $20,000 and ordered to pay the SFC’s investigation costs.","entities":[[0,3,"ORG"],[45,48,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On 28 March 2013, DBA published results announcement for the year ended 31 December 2012 on the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited’s (SEHK) website.","entities":[[18,21,"ORG"],[96,131,"ORG"],[135,139,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleges that the financial statements had not been agreed by the auditors as required under the Rules Governing the Listing of Securities on the SEHK (the Listing Rules).  DBA’s statement in the results announcement that the financial statements had complied with the applicable disclosure provisions of the Listing Rules was therefore false and misleading in a material particular.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[153,157,"ORG"],[180,183,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC also prosecuted DBA’s former director Mr Chan Wai Chuen for making a false or misleading statement for his alleged involvement in the offence.  The case was adjourned until 9 August 2018 when plea will be taken.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,27,"ORG"],[49,63,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC has successfully prosecuted Mr Ha But Yee for short selling a warrant with stock name SG-CMOB@EC0404.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[39,49,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"An SFC investigation found that between 17 October and 11 November 2003, Ha sold SG-CMOB@EC0404 through four accounts under his control while knowing that he and the account holders did not have any unit of warrant on hand, in contravention of Section 170 of the Securities and Futures Ordinance. Section 170[1) prohibits the sale of securities when the person does not have a presently exercisable and unconditional right to sell them.","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[73,75,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Ha pleaded guilty today before Mr Anthony Yuen, a Magistrate at Eastern Magistracy, to sixteen summonses in relation to his short selling of securities. He was fined a total of $64,000 and ordered to pay investigation costs of $20,952 to the SFC.","entities":[[34,46,"PERSON"],[0,2,"PERSON"],[64,82,"ORG"],[242,245,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Market Misconduct Tribunal (MMT) today fined Mayer Holdings Limited (Mayer) and nine of its current and former senior executives a total of $10.2 million after they were found to have failed to disclose inside information as soon as reasonably practicable as required under the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO)  (Notes 1 & 2).","entities":[[4,30,"ORG"],[32,35,"ORG"],[49,71,"ORG"],[73,78,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The MMT also imposed disqualification orders against the nine current and former senior executives of Mayer: former chairman and executive director, Mr Hsiao Ming-chih; former company secretary and financial controller, Mr Tommy Chan Lai Yin; former executive directors, Mr Lai Yueh-hsing, Mr Chiang Jen-Chin and Mr Xue Wenge; former independent non-executive directors, Mr Huang Jui-hsiang, Mr Lin Sheng-bin and Mr Alvin Chiu; and current non-executive director, Mr Li Deqiang.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[102,107,"ORG"],[152,167,"PERSON"],[223,241,"PERSON"],[274,288,"PERSON"],[293,308,"PERSON"],[316,325,"PERSON"],[374,390,"PERSON"],[395,408,"PERSON"],[416,426,"PERSON"],[467,477,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Tommy Chan and Lai Yueh-hsing, who were fined $1.5 million each, were disqualified by the MMT from being a director or being involved in the management of a listed corporation or any other specified corporation for 20 months (Notes 3 & 4).   ","entities":[[0,10,"PERSON"],[15,29,"PERSON"],[90,93,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The MMT further ordered that:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Mayer and the nine current and former senior executives pay the SFC’s investigation and legal costs, as well as the costs of the MMT proceedings;","entities":[[3,8,"ORG"],[67,70,"ORG"],[132,135,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Mayer appoint a SFC-approved independent professional adviser to review its procedures for compliance with the corporate disclosure regime; and","entities":[[3,8,"ORG"],[19,22,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- the nine current and former senior executives attend a SFC-approved training programme on the corporate disclosure regime, directors’ duties and corporate governance.","entities":[[58,61,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded {X}, a licensed representative of South China Securities Limited and South China Commodities Limited. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[58,88,"ORG"],[93,124,"ORG"]]},{"content":"allowed three of his clients’ accounts at South China Securities to be operated by a third party, namely Mr Leung Cheuk Ho, without making proper inquiry as to whether Leung was authorised by the clients; and","entities":[[42,64,"ORG"],[108,122,"PERSON"],[168,173,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"failed to report the activities of Leung, whom {X} knew was also a person licensed by the SFC, to South China Securities and thus the firm was unable to seek written consent from Leung’s employer.","entities":[[35,40,"PERSON"],[90,93,"ORG"],[98,120,"ORG"],[179,184,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"paragraph 7.1(a)(i) of the Code of Conduct for Persons Licensed by or Registered with the SFC, which prohibits brokers from effecting a transaction for a client without authorisation; and","entities":[[90,93,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concludes that {X}’s fitness and properness as a licensed person has been called into question and decides to reprimand him. The SFC has taken into account that {X} was suspended by South China Securities for one month for his failures.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[137,140,"ORG"],[190,212,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Licensed persons should take steps to ensure that a third party is duly authorised before accepting the third party’s instructions to operate clients’ accounts. The lax attitude adopted by {X} in this matter is unacceptable. {X}’s failure to report to South China the activities of the third party deprived the third party’s employer of an opportunity to monitor the activities of its staff. {X}’s actions fell short of the standard required of a licensed representative.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"],[317,328,"ORG"]]},{"content":"“Had {X} not already been suspended by South China for one month for his failures, the SFC would have imposed a stiffer penalty on him for his misconduct,” Mr Linning said.","entities":[[39,50,"ORG"],[87,90,"ORG"],[159,166,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has banned Mr Aaron Ko Wai Lun from re-entering the industry for 10 years from 24 September 2009 to 23 September 2019 following a referral by the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) (Note 1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[58,74,"PERSON"],[190,218,"ORG"],[220,224,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On the evidence gathered by HKMA, the SFC found that Ko:","entities":[[28,32,"ORG"],[38,41,"ORG"],[53,55,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"effected two investment transactions involving over $3.5 million in the investment account of a client at Hang Seng Bank Ltd (HSB) without the client’s knowledge and authorization on 11 July 2007;","entities":[[106,124,"ORG"],[126,129,"ORG"]]},{"content":"deceived his former employer HSB by preparing and providing false information on bank documents, including two order forms for investment products and a Risk Profiling Questionnaire (RPQ), purported to have contained information about the client, all dated 11 July 2007;","entities":[[29,32,"ORG"]]},{"content":"asked the client to lie to HSB that the client had authorized him to conduct the relevant transactions, with a view to concealing his misconduct.","entities":[[27,30,"ORG"]]},{"content":"As a result of Ko’s wrongdoings, HSB has compensated the client by reversing the relevant transactions in the client’s account.","entities":[[15,17,"PERSON"],[33,36,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has suspended the licence of Mr Ho Kai Yin for six months from 14 January 2011 to 13 July 2011 (Note 1) for breaching the SFC’s Code of Conduct (Note 2) and his employer’s staff dealing policy.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[76,86,"PERSON"],[166,169,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The disciplinary action follows an SFC investigation which found that Ho:","entities":[[35,38,"ORG"],[70,72,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In deciding upon the penalty, the SFC has taken into consideration Ho cooperated with the SFC, admitted his misconduct and has an otherwise clean disciplinary record.","entities":[[67,69,"PERSON"],[90,93,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded Ms Lau Yin Mei Carmela and fined her $53,000 for short selling and other misconduct (Note 1). This is the result of a settlement between Lau and the SFC.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[27,46,"PERSON"],[161,164,"PERSON"],[173,176,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The disciplinary proceedings stemmed from an SFC inquiry in which Lau, a licensed representative of Guotai Junan Securities (Hong Kong) Limited at the material time, was found to have confirmed to the client that she had purchased 3 million shares of a stock on 15 October 2003 when in fact the order had not yet been completed. At the time she confirmed the purchase order, Lau was uncertain as to whether the shares could be delivered. Guotai Junan was unable to deliver the shares to Lau’s client.","entities":[[45,48,"ORG"],[66,69,"PERSON"],[100,143,"ORG"],[375,378,"PERSON"],[438,450,"ORG"],[487,490,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Lau also failed to take heed of an advice given by a dealing director of Guotai Junan not to confirm the purchase order until the shares were delivered.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[73,85,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On 16 October 2003, the client, believing that it had purchased the shares, instructed Lau to sell part of the shares. While knowing that the shares had not yet been delivered to Guotai Junan, Lau sold 350,000 shares for the client, which was a short sale in breach of section 170 of the Securities and Futures Ordinance.","entities":[[87,90,"PERSON"],[179,191,"ORG"],[193,196,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC concludes that Lau has been guilty of misconduct and her fitness and properness has been called into question.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,26,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In settling its disciplinary action and deciding the level of fine, the SFC has considered the Disciplinary Fining Guidelines (Note 2) and all the circumstances of the case, including the fact that Lau:","entities":[[72,75,"ORG"],[198,201,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"put the client and Guotai Junan at risk of litigation and financial loss due to the failure in the delivery of the shares purchased for the client;","entities":[[19,31,"ORG"]]},{"content":"co-operated with the SFC’s investigation;","entities":[[21,24,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC considers the settlement to be in the interest of the investing public and in the public interest. The SFC will pay the sum to the government revenue.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[111,114,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “It is paramount that licensed persons ensure that they do not short sell as it may constitute a criminal offence. Lau should not have confirmed the order, in light of her knowledge that the shares were not yet delivered.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"],[179,182,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC has suspended the licence of Mr Wong Kwok Fan Rico for five weeks, from 28 April 2005 to 1 June 2005 (both dates inclusive) for account opening failings and aiding and abetting unlicensed dealing. The action follows a decision of the Securities and Futures Appeals Tribunal (SFAT).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[40,58,"PERSON"],[242,281,"ORG"],[283,287,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Wong was a securities dealer’s representative and a commodity dealer’s representative and currently holds a full licence as a licensed representative (Note 1).","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Following an investigation, the SFC found that Wong had breached General Principle 2 and paragraph 5.1 of the Code of Conduct for Persons Licensed by or Registered with the SFC (Code of Conduct).","entities":[[32,35,"ORG"],[173,176,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Wong certified that he had explained the risk disclosure statement to a client during account opening but in fact he had not.  Wong did not know the client at the time of the account opening. ","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[127,131,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Wong also admitted in a SFC interview that he had rebated commission to a person who was engaged in unregistered dealings, hence facilitating the latter’s illegal activity (Note 2).","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[24,27,"ORG"]]},{"content":"As a result of the above findings, the SFC concludes that Wong has been guilty of misconduct and that his fitness and properness has been called into question.","entities":[[39,42,"ORG"],[58,62,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC decided to suspend Wong’s licence for two months.  Wong appealed to the SFAT against the SFC’s decision.  The SFAT affirmed the SFC’s decision to suspend Wong and made it plain that a reprimand is not sufficient for the infraction.  However, the SFAT considered that there were extraordinary circumstances which afford Wong a greater degree of leniency and reduced the suspension to five weeks.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[59,63,"PERSON"],[80,84,"ORG"],[97,100,"ORG"],[118,122,"ORG"],[136,139,"ORG"],[162,166,"PERSON"],[254,258,"ORG"],[327,331,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Witnessing documents to say that documents have been explained to a client whom he had not met is improper and warrants suspension.  This has been aggravated by rebating commission to an unlicensed person thus facilitating unlicensed dealing.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has commenced proceedings in the Court of First Instance against Ernst & Young Hong Kong (Ernst & Young) for failing to produce to the SFC specified accounting records.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[77,100,"ORG"],[109,132,"ORG"],[134,147,"ORG"],[179,182,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The records relate to its work as the reporting accountant and auditor for Standard Water Limited (Standard Water) (Note 1).","entities":[[75,97,"ORG"],[99,113,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC issued a formal notice to Ernst & Young seeking the audit working papers and underlying accounting documents relating to Standard Water. Ernst & Young did not comply with this request and claimed that it did not have the relevant records which were held in the Mainland by its joint venture partner in the Mainland, Ernst & Young Hua Ming (EY Hua Ming), whose staff were the ones involved in the engagement.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[34,47,"ORG"],[129,143,"ORG"],[145,158,"ORG"],[324,346,"ORG"],[348,359,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On following up the non-compliance, Ernst & Young then claimed the documents could not be produced because of restrictions under PRC law (Note 2).","entities":[[36,49,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC then sought the assistance of the relevant authority in the Mainland using its standing arrangements for mutual assistance in investigatory matters. However, EY Hua Ming also failed to produce the records to the relevant Mainland authority as requested.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[166,177,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Given Ernst & Young was the reporting accountant and EY Hua Ming was Ernst & Young’s agent, the failure to produce these records to the relevant Mainland authority on the SFC’s request is a matter of serious concern.","entities":[[6,19,"ORG"],[53,64,"ORG"],[69,82,"ORG"],[171,174,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Accounting and audit working papers relating to private companies applying for listing in Hong Kong must be capable of being produced either directly to the SFC or via the relevant Mainland authority under the standing arrangements for cooperation, especially where the SFC is investigating suspected misconduct.","entities":[[157,160,"ORG"],[270,273,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC is invoking section 185 of the Securities and Futures Ordinance which empowers the Court of First Instance to inquire into the circumstances of Ernst & Young’s non-compliance with the SFC’s request for these records. The Court can order Ernst & Young to comply with the SFC’s request if it is satisfied that Ernst & Young does not have any reasonable excuse for not complying.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[91,114,"ORG"],[152,165,"ORG"],[192,195,"ORG"],[229,234,"ORG"],[245,258,"ORG"],[278,281,"ORG"],[316,329,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has brought this proceeding after consulting the relevant Mainland authority about access to these records and the SFC and the relevant Mainland authority are continuing to work closely together in relation to this issue.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[123,126,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded KGI Asia Limited.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,40,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The reprimand follows an inquiry in which the SFC found that KGI had allowed its staff to engage in securities dealing whilst unregistered. The unregistered dealing activities were made possible by KGI’s lax internal control over the management of its branch offices.","entities":[[46,49,"ORG"],[61,64,"ORG"],[198,201,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC found that KGI had failed to employ any staff to supervise the operation of two of its branch offices for several months in 2000, exposing the firm itself to management risk. When KGI did employ a manager to supervise one of the branch offices, the manager was inexperienced and insufficiently trained. There was confusion as to the supervisory role of the manager because there was no clear delineation of responsibilities. As a result, an unregistered staff member engaged in securities dealing (Note 1). Though KGI’s directors made regular visits to the branch office, the unregistered activities were undetected due to poor diligence.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[19,22,"ORG"],[188,191,"ORG"],[522,525,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC further found that there was insufficient control of trading limits at that branch office due to an unclear division of duty in this area. Trading often exceeded the limits in two clients’ accounts and KGI was exposed to unnecessary financial risks. Further, account executives were given latitude in the control of the trading limits based on their own risk assessment, which lacked uniformity, objectivity and supervision. When an automatic interdiction system was later installed to prevent trading over limits, it still allowed manual circumvention.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concludes that KGI has been guilty of misconduct and that its fitness and properness has been called into question. It therefore decides that a public reprimand is appropriate in the circumstances.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,26,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: \"Lax internal controls in a brokerage put the clients and the firm itself at risk. They facilitate employees’ misconduct that prejudices the interests of both the clients and the firm. We will not tolerate firms with poor internal controls. If this case were to be dealt with under the Securities and Futures Ordinance, we would have considered imposing a fine and other new sanctions.\"","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"]]},{"content":"KGI is a licensed corporation under the Securities and Futures Ordinance.","entities":[[0,3,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC announces today that it has successfully prosecuted {X} of Asia Aluminum Holdings Limited (Asia Aluminum), under the Securities (Disclosure of Interests) Ordinance (SDIO). ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[67,97,"ORG"],[99,112,"ORG"]]},{"content":"{X} pleaded guilty to one summons relating to his failure to report to the Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEx) his interest in 1,668,000 shares of Asia Aluminum within five business days following the date of his appointment as a director on 14 June 2001 as required under the SDIO. {X} did not notify the HKEx of his interest until 11 September 2001, a delay of 67 days.","entities":[[75,115,"ORG"],[117,121,"ORG"],[159,172,"ORG"],[318,322,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Ms Polly Lo, a Magistrate at Western Magistracy, fined {X} a total of $5,000 and ordered him to pay costs of $11,696 to the SFC.","entities":[[3,11,"PERSON"],[29,47,"ORG"],[124,127,"ORG"]]},{"content":"An SFC spokesman reminds newly appointed directors of listed companies of their obligations to disclose their interests in the shares of those listed companies to the HKEx and the companies within five business days following the date of appointment as directors.","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[167,171,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (\"SFC\"] and The Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited (the \"Exchange\"] jointly announce today that they had taken action against CAF Securities Company Limited (\"CAF\"], a securities dealer and a Member of the Exchange, and against its Dealing Director, Mr Lee Wah Kin (\"Lee\"]. The SFC has also taken action against CAF's former director, {X}.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[40,43,"ORG"],[50,89,"ORG"],[96,104,"ORG"],[165,195,"ORG"],[198,201,"ORG"],[245,253,"ORG"],[292,303,"PERSON"],[306,309,"PERSON"],[317,320,"ORG"],[351,354,"ORG"]]},{"content":"This action arose because of the misconduct of {X} and Lee which took place during their employment with CAF and another securities dealer Chintron Securities Limited (\"Chintron\"]. Chintron was subsequently taken over by new management on 6 December 1995.","entities":[[105,108,"ORG"],[139,166,"ORG"],[169,177,"ORG"],[181,189,"ORG"]]},{"content":"{X} was a director of both CAF and Chintron and, although not registered in any capacity with the SFC, was the person responsible for the day to day operations and management at both Chintron and CAF. His misconduct was related to the following acts:","entities":[[27,30,"ORG"],[35,43,"ORG"],[98,101,"ORG"],[183,191,"ORG"],[196,199,"ORG"]]},{"content":"a. performing the functions of a dealer on behalf of Chintron during the period March 1994 to December 1995 and CAF during the period December 1995 to June 1997 respectively whilst not registered;","entities":[[53,61,"ORG"],[112,115,"ORG"]]},{"content":"b. engaging in trading malpractices which were not in the best interest to the clients of Chintron and CAF by means of in-house manual cross trades between clients' accounts and his nominee accounts maintained at both Chintron and CAF during the period October 1995 to February 1996 and by preferential reallocation of trades executed for clients of CAF to his nominee accounts at CAF; and","entities":[[90,98,"ORG"],[103,106,"ORG"],[218,226,"ORG"],[231,234,"ORG"],[381,384,"ORG"],[350,353,"ORG"]]},{"content":"{X} had since ceased to be employed by CAF.","entities":[[39,42,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Lee was the sole registered Dealing Director of both Chintron and CAF with the principal responsibility of supervising their securities business. He failed to properly carry out his responsibilities in that he condoned the unregistered dealing activities of {X} and knowingly facilitated {X}'s trading malpractices. However, Lee did not derive any personal gains from the trading malpractices of {X} other than the commission generated from the trades.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[53,61,"ORG"],[66,69,"ORG"]]},{"content":"By reason of the misconduct of its directors {X} and Lee in relation to its securities business and by reason of its failure to ensure that proper checks and balances were in place in its systems and procedures to detect improper and illegal activities, CAF also failed in its responsibilities to properly supervise its business.","entities":[[53,56,"PERSON"],[254,257,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has decided to publicly reprimand CAF and {X}, and suspend the registration of Lee for a period of 24 months effective 25 June 1998. On the other hand, the Disciplinary Committee of the Exchange (the \"Disciplinary Committee\"] has decided to publicly censure both CAF and Lee. In addition, the Disciplinary Committee has decided to fine CAF HK$30,000 and Lee HK$15,000.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[42,45,"ORG"],[194,202,"ORG"],[271,274,"ORG"],[344,347,"ORG"],[279,282,"PERSON"],[87,90,"PERSON"],[362,365,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In deciding on these courses of action, the SFC and the Disciplinary Committee took into account:","entities":[[44,47,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Lee had left all positions with CAF.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[32,35,"ORG"]]},{"content":"CAF had undertaken remedial action following the SFC's investigation to ensure that its securities business would be conducted in a proper manner, including that:the internal control procedures of CAF were reviewed by an independent firm of accountants and CAF had undertaken to implement all the recommendations in the review report to the satisfaction of the Exchange; and","entities":[[0,3,"ORG"],[49,52,"ORG"],[197,200,"ORG"],[257,260,"ORG"],[361,369,"ORG"]]},{"content":"CAF had appointed a person with full responsibility for corporate compliance acceptable to the SFC.","entities":[[0,3,"ORG"],[95,98,"ORG"]]},{"content":"For further information, please contact Mr Bill Weeks or Mr Chan Chi-keung of the SFC at 2840-9287 or Mr Henry Law of the Exchange at 2840-3862.","entities":[[60,74,"PERSON"],[43,53,"PERSON"],[82,85,"ORG"],[105,114,"PERSON"],[122,130,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Stock Exchange of Hong Kong","entities":[[4,31,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited (the \"Exchange\"] announces that on 16 June 1998, the Disciplinary Committee heard the cases of the Member, CAF Securities Company Limited (\"CAF\"] and its Dealing Director, Mr Lee Wah Kin (\"Mr Lee\"]. The Disciplinary Committee found a charge against each of CAF and Mr Lee for breach of the Rules of the Exchange proved.","entities":[[4,39,"ORG"],[46,54,"ORG"],[147,177,"ORG"],[180,183,"ORG"],[215,226,"PERSON"],[297,300,"ORG"],[308,311,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The substance of the charge proved against Mr Lee was that:-","entities":[[46,49,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"i. during the period December 1995 to June 1997, Mr Lee had condoned the unregistered dealing activities conducted by a former director of CAF; and","entities":[[52,55,"PERSON"],[139,142,"ORG"]]},{"content":"ii. Mr Lee had failed to put in place proper internal control in CAF, resulting that the said director engaged in trading malpractices by means of in-house manual cross trades between clients' accounts and the director's nominee accounts maintained at CAF and by means of preferential reallocation of trades executed for CAF's clients to his nominee accounts maintained at CAF during the period December 1995 to February 1996. It also resulted that the staff of CAF engaged in illegal short-selling activities through nominee accounts maintained at CAF during the period December 1995 to February 1996.","entities":[[7,10,"PERSON"],[65,68,"ORG"],[321,324,"ORG"],[252,255,"ORG"],[373,376,"ORG"],[462,465,"ORG"],[549,552,"ORG"]]},{"content":"By reason of the above misconduct of the said director and Mr Lee and by reason of CAF's failure to ensure that proper checks and balances were in place in its systems and procedures to detect the improper and illegal activities, CAF had failed in its responsibilities to properly supervise its business.","entities":[[62,65,"PERSON"],[83,86,"ORG"],[230,233,"ORG"]]},{"content":"ii. Mr Lee had left all positions with CAF; and","entities":[[7,10,"PERSON"],[39,42,"ORG"]]},{"content":"iii. CAF had undertaken remedial action following the investigation to ensure that its securities business would be conducted in a proper manner, including that:-","entities":[[5,8,"ORG"]]},{"content":"a. the internal control procedures of CAF were reviewed by an independent firm of accountants and CAF had undertaken to implement all the recommendations in the review report to the satisfaction of the Exchange; and","entities":[[38,41,"ORG"],[98,101,"ORG"],[202,210,"ORG"]]},{"content":"b. CAF had appointed a person with full responsibility for corporate compliance acceptable to the Securities and Futures Commission,","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[98,131,"ORG"]]},{"content":"the Disciplinary Committee resolved that a penalty of public censure plus a fine of HK$30,000 be imposed on CAF and a penalty of public censure plus a fine of HK$15,000 be imposed on Mr Lee. The penalty of public censure is hereby imposed on each of CAF and Mr Lee.","entities":[[108,111,"ORG"],[186,189,"PERSON"],[250,253,"ORG"],[261,264,"PERSON"],[4,26,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited","entities":[[4,39,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Fanny Chung","entities":[[0,11,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded and fined FXCM Asia Limited (HK FXCM) (now known as Rakuten Securities Hong Kong Limited) HK$2 million for regulatory breaches and internal control failings relating to under-segregation of client money (Notes 1 & 2).   ","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[70,87,"ORG"],[89,96,"ORG"],[112,148,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC’s investigation found that from January 2013 to January 2015, HK FXCM under-segregated client monies as a result of:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[70,77,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- meeting clients’ withdrawals of monies that are in excess of the amounts HK FXCM segregated for them with the monies that are held for other clients; and","entities":[[76,83,"ORG"]]},{"content":"These actions of HK FXCM were contrary to the Client Money Rules and the Code of Conduct (Notes 3 & 4).       ","entities":[[17,24,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC considers that HK FXCM failed to have adequate internal controls in place to prevent under-segregation of client monies, and to ensure that client assets were properly accounted for and adequately safeguarded. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,30,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In deciding the disciplinary sanctions, the SFC took into account that HK FXCM:","entities":[[44,47,"ORG"],[71,78,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- co-operated with the SFC in resolving the SFC’s concerns;","entities":[[24,27,"ORG"],[45,48,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- is now under new ownership and management and the failures relating to its client money handling procedures were attributable to the former management of HK FXCM.","entities":[[157,164,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC welcomes the Court of Appeal’s decision to dismiss an appeal brought by Mr Koon Wing Yee against the SFC. The proceedings were dismissed at trial by Mr Justice Saunders on 5 November 2007. Koon launched an appeal against this decision which was heard by the Court of Appeal on 29 July 2008 (Note 1).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[21,36,"ORG"],[83,96,"PERSON"],[109,112,"ORG"],[160,176,"PERSON"],[197,201,"PERSON"],[266,281,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC had issued a notice to Koon using special investigative powers under the Securities & Futures Ordinance (SFO) which permit the SFC to interview certain people during an investigation and obtain answers to questions (Note 2).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[31,35,"PERSON"],[135,138,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Koon argued that this power infringed his basic rights including his rights to silence and refused to give answers to questions. The SFC argued that Koon’s objection is misplaced because the SFO properly protects all relevant fundamental rights.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[133,136,"ORG"],[149,153,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In dismissing Koon’s appeal, the Court of Appeal awarded costs to the SFC and indicated that it will give reasons for the decision at a later date.","entities":[[14,18,"PERSON"],[33,48,"ORG"],[70,73,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded Chan Ngok Ming Securities Limited (CNMSL), a licensed corporation, for internal control failures.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,57,"ORG"],[59,64,"ORG"]]},{"content":"An SFC inspection of the business operations of CNMSL in late 2002 revealed a number of internal control weaknesses in CNMSL’s operations, including the following:","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[48,53,"ORG"],[119,124,"ORG"]]},{"content":"mistakes in relation to client transactions were identified in CNMSL’s settlement records; and","entities":[[63,68,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC found that a considerable number of CNMSL’s internal control weaknesses were caused by its outdated and defective computer system and the lack of employee supervision.  The SFC concludes that the fitness and properness of CNMSL has been called into question and decides to reprimand it. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[44,49,"ORG"],[230,235,"ORG"],[181,184,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In deciding to reprimand CNMSL, the SFC has taken into account that no client of CNMSL has suffered any financial loss, and CNMSL has taken a number of rectification measures including the implementation of a new computer system and appointment of new supervisory staff to strengthen its internal control procedures.  Had these measures not been taken, the penalty imposed would have been more severe.","entities":[[25,30,"ORG"],[36,39,"ORG"],[81,86,"ORG"],[124,129,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Internal control failings make fraud easy to conceal and difficult to detect, which harm the interest of the investing public and the integrity of markets.  As repeatedly stated in our recent press releases, we do not tolerate firms with internal control failures and where such failures caused clients’ losses or otherwise facilitated serious misconduct, we will not hesitate to impose a fine, or in the most serious cases, a lengthy suspension or even a revocation of the licence of the brokerage firm and the management concerned.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"]]},{"content":"“The current case is significantly mitigated by the absence of clients’ losses and staff misconduct.  CNMSL has also taken steps to improve its internal control procedures.  If clients had suffered losses as a result of the internal control failures, a proportionate suspension would have been appropriate,”  Mr Linning added.","entities":[[102,107,"ORG"],[312,319,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC announced today that it had publicly reprimanded {X}, a dealer's representative under the Securities Ordinance and a commodity dealer's representative under the Commodities Trading Ordinance. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The reprimand stems from an inquiry in which the SFC found that {X}, during the period from April 1997 to June 2000 while employed by Seapower Futures Limited, Seapower Securities Limited, KGI Seapower Futures Limited, KGI Seapower Securities Limited, Shenyin Wanguo Securities (HK) Limited and Shenyin Wanguo Futures (H.K.) Limited, had conducted her own trading through her relatives' accounts, contrary to the staff dealing policies of her employers.","entities":[[49,52,"ORG"],[134,158,"ORG"],[160,187,"ORG"],[189,217,"ORG"],[219,250,"ORG"],[252,290,"ORG"],[295,332,"ORG"]]},{"content":"As a result of the above findings, the SFC concluded that {X}'s fitness and properness had been impugned and decided to publicly reprimand her.","entities":[[39,42,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had suspended the registration of Mr Kwong Kin Fai, Anthony (Kwong), a dealer's representative under the Securities Ordinance for a period of 3 weeks. ","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[105,127,"PERSON"],[129,134,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The suspension followed an inquiry in which the SFC found that Kwong, a dealer's representative of South China Securities Limited had, by furnishing to an unregistered employee details of another employee, enabled the unregistered employee to dishonestly gain access to the trading hall of the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited and to execute orders in contravention of the registration requirements of section 50 of the Securities Ordinance.","entities":[[48,51,"ORG"],[63,68,"PERSON"],[99,129,"ORG"],[294,329,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concluded that Kwong's actions impugned his fitness and properness and decided to suspend his registration. In considering the period of suspension, the SFC had taken into account that at the time of the event Kwong acted thoughtlessly at a time of heavy trading activity and staff shortages due to illness.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,28,"PERSON"],[161,164,"ORG"],[218,223,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC has successfully prosecuted Wall Street Global (Hong Kong) Limited and its senior officers, {X1} and {X2}, for holding themselves out as performing a regulated function in relation to securities dealing whilst unlicensed.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[36,74,"ORG"]]},{"content":"An SFC investigation revealed that between 28 May 2004 and 16 March 2005, whilst not licensed by the SFC in any capacity, Wall Street Global had held itself out as carrying on a securities dealing business by introducing some investment products to investors in Hong Kong, in contravention of section 114 of the SFO. {X1} and {X2} aided and abetted the offence of the company through their activities on its behalf, in contravention of sections 114 and 390 of the SFO.","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[122,140,"ORG"],[101,104,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Wall Street Global, {X1} and {X2} were convicted today after trial before Mr David Thomas, a Magistrate at Eastern Magistracy. They were each fined $ 10,000 and ordered to pay total investigation costs of $13,386 to the SFC.","entities":[[0,18,"ORG"],[77,89,"PERSON"],[107,125,"ORG"],[220,223,"ORG"]]}]