[{"content":"The SFC today publishes the November issue of SFC Enforcement Reporter, which is also the first anniversary issue. The issue begins with a special review of enforcement cases and trends in the past year, followed by the regular summary of enforcement actions in the month of October 2003 and discussion of the compliance issues highlighted by recent cases.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[46,49,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC notes a substantial increase in market manipulation prosecutions, more breaches of the financial resources requirements, and re-emergence of cases of unlicensed dealing after a period of decline. The SFC warns that tougher judicial or disciplinary penalties are available under the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO), which became effective on 1 April 2003, against these breaches. People who lie or refuse to co-operate in SFC investigations can also expect harsh penalties.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[208,211,"ORG"],[436,439,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In October, the SFC successfully prosecuted three people for unregistered dealing or aiding and abetting such activities.","entities":[[16,19,"ORG"]]},{"content":"During the month, the SFC disciplined 11 licensees. The SFC imposed, for the first time under the SFO, a prohibition order on a licensed representative to ban him for life from working again in the securities industry for attempted theft. It fined a licensee, also for the first time under the SFO, for unlicensed dealing.","entities":[[22,25,"ORG"],[56,59,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Appeals Tribunal upheld an SFC decision to suspend a responsible officer for six weeks. The SFC welcomes the first decision of the Tribunal for setting clear parameters for reviewing cases.","entities":[[54,57,"ORG"],[119,122,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Since 1 April 2003, the SFC has successfully prosecuted 36 people and disciplined 55 licensees for various regulatory breaches.","entities":[[24,27,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Copies of the November issue of SFC Enforcement Reporter are available at the SFC office. All issues are also available on the SFC website under “Press Releases, Publications & Speeches” – “Publications”.","entities":[[32,35,"ORG"],[78,81,"ORG"],[127,130,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The public are welcome to subscribe to the newsletter by registering for the SFC Website Update Email Alert service on the SFC's homepage. They will then be able to receive the newsletter via email.","entities":[[77,80,"ORG"],[123,126,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The public are also invited to provide feedback so we can improve the SFC Enforcement Reporter. Comments can be emailed to enfreporter@hksfc.org.hk.","entities":[[70,73,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has suspended Mr Tsui Kwok Fan for five months from 6 November 2007 to 5 April 2008 (Note 1).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[25,38,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The disciplinary action follows an SFC investigation which found that Tsui:","entities":[[35,38,"ORG"],[70,74,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Tsui did not dispute the SFC’s findings and received a discounted penalty for his co-operation (Note 2).","entities":[[25,28,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has banned Ms Lok Wai Fong, a former employee of Bank of China (Hong Kong) Limited (Bank), from re-entering the industry for life (Note 1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[58,70,"PERSON"],[93,126,"ORG"],[128,132,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The disciplinary action follows an SFC investigation which found that from April 2009 to January 2012, Lok transferred a sum of around $1.6 million from the savings account of a customer to the bank account of a securities firm, without his knowledge and authorization.  The transfers were made purportedly to settle trades conducted in the securities accounts in the name of Lok’s niece and nephew-in-law when in fact the trades were Lok’s own trades.","entities":[[35,38,"ORG"],[103,106,"PERSON"],[435,438,"PERSON"],[376,379,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC also found that Lok received securities trading instructions from the customer’s wife, who is a customer of the Bank as well, but Lok failed to act on those instructions.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,27,"PERSON"],[120,124,"ORG"],[138,141,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In deciding the sanctions against Lok, the SFC considers that her dishonest conduct casts serious doubts on her fitness and properness to be a regulated person.","entities":[[34,37,"PERSON"],[43,46,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The case was referred to the SFC by the Hong Kong Monetary Authority.","entities":[[29,32,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded Guosen Securities (HK) Brokerage Company, Limited (Guosen) and fined it $15.2 million for failures in complying with anti-money laundering (AML) and counter-terrorist financing (CFT) regulatory requirements when handling third party fund deposits (Note 1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[60,109,"ORG"],[111,117,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC’s investigation revealed that between November 2014 and December 2015, Guosen had processed 10,000 third party deposits totalling approximately $5 billion for more than 3,500 clients. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[79,85,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Specifically, the SFC found that:","entities":[[18,21,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- over 100 Guosen’s clients received third party deposits that were incommensurate with their financial profiles;","entities":[[12,18,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- certain third parties made numerous deposits to the accounts of Guosen’s clients and had no apparent relationships with these clients.","entities":[[67,73,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Despite the apparent AML/CFT red flags, Guosen failed to make enquiries about such third party deposits and did not submit suspicious transaction reports to the Joint Financial Intelligence Unit (JFIU) in a timely manner.","entities":[[40,46,"ORG"],[161,194,"ORG"],[196,200,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC is concerned that Guosen only began to report the more than 2,200 third party deposits, which took place between November 2014 and December 2015, as being suspicious to JFIU in March 2016 after an SFC review.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[26,32,"ORG"],[205,208,"ORG"],[177,181,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC also found that Guosen failed to:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,30,"ORG"]]},{"content":"It also emerged that certain staff members of Guosen had brought some of the above-mentioned internal control deficiencies to the attention of its former senior management and a former responsible officer as early as 2013 and made suggestion to address the deficiencies.  However, the senior management and the responsible officer did not take any steps to ensure that the AML/CFT internal controls on third party deposits were effective.","entities":[[46,52,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC is of the view that Guosen’s conduct was in breach of the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing Ordinance (AMLO) and the Guideline on Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing (AML/CFT Guideline), which require licensed corporations to implement appropriate AML/CFT internal controls to mitigate the risk of ML/TF (Notes 2,3 & 4).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[28,34,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In deciding the disciplinary sanction, the SFC took into account that:","entities":[[43,46,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Guosen processed more than 2,200 suspicious third party deposits totalling over $2.3 billion in the course of a 14-month period;","entities":[[3,9,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- the former senior management and a former responsible officer of Guosen, who have now been replaced, turned a blind eye to the ML/TF risks associated with third party deposits;","entities":[[68,74,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Guosen engaged an independent reviewer to conduct a review of its internal controls and took steps to remediate the deficiencies identified, including implementing new AML/CFT policies and third party deposit procedures;","entities":[[3,9,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Guosen cooperated with the SFC in resolving the SFC’s concerns and accepting the disciplinary action; and","entities":[[3,9,"ORG"],[30,33,"ORG"],[51,54,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Guosen has an otherwise clean disciplinary record.","entities":[[3,9,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has suspended the registration of Mr Tsang Wa Wai William for four months and reprimanded Masterlink Securities (Hong Kong) Corporation Limited and its dealing director {X}.   ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[45,65,"PERSON"],[98,151,"ORG"],[177,180,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Tsang","entities":[[0,5,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The action follows an inquiry into a complaint made to the SFC by clients of Masterlink about unauthorized trading in their accounts.  After investigating, the SFC found that from 1 July 2000 to 31 August 2000, Tsang, a dealer’s representative of Masterlink, had accepted orders from another employee of Masterlink for the accounts of two clients without their authority.  The employee’s unauthorized trading was substantial and created losses of over $400,000 in the clients’ accounts.   ","entities":[[59,62,"ORG"],[77,87,"ORG"],[160,163,"ORG"],[211,216,"PERSON"],[247,257,"ORG"],[304,314,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC found that Tsang’s accommodating the employee’s unauthorised trading was improper and exposed the relevant parties to unnecessary risks.  Further, his failure to monitor the trading in the two clients’ accounts and his failure to ensure that the employee had the necessary authority to operate these two accounts breached the Code of Conduct. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[19,24,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Masterlink ","entities":[[0,10,"ORG"]]},{"content":"At the time of Tsang’s misconduct, Masterlink had insufficient credit and trading limits controls in place.  The SFC also found that Masterlink’s action in pursuing debt recovery against one of the clients was inappropriate and amounted to conduct unbefitting of a registered person.  By then, Masterlink knew that the trading had been conducted without the knowledge and consent of the client.  During the inquiry, the SFC also found inadequacies in the way in which Masterlink handled client funds so that clients were inadequately protected from financial losses.  At the SFC’s request, Masterlink appointed accountants to review its systems and controls. ","entities":[[15,20,"PERSON"],[35,45,"ORG"],[113,116,"ORG"],[133,143,"ORG"],[294,304,"ORG"],[420,423,"ORG"],[575,578,"ORG"],[590,600,"ORG"],[468,478,"ORG"]]},{"content":"{X}","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Between 1 July 2000 and 31 August 2000, {X} was the sole dealing director who was responsible for Masterlink’s day-to-day operations.  The SFC found that {X} bore responsibility for the failings identified in Masterlink’s internal controls and procedures and that he had failed to properly supervise his staff.      ","entities":[[40,43,"PERSON"],[98,108,"ORG"],[139,142,"ORG"],[154,157,"PERSON"],[209,219,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Based on these findings, the SFC concluded that Tsang, Masterlink and {X} were guilty of misconduct and their fitness and properness had been called into question.  The SFC therefore decided to suspend Tsang’s registration for four months and reprimand Masterlink and {X}. ","entities":[[55,65,"ORG"],[70,73,"PERSON"],[48,53,"PERSON"],[169,172,"ORG"],[268,271,"PERSON"],[253,263,"ORG"],[202,207,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In determining the level of penalty, the SFC noted that Masterlink had been co-operative during the SFC investigation and had taken measures to improve its systems and internal controls.   ","entities":[[41,44,"ORG"],[56,66,"ORG"],[100,103,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “A registered person must establish and maintain effective policies, operational procedures and controls in relation to its day-to-day business operations. In particular, prior to executing a client order, a designated staff member must check the sufficiency of available funds or securities in the relevant account, its margin position (including any applicable limitations) and the authority of the person placing the order.  A registered person must also justify its action to be taken against its clients for collection of debt.  It is not acceptable to hold clients responsible for losses caused by a staff member’s misconduct. We will treat any breaches of these requirements seriously.” ","entities":[[17,20,"ORG"],[3,15,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Masterlink is a registered dealer under the Securities Ordinance.","entities":[[0,10,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has issued restriction notices to nine brokers, prohibiting them from dealing with or processing certain assets held in their clients’ accounts which are related to suspected market manipulation in the shares of China Ding Yi Feng Holdings Limited (China Ding Yi Feng) between 2018 and early 2019 (Notes 1 & 2).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[256,291,"ORG"],[293,311,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The nine brokers are: Futu Securities International (Hong Kong) Limited, GF Securities (Hong Kong) Brokerage Limited, Guotai Junan Securities (Hong Kong) Limited, Haitong International Securities Company Limited, Orient Securities (Hong Kong) Limited, SBI China Capital Financial Services Limited, Shenwan Hongyuan Securities (H.K.) Limited, Sun Hung Kai Investment Services Limited, and Yunfeng Securities Limited.","entities":[[22,71,"ORG"],[73,116,"ORG"],[118,161,"ORG"],[163,211,"ORG"],[213,250,"ORG"],[252,296,"ORG"],[298,340,"ORG"],[342,382,"ORG"],[388,414,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC is not investigating these brokers, which have cooperated with the SFC’s ongoing investigation.  The restriction notices do not affect their operations or their other clients.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[75,78,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The restriction notices prohibit them, without the SFC’s prior written consent, from disposing of or dealing with, assisting, counselling or procuring another person to dispose of or deal with any assets in any way in the client accounts, including: (i) entering into transactions for any securities; and/or (ii) processing any withdrawals or transferring of securities and/or cash arising from the disposal of securities; and/or (iii) disposing of or dealing with any securities or cash on the instructions of any authorized persons of the client accounts or by any persons acting on their behalf; and/or (iv) assisting another person to dispose of or deal with any relevant property in the client accounts in any manner.  The brokers are also required to notify the SFC if they receive any of these instructions.","entities":[[51,54,"ORG"],[768,771,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC considers that the issue of the restriction notices is desirable in the interest of the investing public or in the public interest.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC’s investigation is continuing.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded CLSA Limited, a securities dealer licensed under the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,36,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The reprimand stems from an SFC inquiry into the effectiveness of the internal controls at CLSA which was initiated following CLSA’s discovery in November 2002 that a former employee of CLSA, Yeung Tsz Chung (Yeung) had misappropriated more than HK$22 million over a period of more than 10 years (Note 1).","entities":[[28,31,"ORG"],[91,95,"ORG"],[126,130,"ORG"],[186,190,"ORG"],[192,207,"PERSON"],[209,214,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC and CLSA engaged an independent accounting firm to conduct an investigation into the activities of Yeung and to review CLSA’s internal controls and procedures. That review has shown that, at the relevant times, there were internal control weaknesses at CLSA (which CLSA has since remedied) which were exploited by Yeung to enable him to commit and conceal his fraudulent activities. In particular:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[12,16,"ORG"],[127,131,"ORG"],[107,112,"PERSON"],[261,265,"ORG"],[273,277,"ORG"]]},{"content":"there should have been a segregation of duties so that Yeung was not responsible for both processing transactions and reconciliation of positions;staff should have been reminded of the importance of ensuring strict adherence to procedural guidelines, and in particular those relating to computer access and security;staff should have been required to take their full holiday entitlement as it can provide the employer with an opportunity to detect fraudulent conduct;CLSA should have ensured that the stock reconciliations and calculation of dividend and bonus share entitlements of clients which were conducted by Yeung were independently verified;CLSA’s own pool of securities, securities holdings at other locations and infrequently traded accounts should have been monitored on a regular basis. Yeung’s access to these enabled him to steal stock from CLSA and cover up the theft;transfers of stock by staff members for their personal account should have been more closely monitored as this could have indicated Yeung’s wrongful activities;the internal audit controls, as well as the resources committed by CLSA to supervision of certain settlement staff at the relevant times, were not adequate as a result of which the fraudulent activities of Yeung went undetected for too long;due to system limitations, CLSA failed in certain instances to maintain an audit trail of changes to client standing data, these limitations have since been rectified;CLSA should have examined and evaluated the adequacy and effectiveness of its internal controls to detect fraud; andCLSA should have ensured at the relevant times, more adequate planning, control and recording of all audit and review work performed and should have also ensured that risks highlighted in internal reports were followed up and resolved satisfactorily.","entities":[[55,60,"PERSON"],[467,471,"ORG"],[615,620,"PERSON"],[649,653,"ORG"],[799,804,"PERSON"],[855,859,"ORG"],[1015,1020,"PERSON"],[1110,1114,"ORG"],[1249,1254,"PERSON"],[1311,1315,"ORG"],[1451,1455,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concludes that the fitness and properness of CLSA has been called into question. In deciding its action, the SFC has taken into account the fact that CLSA has implemented the recommendations proposed by the independent accounting firm to additionally improve its internal control systems as well as the supervision and monitoring of the work of its employees. The independent review notes that since the company began its system upgrades in 2000, a number of system and operational changes were in process, which if implemented would have rectified most if not all the weaknesses. CLSA has notified the 32 known staff, affiliate, client and inactive accounts affected and also pledged to notify any additional clients affected by the misappropriation and credit their accounts with the shortfall amounts and has undertaken to the SFC to compensate future claimants for loss caused by Yeung’s theft. The SFC acknowledges that CLSA has taken internal disciplinary action against individuals whose failings unwittingly facilitated the misappropriation by Yeung (Note 2).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[53,57,"ORG"],[117,120,"ORG"],[158,162,"ORG"],[589,593,"ORG"],[838,841,"ORG"],[892,897,"ORG"],[911,914,"ORG"],[933,937,"ORG"],[1060,1065,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: \"Intermediaries must ensure that they have effective internal control procedures and that their staff are properly supervised and monitored in order to adequately safeguard client assets. With proper internal control, fraud and misconduct such as misappropriation can be detected at an earlier stage or prevented altogether. We will take disciplinary action against companies that fail to put in place adequate internal controls.\"","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\"For a long time, the SFC has reprimanded brokerages for similar failings. Yet, we continue to come across this type of cases all too often. It therefore appears that reprimands are proving to be an inadequate deterrent. Under the SFO, the SFC may fine and partially suspend or revoke licences. In future, in cases of internal control and supervision failings facilitating serious misconduct harming clients, the SFC will consider imposing heavier sanctions. In the most severe cases, we will consider suspending a brokerage’s licence for a long period or even revoking it. Investor protection demands this,\" he added.","entities":[[22,25,"ORG"],[240,243,"ORG"],[413,416,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) today obtained an order in the High Court against Mr Chow Chun Kwong, a former director of GP NanoTechnology Group Ltd (GP Nano), disqualifying him from being a director or being involved in the management of any listed company, without leave of the court, for a period of six years (Note 1). The disqualification order will take effect on 20 February 2009.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[75,85,"ORG"],[97,112,"PERSON"],[135,162,"ORG"],[164,171,"ORG"]]},{"content":"This is the second former director of GP Nano to be disqualified from being a company director on the basis of his misconduct. On 27 November 2008 Mr Ong Hong Hoon, a former director of GP Nano, was disqualified from being a director or being involved in the management of any company for a period of five years (Note 2). The SFC is also taking similar action against three other former directors of the company (Note 3).","entities":[[38,45,"ORG"],[150,163,"PERSON"],[186,193,"ORG"],[326,329,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleged that Chow had:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[21,25,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"abdicated responsibility as director of publicly listed GP Nano;","entities":[[56,63,"ORG"]]},{"content":"failed to ensure the company complied with the relevant rules and regulations, namely the Growth Enterprise Market listing rules and the Code on Takeovers and Mergers.","entities":[[90,114,"ORG"]]},{"content":"“This is the third disqualification order made by the court against a listed company director for misconduct,” said Mr Mark Steward, the SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement. “The SFC will continue its program of action against listed company directors who provide misleading information to the market and breach their duties to the company at the expense of shareholders. Shareholders are entitled to expect competent and honest governance from listed company directors (Note 4).”","entities":[[119,131,"PERSON"],[137,140,"ORG"],[183,186,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC reminds the industry that misappropriating client assets attracts serious criminal consequences.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC notes the conviction today of Mr Law Siu Kong, sole proprietor of the now collapsed Lawsons Securities Company, for conspiracy to defraud involving $32 million worth of client assets.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[41,53,"PERSON"],[92,118,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In 2002, the SFC referred the case to the Commercial Crime Bureau following an audit check on Lawsons which found client assets were missing.","entities":[[13,16,"ORG"],[94,101,"ORG"],[42,65,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Law was arrested by Police in June 2007 and pleaded guilty today in the District Court. Sentencing is adjourned pending the trial of two other defendants in the case in February 2008. Law is remanded in jail custody.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[184,187,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Mark Steward, the SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “The SFC will continue to refer appropriate cases to the Commercial Crime Bureau and will provide assistance to them in fighting criminal activity that endangers the investing public.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[21,24,"ORG"],[73,76,"ORG"],[125,148,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC would also like to remind investors to always stay vigilant against misappropriation. In particular:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Court has issued an arrest warrant for Ms Pan Caihong, a Mainland lawyer, who did not appear at the Eastern Magistracy this morning to face nine counts of insider dealing charges commenced by the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC).","entities":[[4,9,"ORG"],[46,57,"PERSON"],[104,122,"ORG"],[200,233,"ORG"],[235,238,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleges that Great World Company Holdings Limited (Great World), a company listed on the Growth Enterprise Market of the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong, engaged Pan to manage the announcement of a proposed placement of 80,000,000 shares of Great World. The proposed placement was announced on 27 July 2009 with Pan acting as spokesperson for the company at a press conference held the following day.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[21,57,"ORG"],[59,70,"ORG"],[129,156,"ORG"],[166,169,"PERSON"],[245,256,"ORG"],[316,319,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleges that details of the proposed placement, which constituted about 16% of the total issued share capital of the company, including the fact that it was priced at a discount of about 14.5% to the prevailing market price, was confidential price sensitive information and that Pan was an insider before the placement was announced to the market. As well as handling the announcement and the press conference, Pan was also a shareholder in the company.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[287,290,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"A few days prior to the announcement, on 23 July 2009, the SFC alleges Pan sold 1,652,000 Great World shares, avoiding a potential loss of about $87,000.","entities":[[71,74,"PERSON"],[59,62,"ORG"],[90,101,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC told the court that Pan is a Mainland resident and was a frequent traveller to Hong Kong but she has not returned to Hong Kong since not long after the SFC’s investigation commenced.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[28,31,"PERSON"],[160,163,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Upon the SFC’s application, Mr David Dufton, Acting Principal Magistrate of the Eastern Magistracy, issued an arrest warrant for Pan.","entities":[[9,12,"ORG"],[31,43,"PERSON"],[129,132,"PERSON"],[80,98,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC also announced today that it had successfully prosecuted YourShare Holdings Corporation for issuance of unauthorized advertisements and promotional documents, which invited members of the public to take part in an investment arrangement relating to the allocation of warrants in return for registration as a member of the website. ","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[65,95,"ORG"]]},{"content":"YourShare Holdings Corporation pleaded guilty before Ms Polly Lo to a summons for breaching sections 4[1)(b) and 4[4) of the Protection of Investors Ordinance and was fined a total of $10,000 and ordered to pay investigation costs of $11,253 to the SFC.","entities":[[0,30,"ORG"],[56,64,"PERSON"],[249,252,"ORG"]]},{"content":"This prosecution came to light as a result of the SFC's monitoring of the Internet. People offering rewards, incentives or gimmicks as a promotional ploy to attract clients should pay attention to the provisions of the Protection of Investors Ordinance because any advertisements inviting the public to take part in what could amount to an investment arrangement requires prior authorization from the SFC.","entities":[[50,53,"ORG"],[401,404,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC announces today that it has successfully prosecuted {X} of Winsor Properties Holdings Limited, under the Securities (Disclosure of Interests) Ordinance.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[60,63,"PERSON"],[67,101,"ORG"]]},{"content":"{X} pleaded guilty in relation to two summonses regarding his failure to report to the Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEx) and Winsor Properties within five business days following his acquisition of 447,000 shares of Winsor Properties on 3 September 2001. {X} did not notify the HKEx and Winsor Properties of his interest until 15 November 2001.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[129,133,"ORG"],[87,127,"ORG"],[139,156,"ORG"],[230,247,"ORG"],[269,272,"PERSON"],[292,296,"ORG"],[301,318,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Ms Polly Lo, a Magistrate at Western Magistracy, fined {X} a total of $10,000 and ordered him to pay costs of $17,516 to the SFC.","entities":[[3,11,"PERSON"],[29,47,"ORG"],[125,128,"ORG"],[55,58,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that they had taken action against Ng May Wah Priscilla (Priscilla Ng), a registered dealer’s representative under the Securities Ordinance (SO) and a registered dealer’s representative under the Commodities Trading Ordinance (CTO).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[95,115,"PERSON"],[117,129,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The action arose from an inquiry by the SFC relating to a Client (Client) complaint. It was found that in the course of administering a client account, whilst in the employment of CEF Brokerage Limited as a dealer’s representative, Priscilla Ng had:","entities":[[40,43,"ORG"],[180,201,"ORG"],[232,244,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Ms Ng’s conduct impugned her fitness and properness as a registered person under both the SO and CTO. As a result of the above findings, the SFC has decided to:","entities":[[3,5,"PERSON"],[141,144,"ORG"]]},{"content":"a. suspend the registrations of Ms Ng for a period of six months commencing 24 February, 2000;","entities":[[35,37,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"b. Ms Ng will be prohibited from operating a client’s account on a discretionary basis for a period of 5 years from the date of the expiry of the 6-month suspension period; and","entities":[[6,8,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"c. after the expiry of the suspension, Ms Ng will be subject to strict supervision by her new employer for a period of 5 years.","entities":[[42,44,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In deciding on this course of action, the SFC has taken into account that:","entities":[[42,45,"ORG"]]},{"content":"a. Ms Ng had cooperated fully with the SFC, her Client and her previous employer, in order to resolve the complaint, including agreeing to a settlement involving full payment of the Client’s claims;","entities":[[6,8,"PERSON"],[39,42,"ORG"]]},{"content":"b. Ms Ng had not engaged in any rat trading or similar misconduct for her own benefit as she, apart from the commission income, had not profited from the trading activities in the Client’s account. Her intention was to trade for the benefit of her Client despite her mishandling of the Client’s account without proper written authorization for discretionary trading; and","entities":[[6,8,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"c. This is the first offence of Ms Ng since her first registration with SFC as she has not been subject to any regulatory sanction or to SFC inquiry in respect of any misconduct.","entities":[[35,37,"PERSON"],[72,75,"ORG"],[137,140,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In its fourth such prosecution this year, the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has commenced criminal proceedings against a former financial advisor and a former fund manager for alleged insider dealing offences related to JCDecaux Pearl & Dean Ltd’s acquisition of a majority stake in a then Hong Kong-listed rival outdoor advertising agency.","entities":[[46,79,"ORG"],[81,84,"ORG"],[230,255,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Allen Lam Kar Fai, a former investment banking director at CLSA Equity Capital Markets Ltd (CLSA) and Mr Ryan Fong Yen-hwung, a former fund manager at HSZ (Hong Kong) Ltd (HSZ), appeared at the Eastern Magistracy today on a total of three charges of insider dealing. No plea was taken.","entities":[[3,20,"PERSON"],[62,93,"ORG"],[95,99,"ORG"],[108,127,"PERSON"],[154,173,"ORG"],[175,178,"ORG"],[197,215,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The charges concern alleged trading in the shares of Media Partners International Holdings Inc, a Shanghai-based company then trading in Hong Kong under stock code 8072, prior to an announcement on 21 September 2005 that JCDecaux Pearl & Dean would acquire from it a 73.38% controlling interest at $1.141 per share.","entities":[[53,94,"ORG"],[221,242,"ORG"]]},{"content":"At the time of the alleged offences, CLSA was engaged as the financial adviser for the purchaser. The SFC alleges that, while employed by CLSA, Lam knew about the acquisition before it was announced and disclosed information about the transaction to Fong, who was at the time a director of HSZ.","entities":[[37,41,"ORG"],[102,105,"ORG"],[138,142,"ORG"],[144,147,"PERSON"],[250,254,"PERSON"],[290,293,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC also alleges, while in possession of such information before the announcement of the acquisition, Fong purchased a total of 10,626,000 shares of Media Partners for an HSZ fund and for himself at prices ranging from $0.6 to $0.83 from 21 July 2005 to 12 September 2005. After the acquisition was announced, Media Partners’ share price rose and Fong was able to sell the shares at prices ranging from $1.09 to $1.10.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[106,110,"PERSON"],[153,167,"ORG"],[314,328,"ORG"],[175,178,"ORG"],[351,355,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"This is the fourth criminal insider dealing case commenced by the SFC this year (Note 1).","entities":[[66,69,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has successfully prosecuted Mr Tang Yuk Kuen and Mr Cheung Tak Woo under Part XV of the Securities and Futures Ordinance.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[39,52,"PERSON"],[60,74,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Tang today pleaded guilty to six summonses in relation to his failure to notify both the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong and B&S Entertainment Holdings Limited within the specified period regarding his acquisition of shares in B&S on 16 March 2004 and 18 June 2004 and his disposal of the shares on 23 August 2004.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[89,116,"ORG"],[121,155,"ORG"],[223,226,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Cheung also pleaded guilty to six summonses in relation to his failure to notify both the Exchange and B&S within the specified period regarding his acquisition of shares in B&S on 28 July 2004 and 10 August 2004 and his disposal of the shares on 23 August 2004.","entities":[[0,6,"PERSON"],[90,98,"ORG"],[103,106,"ORG"],[174,177,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Ms L. K. LOH, a Magistrate at Eastern Magistracy, fined Tang and Cheung each $15,000and ordered them to pay investigation costs of $4,923 and $4,855 respectively to the SFC.","entities":[[3,12,"PERSON"],[30,48,"ORG"],[56,60,"ORG"],[65,71,"ORG"],[169,172,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission announced today that it had publicly reprimanded {X}, who was registered as a securities dealer's representative of Uni-Crown Investment Limited (Uni-Crown) under the Securities Ordinance.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[87,90,"PERSON"],[154,182,"ORG"],[184,193,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC conducted an inquiry under section 56 of the Securities Ordinance which revealed that during January to September 1997 {X} had:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[127,130,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"(a) knowingly facilitated two persons to open nominee accounts with Uni-Crown to enable those persons to circumvent the staff dealing policies of another brokerage with whom they were employed;","entities":[[68,77,"ORG"]]},{"content":"(b) executed orders for a prospective client even though that prospective client had not opened an account with Uni-Crown; and","entities":[[112,121,"ORG"]]},{"content":"(c) breached Code 12.2 of the Commission's \"Code of Conduct for Persons Registered with the Securities and Futures Commission\" in that he had knowingly dealt in securities for two employees of another registered person without having first sought the written consent of that other registered person.","entities":[[30,40,"ORG"],[92,125,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On this basis the SFC concluded that {X}'s fitness and properness as a registered person has been impugned.","entities":[[18,21,"ORG"],[37,40,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"An SFC spokesman, commenting on the action against {X}, noted that a registered person cannot knowingly deal in securities or futures contracts for another registered person's employee unless he has written to that registered person and received his written consent. This rule is designed to allow brokers to monitor their staff's trading when permitted to do so through other brokers. In this manner brokers are able to ensure that their staff's trading does not conflict with their own clients' trading.","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[51,54,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC has successfully prosecuted Chan Kim Wing and Tang Kin Lok, Eddie for failing to comply with notices issued by SFC’s investigators requiring attendance at interviews.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[36,49,"PERSON"],[54,73,"PERSON"],[119,122,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Four notices under Section 33[4) of the Securities and Futures Commission Ordinance and section 183(c) of Securities and Futures Ordinance were issued to Chan and Tang requiring them to attend interviews with investigators in connection with two investigations into market manipulation. However, Chan and Tang without reasonable excuse failed to attend the interviews.","entities":[[154,158,"PERSON"],[163,167,"PERSON"],[296,300,"PERSON"],[305,309,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Chan and Tang pleaded guilty to two summonses each before Principal Magistrate Mr T. S. Jenkins at Western Magistracy on 23 September 2003. They were today fined $20,000 each. In passing sentence, Mr T. S. Jenkins warned the two defendants that they had an ongoing obligation to assist the SFC investigation and if there were any further breach, he would consider giving them custodial sentences.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[9,13,"PERSON"],[82,95,"PERSON"],[99,117,"ORG"],[290,293,"ORG"],[200,213,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, welcomed the court decision and warning as to custodial sentence. He reminds those persons who are served with notices that they must comply with the requirements of the notices and warned that the SFC will not hesitate to prosecute any parties seeking to frustrate its investigation.","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"],[256,259,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded {X}, a licensed representative of Onshine Securities Limited, for trading malpractices and failure to maintain an adequate audit trail of orders (Note 1). The reprimand is the result of a settlement between{X} and the SFC.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[24,27,"PERSON"],[58,84,"ORG"],[242,245,"ORG"]]},{"content":"An SFC investigation revealed that {X}, a terminal operator of Onshine at the material time, had input numerous bid and ask orders, each for one million shares of PICC Property and Casualty Company Limited, which were cancelled almost immediately during the normal trading session on PICC's debut on 6 November 2003.{X} said that this was to \"test his luck\" as he had neither the means nor the intention to buy or sell those shares. He was under stress due to personal reasons at that time and believed that he would be lucky if he could cancel the orders before they were executed. He admitted that the trades might have misled investors. He also failed to submit \"order journals\" printed from his terminal to Onshine and hence failed to maintain an orderly audit trail. As a result,{X} breached the Code of Conduct for Persons Licensed by or Registered with the Securities and Futures Commission (Note 2).","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[35,38,"PERSON"],[63,70,"ORG"],[163,205,"ORG"],[284,288,"ORG"],[316,319,"PERSON"],[711,718,"ORG"],[864,897,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concludes that{X} has been guilty of misconduct and his fitness and properness has been called into question.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In deciding the penalty, the SFC has taken into account all the circumstances of the case, including the fact that:","entities":[[29,32,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- the orders in question, albeit numerous, did not have any direct impact upon the market price of the PICC shares;","entities":[[104,108,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- {X} was suspended from operating a terminal by Onshine pending the outcome of disciplinary proceedings against him by the SFC;","entities":[[3,6,"PERSON"],[50,57,"ORG"],[125,128,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- {X} did not get a year-end bonus or an increase in his salary due to his malpractice;","entities":[[3,6,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"\t- {X} who had a clean disciplinary record was remorseful; and","entities":[[3,6,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"\t- {X} co-operated fully with the SFC's investigation and in settling the SFC's disciplinary proceedings.","entities":[[3,6,"PERSON"],[34,37,"ORG"],[74,77,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC's Executive Director of Enforcement, said: \"In conducting regulated activities, a licensed person should act with due skill, care and diligence, in the best interests of his clients and the integrity of the market. {X}'s orders posed potential settlement risks to Onshine and might have misled other investors as to the demand for the stock in question. But for the unusual circumstances of {X}'s case, we would have suspended or fined{X} for his recklessness\".","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"],[236,239,"PERSON"],[285,292,"ORG"],[412,415,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had publicly reprimanded K.K.M. Securities Limited (KKM), its dealing director, {X1}, and two of its dealer's representatives, {X2} and {X3}, under the Securities Ordinance. ","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[93,118,"ORG"],[120,123,"ORG"],[148,152,"PERSON"],[195,199,"PERSON"],[204,208,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The action stemmed from an investigation in which it was found that a dealer's representative and a settlement clerk of KKM had extensively dealt with client assets without authorization in different periods between February 1996 and May 1998 causing losses to clients in excess of $6 million. The registration of that dealer's representative has already been revoked as a result.","entities":[[120,123,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In the course of its investigation, the SFC also found that:","entities":[[40,43,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- there was no proper control over the access to KKM's computer system which allowed unauthorized access to amend transaction records;","entities":[[50,53,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The above deficiencies in KKM's internal controls and supervision had facilitated the misconduct of its staff. {X1}, who was the dealing director responsible for managing the day-to-day operation of KKM, had the direct responsibility for the above matters. {X3}, who was the account executive for some of the clients concerned, allowed the settlement clerk to perform the dealing function whilst unregistered. {X2}, who was the immediate supervisor of the settlement clerk, failed to properly supervise his activities. Accordingly the SFC concluded that the fitness and properness of KKM, {X1}, {X2} and {X3} as registered persons had been impugned.","entities":[[26,29,"ORG"],[111,115,"PERSON"],[257,261,"PERSON"],[410,414,"PERSON"],[535,538,"ORG"],[584,587,"ORG"],[589,593,"PERSON"],[595,599,"PERSON"],[604,608,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In deciding upon this course of action, the SFC took into account that :","entities":[[44,47,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- KKM had significantly improved its internal controls following the review; and","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- KKM had compensated the clients who suffered financial losses as a result of the misconduct of its staff.","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission announced today that it had successfully prosecuted Mr Sung Wah Ting (Sung) for short-selling securities on the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited on 3 and 4 February 1998.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[93,106,"PERSON"],[108,112,"PERSON"],[150,185,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Sung pleaded guilty before Ms Polly Lo at Western Magistracy yesterday to a total of 37 summonses in relation to his short selling of securities in contravention of section 80 of the Securities Ordinance. Section 80 [1) of the Securities Ordinance prohibits the sale of securities when the seller does not have a presently exercisable and unconditional right to sell.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[30,38,"PERSON"],[42,60,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Sung was fined a total of $185,000 for the 37 summonses and ordered to pay investigation costs of $38,099 to the SFC.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[113,116,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has successfully prosecuted {X} for manipulating the share price of SEEC Media Group Limited (formerly known as Sino Infotech Holdings Limited).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[36,39,"PERSON"],[76,100,"ORG"],[120,150,"ORG"]]},{"content":"{X} pleaded guilty today before Mr Anthony Yuen, acting Principal Magistrate at Western Magistracy, to one summons for intentionally creating a false market in respect of the shares of SEEC Media Group in February and March 2002. {X} was sentenced to two months’ imprisonment suspended for one year, plus a fine of $5,000 and ordered to pay costs of $18,217 to the SFC.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[35,47,"PERSON"],[80,98,"ORG"],[185,201,"ORG"],[230,233,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC investigation found that during the last few minutes before market close on a few days in February and March 2002, {X} placed a total of seven small board-lot orders to buy 2,000 to 4,000 shares of SEEC Media Group at prices six to eight spreads higher than the then prevailing market price. These orders though not executed had the effect of pushing up the closing price of SEEC Media Group. By doing this {X} intentionally created a false market by misleading the market to believe that the share price was going up. His aim was to sell the SEEC Media Group shares on hand at higher prices on the next day.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[123,126,"PERSON"],[206,222,"ORG"],[383,399,"ORG"],[415,418,"PERSON"],[551,567,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In passing the sentence, Mr Yuen commented that the offence was a serious matter as {X}’s action had created a false perception by the market that the share price was going up.","entities":[[28,32,"PERSON"],[84,87,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission today announced the outcome of its inquiries into dealings through Nomura International (Hong Kong) Limited (NIHK) of Nomura International Plc (NIP), a UK company on the Australian Stock Exchange (ASX) and the Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE) on 29 March 1996.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[105,145,"ORG"],[147,151,"ORG"],[156,180,"ORG"],[182,185,"ORG"],[208,233,"ORG"],[235,238,"ORG"],[248,271,"ORG"],[273,276,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The dealings were in reference to NIP's Australian Index arbitrage book. Most of the trading was undertaken on NIP's behalf by NIHK on the instructions of NIP. All relevant trades were executed on behalf of NIP on a proprietary basis. Responsibility for devising the overall strategy to be adopted on 29 March 1996 was in London.","entities":[[34,37,"ORG"],[111,114,"ORG"],[127,131,"ORG"],[155,158,"ORG"],[207,210,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On 29 March 1996, as part of its Australian index arbitrage operations, NIP went to an expiry in relation to its position in sold March 1996 SPI Contracts, and placed orders with ten Australian securities brokers to sell parcels of 345 individual securities worth approximately AUD$600 million in the last 30 minutes of trading on the ASX. At the close of trading on 28 March 1996, NIP had a short futures position of 10,912 sold March 1996 SPI Contracts on the SFE, being approximately 14% of total open interest in those contracts. Those contracts were cash settled by reference to the closing price of the All Ordinaries Index (All Ords) on 29 March 1996.","entities":[[72,75,"ORG"],[335,338,"ORG"],[382,385,"ORG"],[462,465,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In addition to giving instructions to sell AUD$600 million worth of stocks, Nomura instructed one of the ten Australian securities brokers to input into the ASX Stock Exchange Automated Trading System (a computerised order-driven trading system) bid orders for the same stocks at between 5 and 20% discount to the closing price on 28 March 1996. The effect of this was that there would always be a bid order (on behalf of NIP) available to match the selling orders given by Nomura, so that the selling orders could be executed even if there were no third party buying orders, that is that in the event there were no third party buyers NIP would buy the stocks from itself at a discount. NIP's bid orders are also referred to as a \"bid basket\". The probability that NIP's bid basket would be traded was highest for the less liquid stocks. Had the selling orders been traded as anticipated by Nomura, Nomura would have purchased stock for itself at or near the close and as a consequence there would have been a greater impact on the All Ordinaries Index and in turn the settlement price of the March SPI contract.","entities":[[76,82,"ORG"],[157,160,"ORG"],[422,425,"ORG"],[635,638,"ORG"],[687,690,"ORG"],[765,768,"ORG"],[891,897,"ORG"],[899,905,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Nomura also instructed two Australian futures brokers to sell March expiry SPI futures contracts during the course of the day on 29 March 1996, thus increasing Nomura short March SPI futures position by 2,607 contracts. This was a trade which would be profitable if the All Ords fell.","entities":[[0,6,"ORG"],[160,166,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Nomura also instructed those brokers to sell June expiry SPI futures contracts during the course of the day on 29 March 1996. This was in order to hedge against the expected long position in stock which would arise from a failure to sell all of the position to third parties. NIP sold 1,040 June SPI futures contract during the day.","entities":[[0,6,"ORG"],[276,279,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In the event, on 29 March 1996, the All Ords fell from a high of 2251.3 at 3:05 p.m. to 2225.6 at the close, a fall of 25.7 points. At 3:45 p.m., the All Ords stood at 2237.9 points. The index therefore fell 12.3 points in the last 15 minutes of trading during which time the NIP sale orders were being executed. Notwithstanding Nomura instructions, the ten Australian securities brokers managed to sell less than half of the AUD$600 million worth of stocks on 29 March 1996 at the market close but further sales took place after the market closed, mostly at the closing price. As a result of NIP having given both buying and selling orders in those stocks two sales involving no change of beneficial ownership (wash trades) were executed on behalf of NIP, at a discount of 15% and 20% respectively on the closing price of 28 March 1996. In addition to the costs incurred of brokerage and stamp duty of AUD$1.54 million, NIP made a loss of AUD$900,000 arising from the failure to dispose of all of the stocks on 29 March 1996 and further losses from the consequently unbalanced nature of NIP's Australian index arbitrage book. NIP made a profit of AUD$1.1 million on the expiry of the 2,607 sold March SPI futures contracts entered into on 29 March 1996.","entities":[[276,279,"ORG"],[329,335,"ORG"],[593,596,"ORG"],[752,755,"ORG"],[921,924,"ORG"],[1127,1130,"ORG"],[1088,1091,"ORG"]]},{"content":"This trading, to the extent conducted on behalf of NIP by NIHK, was of concern to the SFC because NIHK is registered by it. While the authorities in Australia, London and Hong Kong have each conducted their own investigation under their respective legal powers, they have closely co-operated with each other and exchanged the information that they gathered and that had been voluntarily supplied by Nomura.","entities":[[51,54,"ORG"],[58,62,"ORG"],[86,89,"ORG"],[98,102,"ORG"],[399,405,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Australian Securities and Investments Commission instituted civil legal proceedings in the Federal Court of Australia alleging that the conduct of NIP, but not NIHK or any individuals, had contravened Sections 995, 998 and 1260 of the Corporate Law, which deal with misleading and deceptive dealing in securities (S.995) and false or misleading appearance of active trading in securities (S.998) and in future contracts (S.1260). Judgment was delivered on 10 December 1998. The Federal Court found that: NIP's conduct in giving instructions to sell a large volume of stocks and the placement of bid basket at well below market levels meant that the sell order which hit the bids in the bid basket in respect of the 2 stocks were wash trades and contravened Section 998. The Court further found that the combined operation of the sell orders and the placing of the bid basket constituted conduct intended to create a false or misleading appearance of active trading in illiquid securities in contravention Section 998. NIP's measures were intended to determine the closing price of illiquid securities on the expiry date for future contracts and have influence the cash settlement price of futures contracts going to expiry and consequently created a false or misleading appearance with respect to the price for dealings in a futures contract on a futures market in contravention of Section 1260.","entities":[[4,52,"ORG"],[151,154,"ORG"],[164,168,"ORG"],[508,511,"ORG"],[778,783,"ORG"],[1022,1025,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC instituted disciplinary proceedings against NIHK and certain individuals for misconduct and on the basis that their fitness and propriety to be registered as securities and futures representatives had been impugned. Nomura challenged the timing of these disciplinary proceedings in the High Court of Hong Kong by way of judicial review. In December 1997, the High Court granted Nomura's application to stay the disciplinary proceeding thereby temporarily preventing the SFC from proceeding. In April 1998, the SFC successfully appealed to the Court of Appeal who unanimously allowed its appeal deciding that NIHK had not established sufficient evidence of a real risk of serious prejudice. NIHK sought leave to appeal this decision to the Court of Final Appeal. The Court, on 21 October 1998, dismissed the application and awarded costs to the SFC.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[52,56,"ORG"],[224,230,"ORG"],[294,304,"ORG"],[478,481,"ORG"],[518,521,"ORG"],[386,392,"ORG"],[616,620,"ORG"],[551,566,"ORG"],[698,702,"ORG"],[747,768,"ORG"],[774,779,"ORG"],[852,855,"ORG"],[367,377,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Whilst NIHK understands that NIP is giving consideration to the possibility of an appeal against the decision of the Federal Court in Australia against NIP, NIHK has taken account of this decision. NIHK acknowledges that the SFC had wholly legitimate concerns about the appropriateness of its conduct. NIHK has expressed deep regret that it did not more actively pursue an agreed outcome with the SFC. NIHK has confirmed that it has taken steps to ensure that it does not knowingly execute wash trades with the intention of depressing, raising or stabilizing the market price of any securities and does not knowingly allow its staff to engage in conduct in any market which would not meet Hong Kong standards of fitness and properness.","entities":[[7,11,"ORG"],[29,32,"ORG"],[152,155,"ORG"],[157,161,"ORG"],[225,228,"ORG"],[198,202,"ORG"],[302,306,"ORG"],[397,400,"ORG"],[402,406,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has severely publicly reprimanded NIHK for failing adequately to supervise the two employees who instructed the ten Australian securities brokers on 29 March 1996 and for allowing NIHK to be involved in conduct on behalf of NIP which it knew or should have known was likely to mislead or deceive participants in the Australian markets. The SFC has also suspended Mr. Duncan Moss, one of the employees concerned, for a period of 12 months for his misconduct. NIHK has agreed to pay the SFC's costs in full.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[42,46,"ORG"],[188,192,"ORG"],[232,235,"ORG"],[348,351,"ORG"],[375,386,"PERSON"],[466,470,"ORG"],[493,496,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded and fined Nomura International (Hong Kong) Limited (Nomura Hong Kong) HK$4.5 million for failing to report significant misconduct by a former trader in a timely manner (Note 1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[70,110,"ORG"],[112,128,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On 11 June 2013, Nomura Hong Kong informed the SFC that Mr X, a trader on secondment from Nomura Securities Co., Ltd in Japan (Nomura Japan), had incurred a US$3.3 million trading loss on 23 May 2013 and that he had been sent back to Japan on 5 June 2013 [11 June Report) (Note 2).","entities":[[17,33,"ORG"],[47,50,"ORG"],[59,60,"PERSON"],[90,116,"ORG"],[127,139,"ORG"]]},{"content":"However, the SFC subsequently found out that at the time of the 11 June Report, Nomura Hong Kong already knew Mr X had admitted to making false entries in Nomura Hong Kong’s risk management system to conceal the real risk exposure of his trades and to providing false information to Nomura Hong Kong. Yet, none of these matters were disclosed to the SFC immediately when they should have been under the Code of Conduct (Note 3).","entities":[[13,16,"ORG"],[80,96,"ORG"],[113,114,"PERSON"],[155,171,"ORG"],[283,299,"ORG"],[350,353,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC also found out that by the time Mr X left Hong Kong following the termination of his secondment with Nomura Hong Kong, Nomura Hong Kong had already noticed some apparent discrepancies between his actual trading activities and the information he had provided to management. Mr X was sent back to Nomura Japan before the SFC had been properly alerted and before Nomura Hong Kong had completed its internal investigation into his conduct.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[43,44,"PERSON"],[109,125,"ORG"],[127,143,"ORG"],[284,285,"PERSON"],[303,315,"ORG"],[327,330,"ORG"],[368,384,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC further found that by 19 June 2013, Nomura Hong Kong had already prepared a draft preliminary report of its investigation on Mr X’s trading activities, but it did not provide the report or its subsequent drafts to the SFC until the SFC made further enquiries.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[44,60,"ORG"],[136,137,"PERSON"],[240,243,"ORG"]]},{"content":"It was not until 17 July 2013, after the SFC followed up on Nomura Hong Kong’s 11 June Report, that Nomura Hong Kong informed the SFC for the first time that Mr X had engaged in inappropriate conduct. The SFC was eventually provided with the preliminary report two days later.","entities":[[41,44,"ORG"],[60,76,"ORG"],[100,116,"ORG"],[130,133,"ORG"],[205,208,"ORG"],[161,162,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Mark Steward, the SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Nomura left out highly relevant information from its first report to the SFC and then had to be chased to report properly. There can be no excuses for such delays in reporting matters requiring our immediate attention. Delays, like these, contribute to misconduct and prejudice investigations. Intermediaries must report problems to us immediately - not after internal investigation, not after legal advice has been obtained but straightaway, without leaving out any important information.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[21,24,"ORG"],[69,75,"ORG"],[142,145,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has successfully prosecuted {X1} for acting as a dealer’s representative of President Securities (Hong Kong) Limited whilst her licence was still accredited to another brokerage, and President and its managing director {X2} for aiding and abetting {X1}.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[36,40,"PERSON"],[84,124,"ORG"],[191,200,"ORG"],[227,231,"PERSON"],[256,260,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"An investigation by the SFC found that in September and October 2002, {X1} introduced clients to open securities trading accounts with her new employer, President, before her licence was transferred to reflect her new employment. (Note 1) {X2} was the managing director of President and knowingly allowed {X1} to work as its dealer’s representative.","entities":[[24,27,"ORG"],[70,74,"PERSON"],[239,243,"PERSON"],[305,309,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"{X1}, {X2} and President each pleaded guilty to one summons today before Mr T S Jenkins, a Magistrate at Western Magistracy. They were fined $10,500 in total and were ordered to pay a total cost of $5,000 to the SFC.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[6,10,"PERSON"],[15,24,"ORG"],[76,87,"PERSON"],[105,123,"ORG"],[212,215,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has obtained orders in the High Court today to disqualify Mr Godfrey Hung Kwok Wa and Mr Hermann Leung Ping Chung, former executive director and former alternate non-executive director respectively of Warderly International Holdings Ltd (Warderly) as company directors for failing to make timely disclosure of material information to the market (Note1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[71,81,"ORG"],[105,125,"PERSON"],[133,157,"PERSON"],[245,280,"ORG"],[282,290,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Honourable Mr Justice Reyes made an order disqualifying Hung from being a director or being involved in the management of any corporation, without leave of the court, for five years. Leung was disqualified for two years from being a director or being involved in the management of any listed company in Hong Kong (Note 2).","entities":[[18,31,"PERSON"],[60,64,"PERSON"],[187,192,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Both Hung and Leung accepted they:","entities":[[5,9,"PERSON"],[14,19,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"failed to manage the company with the necessary degree of skill, care, diligence and competence as reasonably expected of persons of their knowledge and experience holding their offices and functions within Warderly; and","entities":[[207,215,"ORG"]]},{"content":"failed on a number of occasions to ensure Warderly complied with the disclosure requirements under the Listing Rules and to give shareholders all the information they might reasonably expect.","entities":[[42,50,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The court had earlier made disqualification orders against four other former executive directors of Warderly as a result of their misconduct. Today’s decision brings to an end the SFC’s proceedings against the directors of Warderly (Note 3).","entities":[[100,108,"ORG"],[180,183,"ORG"],[223,231,"ORG"]]},{"content":"“Shareholders are entitled to expect competent and honest governance from listed company directors. Warderly was in a dire financial position, as the board of directors knew, yet shareholders were kept in the dark,” said Mr Mark Steward, the SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement.","entities":[[100,108,"ORG"],[224,236,"PERSON"],[242,245,"ORG"]]},{"content":"“The SFC will continue to enforce these obligations that are important to maintaining investor confidence in our markets,” Mr Steward added.","entities":[[5,8,"ORG"],[126,133,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleged that Hung and Leung should have disclosed a number of material events concerning the substantially depleted financial position of Warderly to the market, including:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[21,25,"PERSON"],[30,35,"PERSON"],[146,154,"ORG"]]},{"content":"legal proceedings had been commenced in Hong Kong and the Mainland against Warderly and its subsidiaries by banks and creditors to recover overdue loans;","entities":[[75,83,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Warderly’s operations had been substantially disrupted by labour strikes in its Mainland factory;","entities":[[0,8,"ORG"]]},{"content":"a management committee had been appointed to solve Warderly’s financial problems;","entities":[[51,59,"ORG"]]}]