[{"content":"The Court of First Instance today continued an interim order to freeze assets of up to $1,968,000,000 of Qunxing Paper Holdings Company Limited (Qunxing) and its subsidiary, Best Known Group Limited (Best Known) (Note 1).","entities":[[4,27,"ORG"],[105,143,"ORG"],[145,152,"ORG"],[174,198,"ORG"],[200,210,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) made an application to the court on 12 December 2013 without notice to Qunxing or Best Known alleging that Qunxing’s prospectus for its initial public offer (IPO) in 2007 and the announcements of its annual results for 2007 to 2011 contained materially false or misleading information (Note 2).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[115,122,"ORG"],[126,136,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC also alleges that Qunxing exaggerated its turnover in its annual results for 2006 to 2011 and this information was published in Qunxing’s IPO prospectus and its results announcements from 2007 to 2011. In a hearing before the Court of First Instance today, Qunxing denied the allegations (Note 3).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[26,33,"ORG"],[136,143,"ORG"],[265,272,"ORG"],[234,257,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The interim order freezes the total amount of funds raised by Qunxing from the investing public. The SFC is seeking orders to restore public shareholders and warrant holders who bought Qunxing shares and warrants and still hold them to the positions they were in before the transactions (Note 4).","entities":[[62,69,"ORG"],[101,104,"ORG"],[185,192,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC obtained the interim injunction to stop the dissipation of assets pending the end of its investigation and to ensure there are enough assets to satisfy any restoration or compensation orders, if such orders should be made against Qunxing.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[238,245,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Since 12 December 2013, the SFC has only identified assets worth approximately $149 million held in bank accounts and securities accounts of Qunxing and Best Known in Hong Kong. Assets in these accounts are subject to the interim injunction. The Court of First Instance today ordered that the interim injunction be continued until trial or further order and varied it to permit the company to withdraw $500,000 to meet legal costs.","entities":[[28,31,"ORG"],[141,148,"ORG"],[153,163,"ORG"],[246,269,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On 20 December 2013, the SFC also issued a direction to the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited to suspend trading in Qunxing shares in order to maintain a fair and orderly market and to protect investors (Note 5).","entities":[[25,28,"ORG"],[60,95,"ORG"],[118,125,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC’s investigation is continuing.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has suspended the licence of Ms Kwan Wai Fong for four weeks under the Securities and Futures Ordinance. At the time of the misconduct, Kwan was a dealer’s representative accredited to HT Securities Limited and HT Futures Limited.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[40,53,"PERSON"],[144,148,"PERSON"],[193,214,"ORG"],[219,237,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The action stemmed from an investigation by the SFC in September 2000. The SFC found that Kwan conducted discretionary trading on behalf of her clients in breach of her employer’s policy.","entities":[[48,51,"ORG"],[75,78,"ORG"],[90,94,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Kwan also failed to take reasonable steps to ascertain the true and full identity of a client and the client’s financial standing and investment objectives. Kwan admitted that she had declared witnessing the client signing his account opening documents when in fact she was not certain if she had met the client before.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[157,161,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Furthermore, Kwan accepted orders from a third party without confirming with the particular client whether the third party was properly authorised.  Kwan also failed to ensure that particular client had fully understood the potential risks and possessed sufficient financial resources to deal in derivatives products.","entities":[[13,17,"PERSON"],[149,153,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC found that Kwan had been guilty of misconduct. As a result, the SFC concludes that the fitness and properness of Kwan as a licensed representative has been called into question and decides to suspend her licences for four weeks.   ","entities":[[19,23,"PERSON"],[4,7,"ORG"],[72,75,"ORG"],[121,125,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “The SFC takes a serious view of any improper conduct by licensees that may prejudice the interests of their clients. Sloppy client identification, not checking if clients have properly authorised people placing orders for their accounts, not properly witnessing the execution of client account documents and making careless product recommendations to clients are all things we will punish.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"],[69,72,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Kwan is a licensed representative of HT Securities Limited and HT Futures Limited.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[37,58,"ORG"],[63,81,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had suspended the registration of Ms Tsang Lai Wah Mimi (Tsang) as a securities dealer's representative of Goldenway Securities Company Limited (Goldenway) for a period of 3 months effective from 17 November 1997.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[105,123,"PERSON"],[125,130,"PERSON"],[175,211,"ORG"],[213,222,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC's action stemmed from an investigation covering the period December 1995 to March 1996, during which it was found that Tsang had engaged in trading malpractices through a nominee account at Goldenway, which enabled Tsang to enjoy the allocation of best prices at the expense of Goldenway's clients and to realise a profit of some $12,500. It was also found that Tsang had short sold securities in contravention of Section 80 of the Securities Ordinance, for which she was successfully prosecuted at Western Magistracy on 9 September 1997. The conduct of Tsang was prejudicial to the interests of the investing public.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[127,132,"PERSON"],[223,228,"PERSON"],[198,207,"ORG"],[286,295,"ORG"],[370,375,"PERSON"],[507,525,"ORG"],[562,567,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Eastern Magistracy today sentenced Mr Simon Chui Wing Nin, a former assistant director of finance at CITIC Pacific Limited (CITIC Pacific), to 15 months of imprisonment following his conviction on two counts of insider dealing in the company’s shares prior to a profit warning issued in October 2008 (Note 1).","entities":[[4,22,"ORG"],[42,61,"PERSON"],[105,126,"ORG"],[128,141,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Chui was also fined a total of $1,018,855 and ordered to pay investigation costs of $228,469 to the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC).","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[100,133,"ORG"],[135,138,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The amount of the fine effectively disgorged the benefit earned by Chui from his trading being a loss avoided of $1.36 million (Note 2).","entities":[[67,71,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Court heard that Chui was involved in assessing the impact of the fall in the Australian dollar in mid 2008 on a number of foreign exchange derivatives contracts, including some target redemption forward contracts in Australian dollar, that CITIC Pacific had entered into to hedge its position in funding an Australian mining subsidiary.","entities":[[4,9,"ORG"],[21,25,"PERSON"],[245,258,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The target redemption forward contracts were like accumulator contracts and required CITIC Pacific to purchase a multiple amount of Australian dollar if it fell below designated strike rates.","entities":[[85,98,"ORG"]]},{"content":"By late August 2008, the Australian dollar had fallen significantly against the designated strike prices in the contracts. Chui was involved in calculating the financial impact on CITIC Pacific and knew that CITIC Pacific faced a very substantial mark to market loss that would materially impact the company’s financial position.","entities":[[180,193,"ORG"],[208,221,"ORG"],[123,127,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Whilst in possession of this information and before it was generally available, Chui sold most of his shares in CITIC Pacific.","entities":[[80,84,"PERSON"],[112,125,"ORG"]]},{"content":"On 20 October 2008, CITIC Pacific announced a mark to market loss, as at that point, of over HK$14.7 billion, sending the share price down approximately 60%.","entities":[[20,33,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Mark Steward, SFC’s executive director of Enforcement said, “There is no excuse for this kind of blatant insider dealing. The SFC will continue to attack all forms of market misconduct to protect and enhance the quality of Hong Kong’s markets for the benefit of the investing public in Hong Kong and abroad.”","entities":[[17,20,"ORG"],[3,15,"PERSON"],[129,132,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has successfully obtained orders in the Court of First Instance to wind up Gartlett Investments Ltd (Gartlett).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[84,107,"ORG"],[119,143,"ORG"],[145,153,"ORG"]]},{"content":"This action follows an SFC investigation into unlicensed futures trading by Gartlett which began last year. The SFC alleged that Gartlett was conducting an unlicensed futures dealing business on behalf of approximately 200 clients, mainly in commodity futures contracts traded on the London Metals Exchange.","entities":[[23,26,"ORG"],[76,84,"ORG"],[112,115,"ORG"],[129,137,"ORG"],[284,306,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Last September, the SFC successfully applied to the Court, on an urgent basis, to appoint Mr Rod Sutton and Mr Desmond Chiong of Ferrier Hodgson as interim administrators (Note 1). They have been in control of Gartlett’s affairs since then and the Court appointed the Official Receiver to act as the liquidator of Gartlett.","entities":[[20,23,"ORG"],[52,57,"ORG"],[129,144,"ORG"],[93,103,"PERSON"],[111,125,"PERSON"],[210,218,"ORG"],[248,253,"ORG"],[314,322,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC had alleged that Gartlett executed approximately US$950 million in commodity futures contracts in a two week period in August 2008. The SFC’s action was designed to stop ongoing misconduct and safeguard the assets of innocent customers.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[25,33,"ORG"],[144,147,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Information from the interim administrators has shown that Gartlett is insolvent and the company’s affairs need to be subject to formal administration by an insolvency expert who can trace assets and return money to creditors. The SFC therefore sought orders from the court to wind up Garlett.","entities":[[59,67,"ORG"],[231,234,"ORG"],[285,292,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has resolved compliance issues with Hantec International Limited (currently known as Cinda International FX Limited) (HIL) and Hantec Investment Consultant Limited (currently known as Cinda International Investment Consultant Limited) (HICL) (Notes 1 and 2).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[80,108,"ORG"],[129,159,"ORG"],[162,165,"ORG"],[171,207,"ORG"],[228,277,"ORG"],[280,284,"ORG"]]},{"content":"the SFC reprimands and fines HIL $4 million; and","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[29,32,"ORG"]]},{"content":"HICL voluntarily surrenders its licence to the SFC.","entities":[[0,4,"ORG"],[47,50,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Following an investigation, the SFC found that, in 2004 and 2005, HIL:","entities":[[32,35,"ORG"],[66,69,"ORG"]]},{"content":"facilitated the unlicensed activities of Cosmos Hantec Investment (NZ) Limited (Note 4);","entities":[[41,78,"ORG"]]},{"content":"failed to handle complaints and report suspected breaches to the SFC in a timely manner.","entities":[[65,68,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The decisive considerations for the SFC to enter into this agreement, rather than proceed with disciplinary action, are:","entities":[[36,39,"ORG"]]},{"content":"the failures were attributable to the former management of Hantec which has been replaced;","entities":[[59,65,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Cinda International Holdings Limited (CIH), the current parent company of HIL and HICL, has agreed to dissociate itself from certain current and former senior management members of the Hantec Group and to close down HIL and HICL. (Note 6)","entities":[[0,36,"ORG"],[38,41,"ORG"],[74,77,"ORG"],[82,86,"ORG"],[185,197,"ORG"],[216,219,"ORG"],[224,228,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC wishes to emphasise that SFC’s concerns about the operations of HIL and HICL did not involve CIH or its current management. The SFC acknowledges the cooperation and assistance of CIH in resolving this case at both investigatory and disciplinary stages.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[33,36,"ORG"],[72,75,"ORG"],[80,84,"ORG"],[101,104,"ORG"],[136,139,"ORG"],[187,190,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has suspended the licence of Mr Yeung Ching Kwong for nine months from 29 January 2010 to 28 October 2010 (Note 1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[76,93,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The disciplinary action follows an SFC investigation which found that Yeung was the account executive in relation to a number of accounts opened by Mr Ku Kam Lung, a former representative of Core Pacific-Yamaichi Securities (HK) Ltd, in the names of persons whom Ku claimed were not related to him. The SFC found that each of the account holders was related to Ku and Yeung knew that was the case. Yeung then turned a blind eye as to whether the instructions to operate each account came from the account holder or was a device by Ku to operate secret accounts on his own behalf (Note 2).","entities":[[35,38,"ORG"],[70,75,"PERSON"],[151,162,"PERSON"],[191,232,"ORG"],[263,265,"PERSON"],[303,306,"ORG"],[361,363,"PERSON"],[368,373,"PERSON"],[398,403,"PERSON"],[531,533,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"As a licensed representative, Yeung should not have allowed accounts to be opened on a false or misleading basis and he should have alerted his employer to Ku’s activities which were contrary to his employer’s control systems. As a consequence, Yeung was involved in Ku’s misconduct in operating the secret accounts.","entities":[[30,35,"PERSON"],[156,158,"PERSON"],[267,269,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"In determining the penalty, the SFC took into account Yeung’s co-operation in accepting the SFC’s findings.","entities":[[32,35,"ORG"],[54,59,"PERSON"],[92,95,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had reprimanded Pacific Challenge Securities Limited (PCSL) and one of its dealing directors, {X} for failing to have proper supervision and satisfactory internal control procedures to ensure that an unregistered employee did not act as its dealer's representative. ","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[84,120,"ORG"],[122,126,"ORG"],[162,165,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"An inquiry by the SFC found that Mr Ronald Lam Hung Tat, formerly a settlement clerk of PCSL not registered with the SFC, had, during the period 1 August to 10 September 1996, received client orders, filled in dealing tickets and confirmed the execution of the orders to the clients. {X} was responsible for PCSL's trading system and failed to ensure that PCSL had in place proper internal control system to prevent the settlement clerk from acting as a dealer's representative of PCSL. The failure of PCSL and {X} was, in the opinion of the SFC, prejudicial to the interests of the investing public.","entities":[[18,21,"ORG"],[36,55,"PERSON"],[88,92,"ORG"],[117,120,"ORG"],[284,287,"PERSON"],[308,312,"ORG"],[356,360,"ORG"],[481,485,"ORG"],[511,514,"PERSON"],[542,545,"ORG"]]},{"content":"In reprimanding PCSL and {X}, the SFC took into account their co-operation in the SFC's investigation, the fact that no losses were sustained by the investing public, and the improvements made to dealing procedures and supervision arrangements since September 1996.","entities":[[16,20,"ORG"],[25,28,"PERSON"],[34,37,"ORG"],[82,85,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has revoked the licences of Union Securities Limited (Union Securities) and its two responsible officers, Mr Ma Kin Chung and Ms Cheng Tai Ha.  Ma and Cheng have also been prohibited from re-entering the industry for life (Notes 1 & 2).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[72,96,"ORG"],[98,114,"ORG"],[153,165,"PERSON"],[173,185,"PERSON"],[188,190,"PERSON"],[195,200,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"An SFC investigation found that Union Securities, with the involvement of Ma and Cheng, misappropriated approximately $400,000 from two clients who thought they were depositing those moneys for settlement of orders. ","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[32,48,"ORG"],[74,76,"PERSON"],[81,86,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Under the term of its licence, Union Securities was prohibited from holding client assets and was required to place all orders with an execution broker.  The funds were deposited into an account controlled by Ma in the name of Union Securities’ predecessor which Ma had represented to the SFC to have been ceased to be used. Bogus statements were then issued to the two clients (Note 3).","entities":[[31,47,"ORG"],[209,211,"PERSON"],[227,243,"ORG"],[263,265,"PERSON"],[289,292,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Ma and Cheng fled Hong Kong in late 2012 and Union Securities’ premises were vacated (Note 4).","entities":[[0,2,"PERSON"],[7,12,"PERSON"],[45,61,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The investigation also found that Union Securities provided false and/or misleading information to the SFC by omitting an overdraft in its financial returns submitted under the Securities and Futures (Financial Resources) Rules.","entities":[[34,50,"ORG"],[103,106,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Due to the default of Union Securities, clients may lodge claims to recover their losses with the Investor Compensation Company Limited (Note 5).","entities":[[22,38,"ORG"],[98,135,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Following the joint operation of the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) and the Independent Commission Against Corruption (ICAC) in December 2017, the ICAC today charged five other individuals with conspiracy to defraud (Note 1). ","entities":[[37,70,"ORG"],[72,75,"ORG"],[85,126,"ORG"],[128,132,"ORG"],[156,160,"ORG"]]},{"content":"This came after the ICAC charged Mr Cho Kwai Chee, a former executive director of Convoy Global Holdings Limited (Convoy Global), formerly known as Convoy Financial Holdings Limited, with conspiracy to defraud in May 2019 (Note 2).    ","entities":[[20,24,"ORG"],[36,49,"PERSON"],[82,112,"ORG"],[114,127,"ORG"],[148,181,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Ms Chan Lai Yee and Mr Byron Tan Ye Kai, both former executive directors of Convoy Global, were charged by the ICAC with conspiring with Cho to defraud the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited (SEHK), Convoy Global and its board of directors and shareholders between 1 April 2016 and 7 December 2017 by causing Convoy Global’s subsidiary to acquire an investment company owned by Cho at a consideration of over $89 million.","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[23,39,"PERSON"],[76,89,"ORG"],[111,115,"ORG"],[137,140,"PERSON"],[156,191,"ORG"],[193,197,"ORG"],[200,213,"ORG"],[310,323,"ORG"],[379,382,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Chan was also alleged to have conspired with three individuals – Mr Mak Kwong Yiu, a former executive director of Convoy Global; Ms Wong Shuk On, a former manager of Convoy Global; and Mr Lee Yick Ming, a general manager of Gransing Securities Co., Limited (Gransing) – to defraud SEHK, Convoy Global and its board of directors and shareholders between 1 June 2014 and 7 December 2017 by inducing Convoy Global to pay over $49.6 million as commission for placement of bonds via Gransing to a brokerage firm of which Mak was a shareholder and director.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[68,81,"PERSON"],[114,127,"ORG"],[132,144,"PERSON"],[166,179,"ORG"],[188,201,"PERSON"],[224,256,"ORG"],[258,266,"ORG"],[281,285,"ORG"],[287,300,"ORG"],[397,410,"ORG"],[478,486,"ORG"],[516,519,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Cho, along with the five individuals, will appear before the Eastern Magistracy on 24 July 2019 for mention.   ","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[61,79,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC will continue to collaborate with the ICAC on this matter.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[46,50,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Please see ICAC’s press releases for further details.","entities":[[14,18,"ORG"]]},{"content":"\t- Please see the SFC’s press release dated 16 May 2019 for further details.","entities":[[18,21,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The High Court has granted an interim injunction to freeze assets of up to $1,655,167,000 in relation to former chairman of GOME Electrical Appliances Holdings Ltd, Mr Wong Kwong Yu, his wife Ms Du Juan and two companies.","entities":[[4,14,"ORG"],[124,163,"ORG"],[168,181,"PERSON"],[195,202,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"This follows an application by the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) which commenced proceedings against the two, alleging securities fraud involving dealings in the shares of GOME (Note 1).","entities":[[35,68,"ORG"],[70,73,"ORG"],[182,186,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The amount of assets frozen is the largest that the SFC has ever applied to the court to freeze.","entities":[[52,55,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Wong and Du are alleged to have organised a share repurchase by GOME in January and February 2008 in order to use GOME’s company funds to buy shares originally held by Wong so that Wong could use the proceeds of that share sale to repay a $2.4 billion personal loan to a financial institution (Note 2).","entities":[[0,4,"ORG"],[9,11,"ORG"],[64,68,"ORG"],[114,118,"ORG"],[168,172,"PERSON"],[181,185,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleges that the share repurchase had a negative impact on GOME’s financial position and was not in the best interests of the company and its shareholders. The SFC alleges, however, that it provided the demand for GOME shares and stabilised its share price when Wong disposed of his shares, thereby enabling him to earn more from his share sale.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[67,71,"ORG"],[168,171,"ORG"],[222,226,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleges that this transaction was a fraud or deception in a transaction involving securities and caused a loss of about $1.6 billion to GOME and its shareholders.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[144,148,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC is seeking orders that Wong, Du and two companies owned and controlled by them:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[37,39,"PERSON"],[31,35,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"restore the parties to any transaction, in particular GOME, to the position in which they were before the transaction was entered into; and/or","entities":[[54,58,"ORG"]]},{"content":"pay damages to GOME.","entities":[[15,19,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The injunction serves to prevent the dissipation of assets pending the conclusion of the SFC’s investigation and to ensure there are sufficient assets to satisfy any restoration or compensation orders, if orders are made against Wong, Du and the two companies.","entities":[[89,92,"ORG"],[229,233,"PERSON"],[235,237,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC is conducting further inquiries to identify these assets while investigations continue.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The order is an interim injunction obtained by the SFC ex parte. The defendants have not yet had a chance to reply to the SFC’s allegations.","entities":[[51,54,"ORG"],[122,125,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission announces today that it has suspended the registration of Mr Wu Ka Leung (Wu), a dealer's representative under the Securities Ordinance, for a period of six months.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[99,110,"PERSON"],[112,114,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The suspension follows an inquiry into Wu's conduct before and after he has been registered as a dealer's representative. The inquiry revealed that Wu had:","entities":[[39,41,"PERSON"],[148,150,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC concluded that Wu's conduct fell below the standards of a registered dealer's representative and his fitness and properness to remain registered has been seriously called into question. His failure to settle his debt owed to his client promptly also adversely affected his financial integrity. The SFC therefore decided to suspend his registration for six months.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,25,"PERSON"],[306,309,"ORG"]]},{"content":"An SFC spokesman said: \"A registered person must always ensure that client assets are accounted for properly and promptly. A registered person must also closely monitor his personal financial position to ensure that his fitness and properness will not be undermined or compromised by his personal indebtedness. The SFC will treat any such breaches seriously.\"","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[315,318,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has suspended Mr Chan Ho Yin for 15 months from 14 June 2006 to 13 September 2007 for manipulating the price of certain shares, impersonating a client to place orders with another brokerage, and failing to obtain written authorisation from clients to conduct discretionary transactions in their accounts in breach of the Code of Conduct (Notes 1 and 2).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[25,36,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"An SFC investigation revealed that Chan, a licensed representative of Celestial Securities Limited, had conspired with others to conduct trading activities by operating two client accounts on 4, 5 and 6 December 2002 with the intention to raise the share price of Akup International Holding Limited (Note 3). Chan used the two accounts to dominate the buy side by sweeping the existing ask orders just a few minutes before market close. The aggressive buying raised the share price of Akup to close at 12.5%, 14.5% and 11.1% higher than the nominal prices as at 15:57 hours on those three days respectively.","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[35,39,"PERSON"],[70,98,"ORG"],[264,298,"ORG"],[309,313,"ORG"],[485,489,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Chan operated the two client accounts without written authorisation and failed to keep proper dealing records on those three days. Chan was also found to have impersonated a person residing in Taiwan to place orders for that person’s account at Rexcapital Securities Limited in late 2002.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[131,135,"PERSON"],[245,274,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC concludes that Chan has been guilty of misconduct and his fitness and properness has been seriously called into question, and decides to suspend his licence.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,27,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Eugène Goyne, an SFC Senior Director of Enforcement, said: “Market manipulation is a serious criminal offence which could result in an immediate custodial sentence. Licensees who knowingly render assistance to market manipulators, or participate in or orchestrate the manipulative activities will also face long suspensions, heavy disciplinary fines or even revocation of their licences.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[20,23,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has reprimanded Ms Chau Sau Lai Betty, a licensed representative of Hooray Securities Limited, and fined her $6,000 for breaching the Code of Conduct. The reprimand and fine are the result of a settlement between the SFC and Chau (Notes 1 and 2).","entities":[[225,228,"ORG"],[233,237,"PERSON"],[27,45,"PERSON"],[4,7,"ORG"],[76,101,"ORG"]]},{"content":"An SFC investigation found that between July and September 2004, Chau had breached the Code of Conduct by engaging in the following acts:","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"],[65,69,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"conducting discretionary trades without proper written authorisation from a client. The SFC noted that the client had previously agreed to give Chau a written authorisation;","entities":[[88,91,"ORG"],[144,148,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"putting the financial interest of Hooray Securities at risk by carrying on trading for the client despite the client’s failure in settling previous transactions more than three years ago;","entities":[[34,51,"ORG"]]},{"content":"withholding a cheque issued by Hooray Securities to the client without the client’s consent; and","entities":[[31,48,"ORG"]]},{"content":"obtaining the client’s daily statements without the client’s consent and breaching Hooray Securities’ internal policy.","entities":[[83,100,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC considers the settlement to be in the interest of the investing public and in the public interest. In deciding the penalty, the SFC has taken into account the Disciplinary Fining Guidelines (Note 3) and the following:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Chau has a clear record;","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"there was no loss caused to Hooray Securities;","entities":[[28,45,"ORG"]]},{"content":"the client benefited at the expense of Chau who had to reimburse Hooray Securities for unsettled transactions; and","entities":[[39,43,"PERSON"],[65,82,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Chau co-operated with the SFC in settling the disciplinary action.","entities":[[26,29,"ORG"],[0,4,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: \"All licensed representatives must adhere to the Code of Conduct strictly and without fail. Such compliance is for the benefit of the licensed representative and for the promotion of good standards in the industry. Chau’s worst failing is her continuing to trade for the client when the client had not settled her position thereby putting Hooray Securities in financial risk. Chau learned her lesson the hard way as she had to cover her client’s loss.\"","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"],[279,283,"PERSON"],[440,444,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission announced today that it had, on 13 October 1998 successfully prosecuted {X1},{X2}, & {X3}, for short selling securities on the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited between March and April 1997 through Chung Nam Securities Ltd.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[165,200,"ORG"],[238,262,"ORG"],[110,114,"PERSON"],[115,119,"PERSON"],[123,127,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"{X1},{X2}, & {X3} pleaded guilty before Ms Polly Lo at Western Magistracy to a total of 4 summonses in relation to their short selling of securities in contravention of Section 80 of the Securities Ordinance. Section 80[1) of the Securities Ordinance prohibits the sale of securities when the seller does not have a presently exercisable and unconditional right to sell.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[5,9,"PERSON"],[13,17,"PERSON"],[43,51,"PERSON"],[55,73,"ORG"]]},{"content":"{X1},{X2}, & {X3}were fined a total of $8,500 and were ordered to pay investigation costs totalling $10,400 to the SFC.","entities":[[0,4,"PERSON"],[5,9,"PERSON"],[115,118,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has suspended the licence of Mr Leung Bing Yiu for four months from 15 December 2011 to 14 April 2012 for his failure to comply with the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO) (Note 1).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[76,90,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Leung was convicted at the Eastern Magistrate’s Court on 26 September 2011 of the offence of carrying on securities advisory business without being licensed, in contravention of section 114 of the SFO (Note 2).","entities":[[0,5,"PERSON"],[27,53,"ORG"]]},{"content":"During the period between January and June 2010, Leung entered into an arrangement with an unlicensed person who placed advertisements in a newspaper promoting services of advising on securities.","entities":[[49,54,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The advertisement stated that subscribers who pay monthly fees of $299 would receive daily messages via short messages services containing instantaneous advice on securities and derivatives from Leung. Leung composed the trading advices to be sent to the subscribers.","entities":[[195,200,"PERSON"],[202,207,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC considers that Leung is not a fit and proper person to remain licensed as a result of his conviction. In deciding on the sanction, the SFC has taken into account of Leung’s cooperation in the disciplinary proceedings.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,28,"PERSON"],[143,146,"ORG"],[173,178,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has commenced proceedings in the High Court to seek disqualification and compensation orders against the current chairman, Mr Cheung Keng Ching, a current executive director, Ms Chou Mei, and a former executive director, Mr Lau Ka Man Kevin, of Rontex International Holdings Ltd (Rontex), a Hong Kong-listed company engaged in the trading of garments and premium products.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[77,87,"ORG"],[170,187,"PERSON"],[222,230,"PERSON"],[268,283,"PERSON"],[289,322,"ORG"],[324,330,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleges that the three directors:","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"]]},{"content":"breached their fiduciary duty and/or duty of care owed to Rontex;","entities":[[58,64,"ORG"]]},{"content":"failed to ensure Rontex fully complied with disclosure requirements under the Listing Rules; and","entities":[[17,23,"ORG"]]},{"content":"failed to exercise reasonable skill, care and diligence in entering into a number of transactions, resulting in Rontex suffering losses and damages of about $19 million.","entities":[[112,118,"ORG"]]},{"content":"According to the SFC’s case, the alleged breaches are centred on four investments involving:","entities":[[17,20,"ORG"]]},{"content":"the acquisition of 3.62 million shares in Grandtop International Holdings Ltd, a company listed on the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong, for $9.263 million, which represented an unjustifiable premium of 45% over the prevailing market price for such shares;","entities":[[42,77,"ORG"],[103,130,"ORG"]]},{"content":"the acquisition of $15 million in options for shares in Macau Asia Investments Ltd, a United States-incorporated company listed as a Pink Sheet stock on the American Stock Exchange;","entities":[[56,82,"ORG"],[157,180,"ORG"]]},{"content":"three payments totalling $27.7 million to a Mainland Chinese citizen named Wan Lin; and","entities":[[75,82,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"an investment of $8.454 million in Beijing Kut Ka Lok Fashion Apparels Ltd.","entities":[[35,74,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC alleges Rontex suffered losses and damages of about $19 million as a consequence of the alleged misconduct by the three directors. The SFC is seeking orders that the three directors be disqualified as company directors and that they pay compensation to Rontex.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[16,22,"ORG"],[143,146,"ORG"],[261,267,"ORG"]]},{"content":"This is the second case this month in which the SFC has sought court orders to commence compensation proceedings by a listed company against company directors for alleged misconduct (Note 2).","entities":[[48,51,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The High Court is scheduled to hear the petition on 12 November 2008. A summary of the transactions and the allegations is posted on www.sfc.hk.","entities":[[4,14,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had suspended the registration of Ms Lai Sze Man Dora (Lai), a dealer's representative of Get Nice Investment Limited (Get Nice), for one month under the Securities Ordinance.","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[105,121,"PERSON"],[123,126,"PERSON"],[158,185,"ORG"],[187,195,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The suspension stems from an inquiry in which the SFC found that from 1991 to 1995, Ms Lai had on several occasions improperly signed as a witness to prospective clients' signature on account opening documents when she had in fact not been present when the prospective clients had signed the documents. Further, it was found that Ms Lai knowingly allowed an unauthorized person to operate a client's account.","entities":[[333,336,"PERSON"],[50,53,"ORG"],[87,90,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Eastern Magistracy today granted an application by the Department of Justice to have the Securities and Futures Commission’s (SFC) fourth criminal prosecution this year for insider dealing transferred to the District Court.","entities":[[4,22,"ORG"],[59,80,"ORG"],[93,126,"ORG"],[130,133,"ORG"],[212,226,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Defendants Allen Lam Kar Fai and Ryan Fong Yen-hwung face a total of three charges of insider dealing (Note 1).","entities":[[11,28,"PERSON"],[33,52,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Lam and Fong will appear for plea in the District Court on 4 November 2008.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[8,12,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Eastern Magistrates’ Court today convicted Mr Gordon Mui Kwong Yin for providing online advice on trading in futures contracts without a licence and remanded him in jail custody pending sentence (Note 1).","entities":[[4,30,"ORG"],[50,70,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Court heard that between November 2009 and July 2010, whilst unlicensed, Mui, in the name of “Brandon Chan” also known as “Futures King”, offered to provide trading advice on Hang Seng Index and the Hang Seng China Enterprises Index futures contracts in the form of “futures trade signals” on a website (https://sites.google.com/site/futuresking88) (Note 2).","entities":[[4,9,"ORG"],[77,80,"PERSON"],[98,110,"PERSON"],[179,194,"ORG"],[203,236,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The website charged a subscription fee of $300 per “signal” or $900 for four “signals” and claimed that by following the advice, subscribers would be able to make a profit of 500 to 800 index points in the investment of the futures contracts each time. Mui received approximately $128,700 from 113 subscribers for his advisory service.","entities":[[253,256,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Mui pleaded guilty to the offence. Magistrate Mr Joseph To indicated that one concern he has is that in sentencing, the amount of fine to be imposed should be sufficient in stripping the defendant of the profits earned by the defendant in the illegal activity, otherwise it would render the legislation ineffective and lacks deterrent effect.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[49,58,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) reminds investors that they should not deal with anyone who promises guaranteed riches from securities or futures dealing. They should always check whether the person is licensed by the SFC to give advice (Note 3).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[230,233,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has banned Mr Ye Feng, a former vice president of the Bank of Communications Co., Ltd. (BOCOM), from re-entering the industry for life following his conviction for bribery (Notes 1 & 2).","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[58,65,"PERSON"],[98,130,"ORG"],[132,137,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Eastern Magistrates’ Court found Ye, responsible for handling securities transactions for BOCOM’s clients at the material time, guilty of soliciting illegal commission payments of approximately $919,120 from a client for profits generated from the client’s trades in Hong Kong stocks.","entities":[[4,30,"ORG"],[37,39,"PERSON"],[94,99,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC considers that Ye is not a fit and proper person to be licensed or registered to carry on regulated activities as a result of his criminal conviction.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[23,25,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC has issued a reprimand to Mr Wong Ka Wai and fined him $30,000 (Note 1).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[37,48,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The disciplinary action follows an SFC investigation into the complaint lodged by Wong’s clients who invested in viatical settlements as a result of his recommendation (Note 2).","entities":[[35,38,"ORG"],[82,86,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC found that Wong, whilst acting as the financial consultant of Convoy Financial Services Limited, failed to","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[19,23,"PERSON"],[70,103,"ORG"]]},{"content":"● be conversant with the risks associated with the investment product as required by Convoy;","entities":[[85,91,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Mark Steward, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Viaticals are exotic products unlikely to be suitable for most investors. Wong was incompetent in giving investment advice to clients. Licence holders should beware that failure to advise clients of all the material risks of any investment product, will result in suspension or fine, regardless of how the product is labelled.”","entities":[[3,15,"PERSON"],[17,20,"ORG"],[139,143,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"“This decision reflects both the need to protect the investing public, and the need to discourage Wong and others from repeating the misconduct. In this case, the SFC decided to impose a fine because there was evidence Wong did not use his SFC licence to conduct the bulk of his business, and so suspension or revocation of the licence was insufficient to discourage Wong from repeating the misconduct,” he added.","entities":[[163,166,"ORG"],[219,223,"PERSON"],[98,102,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"The SFC has successfully prosecuted Ms Wan Wai Chi, Katherine for failing to comply with notices issued by SFC’s investigators requiring attendance at interviews.","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[39,61,"PERSON"],[107,110,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Three notices under Section 33[4) of the Securities and Futures Commission Ordinance were issued to Wan requiring her to attend interviews with investigators in connection with an investigation into market manipulation between August and November 2002. However, Wan failed to attend the interviews without reasonable excuse.","entities":[[262,265,"PERSON"],[100,103,"PERSON"]]},{"content":"Wan pleaded guilty to three summonses today before Mr Johnny Chan, a Magistrate at Eastern Magistracy. Wan was fined $30,000 and ordered to pay investigation costs of $12,296 to the SFC.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[54,65,"ORG"],[83,101,"ORG"],[103,106,"PERSON"],[182,185,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The SFC has suspended Ms Law Oi Yee, Ronnie, a former responsible officer of Angus Moore Limited for 12 months from 17 July 2008 to 16 July 2009 for supervisory failures and for providing misleading information to the SFC (Note 1).","entities":[[4,7,"ORG"],[25,43,"PERSON"],[77,96,"ORG"],[218,221,"ORG"]]},{"content":"An SFC investigation found that from April 2005 to August 2006:","entities":[[3,6,"ORG"]]},{"content":"two unlicensed staff members of Angus Moore provided investment advice to clients;a licensed staff member of Angus Moore issued to clients mutual funds promotional documents not authorized by the SFC ;client agreements were only signed and acknowledged after the clients subscribed to mutual funds, breaching the SFC Code of Conduct ; andAngus Moore’s staff failed to properly record investment recommendations they made to clients.","entities":[[109,120,"ORG"],[196,199,"ORG"],[313,316,"ORG"],[344,349,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Law was in charge of the operations at the time when the failures were identified. Law was also found to have provided misleading information to the SFC in relation to the activities of two unlicensed staff who gave investment advice to clients during the SFC’s inspection of Angus Moore.","entities":[[0,3,"PERSON"],[83,86,"PERSON"],[149,152,"ORG"],[256,259,"ORG"],[276,287,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced that yesterday it had successfully prosecuted HK Stock Limited (HK Stock) for carrying on a business of dealing in securities without being registered as a dealer and also {X}, one of HK Stock's directors for consenting to this. Mr Stephen Shiu Yuek Yuen (Stephen Shiu) who was also summonsed for consenting to the unregistered dealing, in his capacity as a director of HK Stock, was acquitted. ","entities":[[4,37,"ORG"],[39,42,"ORG"],[100,116,"ORG"],[118,126,"ORG"],[226,229,"PERSON"],[238,246,"ORG"],[286,308,"PERSON"],[310,322,"PERSON"],[424,432,"ORG"]]},{"content":"Mr Paul Kelly at Western Magistracy fined HK Stock and {X} the sum of $10,000 and $3,000 respectively and ordered them to pay investigation costs of $2,465 and $8,150 respectively to the SFC.","entities":[[3,13,"PERSON"],[17,35,"ORG"],[42,50,"ORG"],[55,58,"PERSON"],[187,190,"ORG"]]},{"content":"The investigation revealed that HK Stock agreed with certain brokers that in return for a membership joining fee and monthly fees payable to HK Stock, broker members would be provided with a trading platform through which their clients could place orders via the Internet to trade in securities. During the period 1 May 2000 to 30 November 2000 HK Stock, with the consent of {X}, ran a \"Simulated Trading Competition\" by which members of the public were solicited to trade 'on-line' via these broker members. The court found that this marketing strategy on the part of HK Stock induced certain members of the public to enter into agreements with broker members to trade in securities thereby constituting unregistered dealing on the part of HK Stock.","entities":[[32,40,"ORG"],[141,149,"ORG"],[345,353,"ORG"],[375,378,"PERSON"],[569,577,"ORG"],[741,749,"ORG"]]},{"content":"A SFC spokesman said that any organization intending to induce persons to deal in securities through a broker or to introduce them to a broker for that purpose, is reminded that they are required to be registered with the SFC. Any organization intending to offer an Internet trading service to brokers is advised to seek legal advice as to whether registration with the SFC is required. Organizations are reminded that the SFC has an Internet surveillance team to monitor Internet activities.","entities":[[2,5,"ORG"],[222,225,"ORG"],[423,426,"ORG"],[370,373,"ORG"]]}]