[["The Securities and Futures Commission announced today the decision of the Securities and Futures Appeals Tribunal to suspend the registration of Mr Kao Ying Lun, John (Kao) as an investment adviser for a period of 4 months effective 19 October 1998.", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [74, 113, "ORGANIZATION"], [148, 166, "PERSON"], [168, 171, "PERSON"]]}], ["The suspension resulted from an inquiry by the SFC into Kao's role in relation to an announcement concerning a proposed acquisition of a shareholding in Tungtex (Holdings) Company Limited (Tungtex) and a general offer for that company in 1995 which did not in the event proceed. Kao was a director and substantial shareholder of the firm which acted as financial adviser to the proposed acquisition.", {"entities": [[47, 50, "ORGANIZATION"], [56, 59, "PERSON"], [153, 187, "ORGANIZATION"], [189, 196, "ORGANIZATION"], [279, 282, "PERSON"]]}], ["Kao failed to act with due skill care and diligence in carrying out the responsibilities of a financial adviser to satisfy himself that the proposed acquirer could and would continue to be able to implement the proposed acquisition and that there were sufficient funds to satisfy the general offer in full before confirming to the market that such financial resources were available.", {"entities": [[0, 3, "PERSON"]]}], ["Please find attached a press release the SFC issues on behalf of Mr John Lees, Administrator of Whole Win Securities Limited.", {"entities": [[41, 44, "ORGANIZATION"], [68, 77, "PERSON"], [96, 124, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has successfully prosecuted China Northern Enterprises Investment Fund Limited and its director {X} under Part XV of the Securities and Futures Ordinance. China Northern was a substantial shareholder of Ningbo Yidong Electronic Company Limited at the material time.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [36, 86, "ORGANIZATION"], [163, 177, "ORGANIZATION"], [211, 251, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["China Northern pleaded guilty to four summonses relating to its failure to notify within the prescribed period the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong and Ningbo regarding its trading in Ningbo shares on 14 November 2003 and 25 November 2003 respectively, which caused China Northern ceased to have or to have a notifiable interest in Ningbo.", {"entities": [[0, 14, "ORGANIZATION"], [115, 142, "ORGANIZATION"], [147, 153, "ORGANIZATION"], [179, 185, "ORGANIZATION"], [261, 275, "ORGANIZATION"], [327, 333, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In addition, {X}, a director of China Northern, pleaded guilty to four summonses relating to his failure to ensure that China Northern made the above-mentioned disclosures.", {"entities": [[32, 46, "ORGANIZATION"], [120, 134, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Mr Ian Candy, a Magistrate at Eastern Magistracy, fined China Northern and {X} a total of $12,000 and $8,000 respectively and ordered {X} to pay investigation costs of $17,000 to the SFC.", {"entities": [[30, 48, "ORGANIZATION"], [56, 70, "ORGANIZATION"], [183, 186, "ORGANIZATION"], [3, 12, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded and fined The Pride Fund Management Limited (Pride Fund Management) $400,000 over its failure to enter into mediation with an eligible claimant under the Financial Dispute Resolution Scheme (FDRS) administered by the Financial Dispute Resolution Centre (FDRC). ", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [70, 103, "ORGANIZATION"], [105, 126, "ORGANIZATION"], [277, 312, "ORGANIZATION"], [314, 318, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The disciplinary action follows a review of the SFC’s decision to sanction Pride Fund Management by the Securities and Futures Appeals Tribunal (SFAT). This is the first time the SFC has enforced the Code of Conduct obligations of intermediaries to comply with the FDRS (Notes 1, 2, 3 & 4).", {"entities": [[48, 51, "ORGANIZATION"], [75, 96, "ORGANIZATION"], [179, 182, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The FDRS, which is administered by the FDRC, is an important part of Hong Kong’s regulatory framework under which banks and brokers are obliged to enter into mediation and potentially arbitration proceedings to resolve certain financial disputes with clients or persons who have been provided with financial services. Pride Fund Management refused to mediate a dispute with an eligible claimant despite requests by FDRC staff. The FDRC issued a Notice of Non-Compliance to Pride Fund Management in June 2013. It was only after the SFC commenced disciplinary proceedings against Pride Fund Management that it eventually agreed to enter into mediation with the claimant (Note 5).", {"entities": [[39, 43, "ORGANIZATION"], [318, 339, "ORGANIZATION"], [431, 435, "ORGANIZATION"], [473, 494, "ORGANIZATION"], [531, 534, "ORGANIZATION"], [578, 599, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Pride Fund Management claimed it had not understood that it was required to comply with the FDRS. The Hon Mr Justice Hartmann NPJ, Chairman of the SFAT, who upheld the SFC’s decision but varied the fine from $700,000 to $400,000, found that Pride Fund Management’s non-compliance was deliberate and that although the obligations under the FDRS may not be generally understood, after the SFAT’s reasons in this case and the public reprimand there can be no further excuse “…on the part of members of the financial industry for a lack of understanding, at least, of the scheme’s basic architecture”. The Hon Mr Justice Hartmann also warned that “…sterner penalties can be expected in the future….” (Note 6).", {"entities": [[0, 21, "ORGANIZATION"], [109, 129, "PERSON"], [147, 151, "ORGANIZATION"], [168, 171, "ORGANIZATION"], [241, 262, "ORGANIZATION"], [387, 391, "ORGANIZATION"], [609, 625, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The FDRS provides an independent and impartial dispute resolution process to facilitate the resolution of monetary disputes between individual customers and financial institutions in Hong Kong. The SFC takes non-compliance with the FDRS seriously and will continue to take action against SFC-licensed intermediaries who fail to comply with the scheme.", {"entities": [[198, 201, "ORGANIZATION"], [288, 291, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it has revoked the registration of Ms Kuo Wai Lan, Peggy (Kuo) in respect of her registration as a dealer's representative under the Securities Ordinance. Kuo ceased to be employed by CAF Securities Company Limited (CAF) on 28 November 1997. ", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [220, 223, "PERSON"], [103, 121, "PERSON"], [123, 126, "PERSON"], [249, 279, "ORGANIZATION"], [281, 284, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The revocation stemmed from an inquiry in which the SFC found that during the period June to November 1997, when Kuo was an accountant and registered dealer's representative of CAF, she:", {"entities": [[52, 55, "ORGANIZATION"], [113, 116, "ORGANIZATION"], [177, 180, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["maintained three nominee accounts at CAF for her extensive personal trading activities;", {"entities": [[37, 40, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["concealed the substantial losses in these nominee accounts from CAF's management by inputting fictitious entries, or causing fictitious entries to be input into the settlement system;", {"entities": [[64, 67, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["knowingly allowed her unsettled balances in these nominee accounts to be effectively financed partly by CAF's internal resources and partly by CAF's clients' monies; and", {"entities": [[104, 107, "ORGANIZATION"], [143, 146, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["informed CAF's management that CAF did not have sufficient liquidity to clear trades but did not inform them that the company's then tight liquidity position was at least in part, if not wholly, due to the aforesaid unsettled balances. Moreover, she proposed CAF's directors issue personal cheques in favour of CAF and subsequently dishonour the same to draw on CAF's uncleared cheques facilities. She too had issued personal cheques in favour of CAF which were dishonoured for the same purpose.", {"entities": [[9, 12, "ORGANIZATION"], [31, 34, "ORGANIZATION"], [259, 262, "ORGANIZATION"], [311, 314, "ORGANIZATION"], [362, 365, "ORGANIZATION"], [447, 450, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Having regard to all the circumstances, the SFC found that Kuo's fitness and properness as a registered person has been seriously impugned and has revoked her dealer's representative registration.", {"entities": [[44, 47, "ORGANIZATION"], [59, 62, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC notes that Lehman Brothers Asia Limited has suspended the provision of secondary market quotes or liquidity for the Lehman Brothers unlisted structured products pending further announcements.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [19, 47, "ORGANIZATION"], [124, 139, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court of First Instance today struck out proceedings commenced by the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) against Tiger Asia Management LLC (Tiger Asia) and three of its officers (collectively the Tiger Asia parties) seeking orders in relation to their alleged contraventions of Hong Kong’s insider dealing and market manipulation laws (Note 1 & 2).", {"entities": [[74, 107, "ORGANIZATION"], [109, 112, "ORGANIZATION"], [122, 147, "ORGANIZATION"], [149, 159, "ORGANIZATION"], [205, 215, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court ordered that the SFC’s proceedings against the Tiger Asia parties be struck out following an earlier decision on 21 June 2011 that the Court did not have jurisdiction under section 213 of the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO) to find contraventions of the insider dealing and market manipulation laws. This meant that the Court did not have power to make orders the SFC sought under section 213 of the SFO premised on a contravention of the insider dealing or market manipulation laws absent a prior finding of the Market Misconduct Tribunal (MMT) or a criminal court.", {"entities": [[27, 30, "ORGANIZATION"], [57, 67, "ORGANIZATION"], [381, 384, "ORGANIZATION"], [417, 420, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has previously indicated its intention to appeal the Court’s June decision on the scope of section 213.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC will also appeal today’s decision to strike out the whole of the proceedings against the Tiger Asia parties.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [97, 107, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC argued that despite the Court’s June decision, the Court could still make the order sought by the SFC under section 213 of the SFO to ban the Tiger Asia parties from dealing in Hong Kong listed securities and their derivatives on the basis that it appeared to the SFC that the Tiger Asia parties had breached these laws or been involved in breaches or may do so in the future.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [106, 109, "ORGANIZATION"], [150, 160, "ORGANIZATION"], [285, 295, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC argued that the order on the trading ban did not require the Court to find a contravention and that this part of the SFC’s case should not be struck out.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [125, 128, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court considered that the SFC had not argued this in the earlier hearing and held that it did not have jurisdiction to make orders like this on the basis of prima facie evidence of a contravention.", {"entities": [[30, 33, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded and fined Guotai Junan Securities (Hong Kong) Limited (Guotai Junan) $25.2 million for multiple internal control failures and regulatory breaches in connection with anti-money laundering, handling of third party fund transfers and placing activities, as well as detection of wash trades and late reporting (Note 1).", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [70, 113, "ORGANIZATION"], [115, 127, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Despite red flags suggesting some of the third party fund transfers were unusual or suspicious, Guotai Junan failed to adequately monitor the activities of its clients, conduct appropriate scrutiny of the fund transfers, identify transactions that were suspicious and report them to the Joint Financial Intelligence Unit in a timely manner (Note 2).", {"entities": [[96, 108, "ORGANIZATION"], [287, 320, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Guotai Junan also did not ensure that its policies and procedures regarding anti-money laundering and counter-financing of terrorism (AML/CFT) were properly and effectively implemented with respect to third party fund transfers.  Specifically, the SFC found that there were:", {"entities": [[0, 12, "ORGANIZATION"], [248, 251, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In addition, Guotai Junan processed 5,406 third party deposits from July 2015 to June 2016 without always documenting the identity of the depositors, their relationship with the account holders, and the reasons for these third party deposits, contrary to the firm’s written policies and procedures.", {"entities": [[13, 25, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["While acting as the placing agent for the global offering of a Hong Kong-listed company’s shares between December 2015 and January 2016, Guotai Junan failed to take reasonable steps to ascertain whether the clients’ subscription applications were consistent with its knowledge of their background and source of funds, and make appropriate enquiries when there were grounds for suspicion.", {"entities": [[137, 149, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Despite such red flags, Guotai Junan did not take reasonable steps to verify the ultimate beneficial owners of the clients’ accounts and their source of funds, nor make appropriate enquiries to ascertain whether the clients were independent of the listed company.  In the end, three of the five placees, who were allotted 11% of the listed company’s shares of the total placing under the international tranche, turned out to be the listed company’s employees (Note 3).", {"entities": [[24, 36, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC further found that Guotai Junan failed to detect 590 potential wash trades in a timely manner between January 2014 and July 2016 due to a lack of adequate written trade monitoring procedures or guidelines and technical failures of its transaction pattern monitoring system.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [27, 39, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["However, despite becoming aware in July 2016 of 210 potential wash trades which could not be detected in a timely manner as a result of the system failure, Guotai Junan did not report these 210 trades to the SFC until seven months later in February 2017.", {"entities": [[156, 168, "ORGANIZATION"], [208, 211, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The above-mentioned findings led the SFC to come to the view that Guotai Junan’s conduct failed to comply with regulatory requirements under the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing (Financial Institutions) Ordinance, the Guideline on Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing, the Internal Control Guidelines and the Code of Conduct (Notes 4 & 5).", {"entities": [[37, 40, "ORGANIZATION"], [66, 78, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In deciding the disciplinary sanction, the SFC took into account that:", {"entities": [[43, 46, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- there were multiple AML/CFT related failures and Guotai Junan was handling a substantial number or amount of third party fund transfers;", {"entities": [[52, 64, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- Guotai Junan’s failures in complying with AML/CFT requirements lasted for an extensive period of time, including its failure to put in place written procedures to identify third party deposits from September 2009 - when the Prevention of Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Guidance Note came into effect - to around September 2016;", {"entities": [[3, 15, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- while the failures in the transaction pattern monitoring system were primarily attributable to the third party vendor, Guotai Junan failed to detect wash trades for more than two years and around 590 potential wash trades were not detected;", {"entities": [[122, 134, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- the SFC has sent a clear message in previous disciplinary cases that licensed corporations are required to report misconduct to the SFC immediately upon discovery of such misconduct;", {"entities": [[7, 10, "ORGANIZATION"], [135, 138, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- Guotai Junan has taken prompt remedial measures to rectify the deficiencies in its trade monitoring system and procedures once identified, and has proactively enhanced its policies and procedures in relation to AML/CFT; and", {"entities": [[3, 15, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- in resolving the SFC’s concerns, Guotai Junan undertook to provide the SFC with a report prepared by an independent reviewer within 12 months confirming that all the identified concerns were properly rectified.", {"entities": [[36, 48, "ORGANIZATION"], [74, 77, "ORGANIZATION"], [20, 23, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\"The disciplinary action against Guotai Junan for serious systemic deficiencies and failures across its internal controls should serve as a stark reminder to licensed corporations the importance of having adequate and effective safeguards in place to mitigate the real risk of becoming a conduit to facilitate illicit activities, such as money laundering, when exposed to potentially suspicious transactions,\" said Mr Thomas Atkinson, the SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement.", {"entities": [[33, 45, "ORGANIZATION"], [439, 442, "ORGANIZATION"], [418, 433, "PERSON"]]}], ["The District Court today acquitted IPFUND Asset Management Limited (IPFUND) and Mr Ronald Sin Chung Yin of charges of dealing in securities without a licence (Note 1).  ", {"entities": [[35, 66, "ORGANIZATION"], [68, 74, "ORGANIZATION"], [83, 103, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Judge found that IPFUND was carrying on a business in operating 16 collective investment schemes at the relevant time. However he found that when the investors were investing in these schemes, they were in fact acquiring shares in private shell companies which held the real properties in question and as the definition of \"securities\" excluded shares of private companies, he held that there was no \"dealing in securities\". ", {"entities": [[21, 27, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The case was prosecuted by the Prosecutions Division of the Department of Justice. The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) is reviewing the decision.", {"entities": [[60, 81, "ORGANIZATION"], [31, 52, "ORGANIZATION"], [83, 120, "ORGANIZATION"], [122, 125, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded Solid King Securities Limited (Solid King) and fined it $700,000 for failing to comply with the telephone recording requirements under the Code of Conduct and put in place effective internal control procedures to safeguard its telephone recording system and monitor its clients’ telephone orders (Notes 1 & 2).", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [60, 89, "ORGANIZATION"], [91, 101, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["During the relevant period, Solid King did not conduct any routine checks on its telephone recording system, nor did it review the recordings of client telephone orders on a regular basis. The loose electric cable was detected and re-attached to the telephone recording system by Solid King on 2 January 2014 and it discovered that its telephone recording system had failed to record client order instructions during the relevant period when it was required by the SFC on 8 January 2014 to produce the telephone recordings of certain client orders. As a result of the undetected defect in its telephone recording system, Solid King was unable to produce the telephone recordings required by the SFC.", {"entities": [[28, 38, "ORGANIZATION"], [280, 290, "ORGANIZATION"], [621, 631, "ORGANIZATION"], [695, 698, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Telephone recording of client orders is an integral part of an intermediary’s audit trails. It protects the interests of both the intermediary and its clients and serves as an effective compliance monitoring tool for preventing or detecting irregularities or fraudulent activities. Solid King’s failures have called into question its fitness and properness as an SFC licensee (Note 3).", {"entities": [[282, 292, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Following an inquiry into misconduct of a member of the staff of Goldenway Securities Company Limited (Goldenway) during the period December 1995 to March 1996, the SFC announced today that it had reprimanded Goldenway and its dealing director, {X}, for failing during the relevant period:", {"entities": [[65, 101, "ORGANIZATION"], [103, 112, "ORGANIZATION"], [165, 168, "ORGANIZATION"], [209, 218, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- to implement sufficient internal controls within Goldenway to detect and prevent unlawful short selling by clients and staff of Goldenway;", {"entities": [[52, 61, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- to introduce and have in place satisfactory internal controls and procedures within Goldenway so as to ensure Goldenway's clients were receiving best execution for their orders; and", {"entities": [[87, 96, "ORGANIZATION"], [113, 122, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- to adequately supervise Goldenway's staff.", {"entities": [[27, 36, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In issuing the reprimand, the SFC took into account the action taken by Goldenway to remedy these failures.", {"entities": [[30, 33, "ORGANIZATION"], [72, 81, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has commenced proceedings in the Market Misconduct Tribunal (MMT) against Mr Andrew Left of Citron Research, alleging market misconduct involving the publication of a research report on Evergrande Real Estate Group Limited (Evergrande) in June 2012 (Note 1).", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [121, 132, "PERSON"], [136, 151, "ORGANIZATION"], [230, 266, "ORGANIZATION"], [268, 278, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Left is the head of Citron Research, a US-based publisher of research reports on listed companies (Note 2).", {"entities": [[0, 4, "PERSON"], [20, 35, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC alleges that on 21 June 2012, Left published a report on Citron Research’s website (www.citronresearch.com) that contained false and misleading information about Evergrande. The report stated, among other things, that Evergrande was insolvent and had consistently presented fraudulent information to the investing public.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [38, 42, "PERSON"], [65, 80, "ORGANIZATION"], [170, 180, "ORGANIZATION"], [226, 236, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The share price of Evergrande fell sharply on the same day following the publication of the report (Note 3).", {"entities": [[19, 29, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC also alleges that shortly before publishing the report, Left short sold 4.1 million shares of Evergrande which he subsequently bought back, making a notional profit of over $2.8 million. Left made a total realised profit of approximately $1.7 million.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [64, 68, "PERSON"], [102, 112, "ORGANIZATION"], [195, 199, "PERSON"]]}], ["A copy of the SFC’s Notice commencing the MMT proceedings will be available on the MMT’s website (www.mmt.gov.hk).", {"entities": [[14, 17, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC announced today the result of its inquiry into Mr Cheung King Wai (Cheung) covering the period from 1 November 1997 to 31 March 1998 (the relevant period).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [58, 73, "PERSON"], [75, 81, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC found that during the relevant period there were deficiencies in the internal control systems and procedures of C.A. Pacific Forex Limited (CAPFL) resulting in breaches of the Leveraged Foreign Exchange Trading Ordinance (LFETO), the Leveraged Foreign Exchange Trading (Financial Resources) Rules, the Leveraged Foreign Exchange Trading (Books, Contract Notes and Conduct of Business) Rules and the Management, Supervision and Internal Control Guidelines. The result of the SFC's inquiry into CAPFL was announced on 21 March 2000 and CAPFL's licence was revoked on 8 January 2000.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [120, 146, "ORGANIZATION"], [148, 153, "ORGANIZATION"], [482, 485, "ORGANIZATION"], [501, 506, "ORGANIZATION"], [542, 547, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC also found that Cheung, as the responsible director of CAPFL responsible for the operation of the business during the relevant period, failed to adequately discharge his functions to properly manage and supervise CAPFL's business. In view of the findings, the SFC has revoked Cheung licence under section 12[4) of the LFETO.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [24, 30, "PERSON"], [63, 68, "ORGANIZATION"], [221, 226, "ORGANIZATION"], [268, 271, "ORGANIZATION"], [284, 290, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Eastern Magistrates’ Court has convicted Mr Sammy Shiu Kin Keung after he pleaded guilty to illegal short selling in the shares of Share Economy Group Limited (formerly known as Vitop Bioenergy Holdings Limited) , Global Tech (Holdings) Limited  and China Ocean Industry Group Limited (formerly known as China Ocean Shipbuilding Industry Group Limited) on 14 occasions.", {"entities": [[4, 30, "ORGANIZATION"], [48, 68, "PERSON"], [141, 162, "ORGANIZATION"], [182, 214, "ORGANIZATION"], [218, 248, "ORGANIZATION"], [254, 288, "ORGANIZATION"], [308, 355, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Shiu was fined a total of $35,000 and was ordered to pay the Securities and Futures Commission’s (SFC) investigation costs.", {"entities": [[0, 4, "PERSON"], [61, 94, "ORGANIZATION"], [98, 101, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In April and May 2014, Shiu placed orders to sell shares of the three companies through his personal trading account at China Rise Securities Asset Management Company Limited when he did not have sufficient quantities of the shares to sell. Shiu later bought back shares to cover some of his short sales and in doing so, made a profit of approximately $22,500.", {"entities": [[23, 27, "PERSON"], [120, 174, "ORGANIZATION"], [241, 245, "PERSON"]]}], ["By short selling the shares, Shiu was in contravention of section 170 of the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO) (Note 2).", {"entities": [[29, 33, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC successfully prosecuted two people in July. Both cases concerned leveraged foreign exchange trading.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Further, in July, the SFC disciplined six licensees for various breaches, including banning an ex-licensee from re-entering the industry for six months for facilitating cold calling.", {"entities": [[22, 25, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Apart from the prosecutions and disciplinary actions, the SFC issued a restriction notice against a broker, Tiffit Securities (Hong Kong) Limited.", {"entities": [[58, 61, "ORGANIZATION"], [108, 145, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Copies of the August issue of the SFC Enforcement Reporter are available at the SFC office. All issues are also available on the SFC website under “Speeches, Publications & Consultations” – “Publications”.", {"entities": [[34, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [80, 83, "ORGANIZATION"], [129, 132, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The public are able to subscribe to the newsletter by registering for the Update Alert service on the SFC website. They will then be able to receive the newsletter via email.", {"entities": [[102, 105, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The public are also invited to provide feedback to improve the SFC Enforcement Reporter. Comments can be emailed to enfreporter@sfc.hk.", {"entities": [[63, 66, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had reprimanded {X}, formerly a registered dealer under the Securities Ordinance (SO). ", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The action stemmed from an inquiry conducted under section 56 of the SO which revealed that {X}, whilst acting as a director and person concerned in the management of Carrier Stock Investment Company Limited (\"Carrier\"], had executed certain significant transactions in September/October 1997 in accordance with verbal instructions given by a third party without having first verified whether the third party had been duly authorised by the actual account holder to act on its behalf. The SFC found that {X} had failed to discharge her function of properly managing and supervising Carrier's business and failed to exercise due care and diligence in protecting the client's interests and the integrity of Carrier's operations, thus putting the clients' assets at risk.", {"entities": [[167, 207, "ORGANIZATION"], [210, 217, "ORGANIZATION"], [489, 492, "ORGANIZATION"], [582, 589, "ORGANIZATION"], [705, 712, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Accordingly, the SFC concluded that {X} had been guilty of misconduct and her fitness and properness as a director or person concerned in the management of a registered corporation had been impugned. {X} has further agreed not to lodge an application for registration as a supervisory director within one year.", {"entities": [[17, 20, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had publicly reprimanded {X}, who is registered as a securities dealer of Mayfair Securities Limited under the Securities Ordinance (SO).", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [142, 168, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["A spokesman of the SFC said that the above matters impugned {X}'s fitness and properness as a registered person.", {"entities": [[19, 22, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC announced today that it had: i. reprimanded Mr Lui Hing Yip, Andy (Lui), formerly a registered dealer under the Securities Ordinance (SO) and; ii. suspended Lui's registration as a dealer's representative under the Commodities Trading Ordinance (CTO) for a period of six weeks. ", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [55, 73, "PERSON"], [75, 78, "PERSON"], [165, 168, "PERSON"]]}], ["The actions stemmed from inquiries conducted under section 56 of the SO and section 36 of the CTO which revealed that Lui, whilst acting as a director and person concerned in the management of China Everbright Securities (HK) Limited, had released a client's assets to another person without obtaining the client's written instruction. The SFC found that Lui had failed to exercise due care and diligence in protecting the client's interests, thus putting the client's assets at risk and also exposing his former employer to potential liabilities.", {"entities": [[118, 121, "PERSON"], [193, 233, "ORGANIZATION"], [340, 343, "ORGANIZATION"], [355, 358, "PERSON"]]}], ["Accordingly, the SFC concluded that Lui had been guilty of misconduct. In deciding the penalties, the SFC took into consideration of the following:", {"entities": [[17, 20, "ORGANIZATION"], [102, 105, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["· Lui appeared not to have personally derived any financial benefit from the above incident; and", {"entities": [[2, 5, "PERSON"]]}], [" · Lui was co-operative during the course of the inquiries.", {"entities": [[3, 6, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded and fined HPI Forex Limited (HPI) $2 million for mis-handling client money (Note 1).", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [70, 87, "ORGANIZATION"], [89, 92, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC’s disciplinary action came after an admission by HPI that it had transferred client money up to $8 million to the accounts of its overseas brokers between March 2013 and April 2014.  ", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [57, 60, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC found that HPI:", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [19, 22, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In doing so, HPI breached the Code of Conduct and the CMR by failing to maintain client money in a segregated client account in Hong Kong with an authorized financial institution (Notes 2, 3 & 4).", {"entities": [[13, 16, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["HPI’s use of the client money to conduct proprietary transactions also constitutes a breach of its fundamental duty as a licensed intermediary to ensure that client assets are promptly and properly accounted for and adequately safeguarded (Note 5).", {"entities": [[0, 3, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In deciding the disciplinary sanction against HPI, the SFC took into account that:", {"entities": [[46, 49, "ORGANIZATION"], [55, 58, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- HPI remitted the client money back to the segregated client account upon discovery of this matter and engaged an auditor to review its compliance with the CMR;", {"entities": [[3, 6, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- HPI cooperated with the SFC in accepting the disciplinary action;", {"entities": [[3, 6, "ORGANIZATION"], [27, 30, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- there is no evidence that HPI’s clients have suffered losses; and", {"entities": [[29, 32, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- HPI has an otherwise clean disciplinary record.", {"entities": [[3, 6, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Safe custody of client money and client securities is a fundamental obligation of all intermediaries.  Intermediaries are reminded to carefully review their internal control procedures for compliance with the CMR and the Securities and Futures (Client Securities) Rules.  The SFC will continue to take action against intermediaries which mis-handle client assets.", {"entities": [[276, 279, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission announced that it had successfully prosecuted Ms Yu Hung Wai, Angel (Yu) and Mr Lo Wai Tai (Lo) for unregistered securities dealing activities in contravention of Section 48 of the Securities Ordinance.", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [84, 105, "PERSON"], [107, 109, "PERSON"], [118, 128, "PERSON"], [130, 132, "PERSON"]]}], ["Yu and Lo pleaded guilty before Mr A Wyeth at South Kowloon Magistracy on 20 August 1998. They were each fined $3,000 for carrying on an unregistered business of securities dealing. In addition to the fines imposed, the defendants were each ordered to pay costs of $5,000 to the SFC.", {"entities": [[0, 2, "PERSON"], [7, 9, "PERSON"], [35, 42, "PERSON"], [46, 70, "ORGANIZATION"], [279, 282, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC investigation revealed that during the period June 1997 to January 1998, Yu and Lo while in the employment of the Hong Kong office of Dizon Investments International Incorporation (Dizon), an investment company incorporated in the United States of America, sold United States securities to clients in Hong Kong. Dizon, its Hong Kong office, Yu and Lo are not registered with the SFC in any capacity.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [81, 83, "PERSON"], [88, 90, "PERSON"], [142, 187, "ORGANIZATION"], [189, 194, "ORGANIZATION"], [320, 325, "ORGANIZATION"], [349, 351, "PERSON"], [356, 358, "PERSON"]]}], ["For further information, please contact Bill Weeks at 2840-9287 or Chan Chi-keung at 2842-7624.", {"entities": [[40, 50, "PERSON"], [67, 81, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC has reprimanded and fined Bright Smart Securities International (HK) Limited and Mr Yip Mow Lum Peter $50,000 each for publishing false and misleading advertisements, despite repeated warnings from the Hong Kong Securities Clearing Company Limited (HKSCC) and the SFC.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [34, 84, "ORGANIZATION"], [92, 109, "PERSON"], [210, 255, "ORGANIZATION"], [257, 262, "ORGANIZATION"], [272, 275, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Yip is the managing director of Bright Smart (Note 1). The SFC found that Bright Smart had from 17 March to 8 April 2003 published 13 statements in two newspapers containing false and misleading statements. These advertisements stated incorrectly that clients of Bright Smart could make direct payment to the CCASS under HKSCC for settlement. Yip drafted all these advertisements.", {"entities": [[0, 3, "PERSON"], [32, 44, "ORGANIZATION"], [59, 62, "ORGANIZATION"], [74, 86, "ORGANIZATION"], [263, 275, "ORGANIZATION"], [321, 326, "ORGANIZATION"], [343, 346, "PERSON"]]}], ["Staff of both the SFC and HKSCC informed Bright Smart and Yip that the information was incorrect immediately after the first advertisement was noticed. CCASS does not receive direct payment from individual investors for settlement of their trades. CCASS only acts as a facilitator for handling trades settlement between brokers and investors. Monies are not directly paid to CCASS, and both the brokers and investor have to monitor the settlement by themselves.", {"entities": [[18, 21, "ORGANIZATION"], [26, 31, "ORGANIZATION"], [41, 53, "ORGANIZATION"], [58, 61, "PERSON"]]}], ["Despite these warnings, Yip continued to cause Bright Smart to publish the misleading statements.", {"entities": [[24, 27, "PERSON"], [47, 59, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC concludes that the fitness and properness of Bright Smart and Yip has been called into question and decides to reprimand and fine them.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [53, 65, "ORGANIZATION"], [70, 73, "PERSON"]]}], ["Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement said: \"Brokerages should not disseminate any false and misleading information in their advertisements. Any person who is concerned in the management of a brokerage, though not licensed, cannot escape liability if circumstances reveal he is not a fit and proper person to be in that position. It is also an aggravating factor when a brokerage willfully ignores prior warnings from the regulators. After considering the Disciplinary Fining Guidelines, a public reprimand and a fine are the most appropriate penalty in the circumstances.\"", {"entities": [[3, 15, "PERSON"], [17, 20, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court of Appeal, in the first such case in Hong Kong, last month dismissed a former investment adviser's appeal against an Securities and Futures Appeals Tribunal (SFAT) decision on his mis-selling, the October issue of the SFC Enforcement Reporter has recorded.", {"entities": [[4, 19, "ORGANIZATION"], [228, 231, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC welcomed the Court’s decision, which upheld the standards that the SFC has been applying to investment advisers, and affirmed the role of SFAT as the checks and balances over the SFC’s disciplinary decisions. The case should offer valuable confirmation of regulatory standards to regulators around the world.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [75, 78, "ORGANIZATION"], [187, 190, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Further in September, the SFC successfully prosecuted one company and five people in September for short selling and unlicensed activities; disciplined six licensees for conducting discretionary trades without written authorisation, aiding and abetting unlicensed activities, breaching their employer’s staff dealing policy and internal control failings. The SFC’s decision to suspend a licensee for six weeks for trading in a client’s account without written authorisation was also upheld by the SFAT.", {"entities": [[26, 29, "ORGANIZATION"], [359, 362, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Apart from the prosecutions and disciplinary actions, the SFC applied to the High Court to continue an interim Mareva Injunction to freeze the assets of two responsible officers of Tiffit Securities (Hong Kong) Limited.", {"entities": [[58, 61, "ORGANIZATION"], [181, 218, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The public are also invited to provide feedback to improve the SFC Enforcement Reporter. Comments can be emailed to enfreporter@sfc.hk.", {"entities": [[63, 87, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has obtained orders in the High Court to disqualify two former executive directors of Wah Sang Gas Holdings Ltd (Wah Sang Gas, now renamed Binhai Investment Co Ltd).", {"entities": [[0, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [130, 155, "ORGANIZATION"], [157, 169, "ORGANIZATION"], [183, 207, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The orders disqualify Mr Shum Ka Sang, former chairman, chief executive officer and executive director of Wah Sang Gas, and Mr Shen Yi, its former chief operating officer and executive director, from being directors or being involved in the management of any listed company, without leave of the court, for a period of six years (Note 1).", {"entities": [[25, 37, "PERSON"], [106, 118, "ORGANIZATION"], [127, 134, "PERSON"]]}], ["The disqualification order against Shum and Shen, made by the Honourable Madam Justice Kwan on 22 May 2009, will take effect on 12 June 2009.", {"entities": [[35, 39, "PERSON"], [44, 48, "PERSON"], [87, 91, "PERSON"]]}], ["The decisions follow an investigation by the SFC into the affairs of Wah Sang Gas, a listed company in the business of construction of gas pipelines, gas connection services, production and sale of gas, through subsidiaries in the Mainland.", {"entities": [[69, 81, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC suspended trading in shares of Wah Sang Gas on 6 April 2004 because of concerns that the company’s financial statements contained false or misleading information (Note 2).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 51, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Following investigations by the SFC and by Wah Sang Gas (under new management), the company published in July 2007 a final results announcement for the year ended 31 March 2004 in which the company acknowledged that:", {"entities": [[32, 35, "ORGANIZATION"], [43, 55, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC contended that Shum and Shen occupied positions of significant responsibility during the period in which the falsification occurred.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [23, 27, "PERSON"], [32, 36, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC alleged that Shum and Shen failed to exercise reasonable skill, care and diligence, to act in the best interests of the company and its members, to ensure the company accurately accounted for its business activities and disclosed them correctly in their published financial statements.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [21, 25, "PERSON"], [30, 34, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC did not allege that Shum and Shen were responsible for making or causing false entries to be made in the company’s accounting records nor was there evidence to do so.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [28, 32, "PERSON"], [37, 41, "PERSON"]]}], ["Instead, the SFC argued they were negligent or reckless and failed to discharge their duties properly, and alleged that:", {"entities": [[13, 16, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Shum failed in his duty as chairman and CEO, by appointing officers whom he knew were not capable of handling the company’s financial transactions, entrusting daily operations to Shen when he knew Shen did not know much about finance; failed to ensure the board was kept informed and ignored specific warnings about deficiencies in the accounting records from the company’s auditors and the company’s audit committee; and", {"entities": [[0, 4, "PERSON"], [179, 183, "PERSON"], [197, 201, "PERSON"]]}], ["Shen, as COO, had responsibility for the company’s financial and accounting systems and failed in his supervisory duty to prevent such systemic falsifications and deficiencies in the company’s affairs.", {"entities": [[0, 4, "PERSON"]]}], ["In ordering the six-year disqualifications, the court took into account their co-operation with the SFC.", {"entities": [[100, 103, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["“The investing public needs to be protected from company directors who negligently or recklessly abuse the trust placed in them. In this case, massive fraud flourished under incompetent, unreliable management who will have no part to play in the company’s ongoing affairs nor in the affairs of any other listed company for six years. The SFC will continue its programme to enforce proper standards of conduct by listed company directors,” said Mr Mark Steward, the SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement. (Note 4)", {"entities": [[338, 341, "ORGANIZATION"], [447, 459, "PERSON"], [465, 468, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has prohibited Mr Law Wing Sang, Vincent from re-entering the industry for three months from 20 December 2006 to 19 March 2007 for making unsolicited calls (Note 1).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [26, 48, "PERSON"]]}], ["The disciplinary action follows an SFC investigation which found that in August 2004, Law cold called a person with a view to inducing the person to open an account to trade leveraged foreign exchange contracts. Law was convicted of making unsolicited calls earlier this year (Note 2).", {"entities": [[35, 38, "ORGANIZATION"], [212, 215, "PERSON"], [86, 89, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Court of First Instance has dismissed an appeal by Mr Lam Fai Man, a substantial shareholder of Victory Group Limited (Victory), against his convictions for failing to disclose to Victory changes in his interests in the shares of Victory, as required by the Securities and Futures Ordinance (Notes 1 & 2).", {"entities": [[58, 69, "PERSON"], [0, 27, "ORGANIZATION"], [100, 121, "ORGANIZATION"], [123, 130, "ORGANIZATION"], [184, 191, "ORGANIZATION"], [234, 241, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Lam was convicted on 30 June 2015 after trial at the Eastern Magistracy and fined $12,000. ", {"entities": [[0, 3, "PERSON"], [53, 71, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Honourable Mr Justice Zervos dismissed Lam’s argument that the trial magistrate erred in law in finding that Lam, who had delegated his duty of disclosure to his account executive, had failed to establish a defence of reasonable excuse for his failure to make disclosures to Victory.", {"entities": [[26, 32, "PERSON"], [43, 46, "PERSON"], [113, 116, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Court held that the legal obligation was on Lam to ensure that his duty of disclosure and notification was properly performed and that obligation remained on Lam, even if he delegated the task.  ", {"entities": [[48, 51, "PERSON"], [162, 165, "PERSON"]]}], ["In his judgment, Mr Justice Zervos said that, if a person who owes the duty delegates it to another, he must make sure that it is strictly complied with for he bears the ultimate responsibility and liability for any failure to perform the duty (Note 3).", {"entities": [[28, 34, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had successfully prosecuted LM Investment Management Hong Kong Ltd. (LMHK) together with {X}, being a director of LMHK, under the Protection of Investors Ordinance for the issuance of various advertisements relating to an investment arrangement without due authorization.", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [96, 135, "ORGANIZATION"], [137, 141, "ORGANIZATION"], [157, 160, "PERSON"], [182, 186, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The investment arrangement was a scheme which allowed an investor to participate as a direct co-owner or part-owner of a Hong Kong commercial property and to receive a regular monthly income. The advertisements related to the marketing of this investment arrangement. Ms Polly Lo, a Magistrate at Western Magistracy, fined LMHK HK$50,000 and {X} HK$5,000 and ordered them to pay costs totalling HK$14,373 to the SFC. ", {"entities": [[323, 327, "ORGANIZATION"], [271, 279, "PERSON"], [412, 415, "ORGANIZATION"], [297, 315, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC spokesman said he wished to reiterate the words that Alan Linning, Executive Director of Enforcement, issued yesterday after a similarly successful prosecution, namely that \"there appears to be a growing trend for property schemes to be marketed in Hong Kong which risk violating the Protection of Investors Ordinance. Promoters and property developers in particular are reminded that any document which contains an invitation or offer to the public to take part in an investment arrangement must be approved in advance by the SFC.\"", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [61, 73, "PERSON"], [535, 538, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Market Misconduct Tribunal (MMT) has found that the former chairman and chief executive officer of Greencool Technology Holdings Limited (Greencool), Mr Gu Chujun, and four former senior executives (including its former financial controller) disclosed false or misleading information inducing transactions and so engaged in market misconduct under the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO) following proceedings brought by the Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) (Notes 1, 2 and 3).", {"entities": [[4, 30, "ORGANIZATION"], [32, 35, "ORGANIZATION"], [103, 140, "ORGANIZATION"], [142, 151, "ORGANIZATION"], [157, 166, "PERSON"], [432, 465, "ORGANIZATION"], [467, 470, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The four ex-Greencool senior executives are former directors, Mr Zhang Xihan, Mr Hu Xiaohui, and Mr Xu Wanping, and former financial controller, Mr Henry Mok Wing Kai.  Mok was also a qualified accountant appointed under the GEM Listing Rules and the company secretary of Greencool.", {"entities": [[12, 21, "ORGANIZATION"], [65, 76, "PERSON"], [81, 91, "PERSON"], [100, 110, "PERSON"], [148, 166, "PERSON"], [169, 172, "PERSON"], [272, 281, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC alleged that Gu and former senior executives of Greencool were involved in grossly overstating the company’s net asset value in its annual reports and results announcements released between 2001 and 2005 as a result of the overstatement of bank deposits and the non-disclosure of bank loans.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [21, 23, "PERSON"], [56, 65, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The MMT found that Gu, with the assistance of Zhang and Hu, had perpetrated a massive, systemic fraud and the fraud was known to Xu and several employees at Mainland subsidiaries who were ordered to participate in it. ", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [19, 21, "PERSON"], [46, 51, "PERSON"], [56, 58, "PERSON"], [129, 131, "PERSON"]]}], ["Gu, Zhang and Hu were involved in gross overstatements of Greencool’s sales, profit, trade receivables and bank deposits, overstating the company’s net asset value for the financial years ended 31 December 2000 to 2004 by approximately RMB487 million, RMB653 million, RMB982 million, RMB1,062 million and RMB904 million respectively which represents 43% to 80% of Greencool’s total net assets in these years.", {"entities": [[0, 2, "PERSON"], [4, 9, "PERSON"], [14, 16, "PERSON"], [58, 67, "ORGANIZATION"], [364, 373, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Mok, a qualified accountant/company secretary, was found culpable of market misconduct by providing materially false or misleading information to the public in circumstances in which he was negligent as to whether the information was false or misleading.  He was negligent in performing his professional duties as a qualified accountant by failing to supervise the implementation of a sound internal control and financial reporting system, thereby enabling Gu, Zhang and Hu to provide false and misleading annual results of Greencool from 2001 to 2005 to defraud the investing public. ", {"entities": [[0, 3, "PERSON"], [457, 459, "PERSON"], [461, 466, "PERSON"], [471, 473, "PERSON"], [524, 533, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The MMT notes that although the responsibilities of a qualified accountant pursuant to Rule 5.11 of the GEM Listing Rules (Rule) is broad in nature and it only sets out the minimum responsibilities, the description of the Rule “does not limit the role of a qualified accountant to that of an adviser; a qualified accountant is to advise and assist the board of directors, that is, to take such steps as may be necessary to implement internal controls and other procedures that are necessary to provide the board with a reasonable basis for making sound commercial judgments” and such duties are “not limited to that of a holding company but extend to taking such steps as may be necessary to implement internal controls and other procedures in all the companies making up ‘the Group’”.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC also commenced proceedings under section 213 of the SFO against Gu in the Court of First Instance in parallel with the MMT proceedings.  The SFC successfully obtained an injunction on 18 July 2014 to freeze over a total of 107,290,000 shares in Hisense Kelon Electrical Holdings Limited up to a value of $1.2 billion.  The SFC believes these shares are held by several people and overseas companies for the benefit of Gu.     ", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [72, 74, "PERSON"], [82, 105, "ORGANIZATION"], [127, 130, "ORGANIZATION"], [149, 152, "ORGANIZATION"], [253, 294, "ORGANIZATION"], [331, 334, "ORGANIZATION"], [426, 428, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC would like to thank the China Securities Regulatory Commission, the China Banking Regulatory Commission and other relevant departments for their extensive assistance under the domestic law.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [32, 70, "ORGANIZATION"], [76, 111, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (\"the Commission\"] announced today that the registration of Miss Lai Mei Chun, Swana as a dealer's representative of Many Fair Securities Company was suspended for 3 years and {X} trading as Many Fair Securities Company had been reprimanded for failing to exercise proper management, supervision and control over his business.", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [40, 54, "ORGANIZATION"], [103, 122, "PERSON"], [155, 183, "ORGANIZATION"], [229, 257, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["This action stemmed from an investigation conducted by the Commission in which it was established that during the period June 1993 to June 1994, Miss Lai had actively facilitated 'rat trading' (a generic term used to cover a wide range of trading malpractices by staff of brokers trading to the disadvantage of their principals' clients) by floor traders of other brokers using nominee accounts maintained at Many Fair Securities Company. Miss Lai's misconduct in this regard was particularly serious because the scale of the rat-traders' activity was considerable and during the course of the investigation she sought to mislead the Commission.", {"entities": [[59, 69, "ORGANIZATION"], [150, 153, "PERSON"], [444, 447, "PERSON"], [409, 437, "ORGANIZATION"], [634, 644, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The rat trading activity by the floor traders occurred because {X}", {"entities": [[63, 66, "PERSON"]]}], ["- failed to supervise Miss Lai;", {"entities": [[27, 30, "PERSON"]]}], ["In deciding on this action the Commission took into account that Lai's activity was prejudicial to the interests of members of the investing public and warranted a penalty that would deter others from offering similar accommodations. In regard to {X}, the Commission took into account that he will voluntarily surrender his dealer's registration with effect from 1 June 1997 and his undertaking that he will not submit any application for re-registration for 6 months and then only if he has incorporated his business, and an officer with responsibility for corporate compliance acceptable to the Commission has been appointed.", {"entities": [[31, 41, "ORGANIZATION"], [65, 68, "PERSON"], [256, 266, "ORGANIZATION"], [247, 250, "PERSON"], [597, 607, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Commenting on this action Mr. Paul Bailey, Senior Director of the Enforcement Division of the Commission said \"The Commission will take firm measures to ensure that registered intermediaries neither engage in improper trading practices nor facilitate such conduct by others. In this regard the maintenance of poor audit trails and inadequate internal controls will not be countenanced and intermediaries will be held accountable for such failings.\"", {"entities": [[30, 41, "PERSON"], [115, 125, "ORGANIZATION"], [94, 104, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has revoked the registration of Yeung Tsz Chung as a securities dealer’s representative for misappropriation of stocks to the value of some $21 million over a period of more than 10 years when he was employed at CLSA Limited.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [40, 55, "PERSON"], [220, 232, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The revocation stems from an inquiry in which the SFC found that Yeung had:", {"entities": [[50, 53, "ORGANIZATION"], [65, 70, "PERSON"]]}], ["Stolen stocks from CLSA which were held on behalf of its clients;", {"entities": [[19, 23, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], [" perpetrated the misappropriation of these stocks through an abuse of his position in CLSA and the trust reposed in him by CLSA; and", {"entities": [[86, 90, "ORGANIZATION"], [123, 127, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], [" caused pecuniary loss to CLSA.", {"entities": [[26, 30, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC also found that Yeung had carried out the above acts intentionally with a view to deceiving CLSA. To perpetrate  his misappropriation, Yeung made false entries in the books of CLSA, defied CLSA’s internal rules and used the passwords of other staff without authority to gain access to computers. Yeung’s conduct was highly improper, serious and unlawful.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [24, 29, "PERSON"], [100, 104, "ORGANIZATION"], [143, 148, "PERSON"], [184, 188, "ORGANIZATION"], [197, 201, "ORGANIZATION"], [304, 309, "PERSON"]]}], ["Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Theft is a very serious matter which will never be condoned under any circumstances. A person guilty of such conduct is not fit and proper to remain registered. The need to protect investors and the market from these types of conduct warrants nothing less than a revocation. Registered persons are reminded to observe, at all times, the highest standards of integrity and ensure that their actions comply with the applicable laws, rules and code of conduct as well as the internal control policies of their employers.”", {"entities": [[0, 12, "PERSON"], [14, 17, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["A negotiating agent was found guilty in the Eastern Magistracy today of insider dealing while acting as representative of the controlling shareholder in a proposed acquisition.", {"entities": [[44, 62, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Mr Pablo Chan Pak Hoe was convicted of one charge of insider dealing after a lengthy trial lasting 15 days. The case was adjourned to 19 August 2010 for sentencing.", {"entities": [[3, 21, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) prosecuted Chan following an investigation which found that:", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [55, 59, "PERSON"]]}], ["as a representative of the controlling shareholder of Universe International Holdings Ltd (Universe), Chan took part in the negotiation of a proposed acquisition by Goldwyn Management Ltd (Goldwyn) of Universe shares from the controlling shareholder between March and June 2008;", {"entities": [[54, 89, "ORGANIZATION"], [91, 99, "ORGANIZATION"], [102, 106, "PERSON"], [165, 187, "ORGANIZATION"], [189, 196, "ORGANIZATION"], [201, 209, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["between 2 May 2008 and 19 June 2008, Chan purchased a total of 3,880,000 Universe shares whilst in possession of confidential, price-sensitive information about Goldwyn’s offer;", {"entities": [[37, 41, "PERSON"], [73, 81, "ORGANIZATION"], [161, 168, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["on 19 June 2008, Universe announced that its controlling shareholder was negotiating with an independent third party regarding the disposal of its entire holding of Universe shares and trading in Universe shares was suspended. Trading resumed the following day and the share price of Universe soared by about 40%; and", {"entities": [[17, 25, "ORGANIZATION"], [165, 173, "ORGANIZATION"], [284, 292, "ORGANIZATION"], [196, 204, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Chan promptly disposed of all his Universe shares, making a profit of approximately $120,000 from the trades.", {"entities": [[0, 4, "PERSON"], [34, 42, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["“It is clear from the evidence that the Defendant received relevant information by virtue of the fact that he was part of the negotiation team. He knew that he had to keep such information confidential,” said Magistrate Mr Anthony Yuen.", {"entities": [[223, 235, "PERSON"]]}], ["“Insider dealing is a dishonest act. Chan, as the negotiating agent for the offeree in a proposed takeover, was at the heart of the transaction with privileged access to information. Today’s verdict underscores our dedication and commitment to protecting ordinary investors from this type of misconduct,” said Mr Mark Steward, the SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement.", {"entities": [[37, 41, "PERSON"], [331, 334, "ORGANIZATION"], [313, 325, "PERSON"]]}], ["“The SFC will continue the fight against market misconduct to ensure ordinary investors can be confident in dealing in Hong Kong’s markets,” Mr Steward added.", {"entities": [[5, 8, "ORGANIZATION"], [144, 151, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Appeals Panel (SFAP) has suspended for 6 months Mr William Chim Chun Kwan's (Mr Chim) registrations as a dealer's representative under the Securities Ordinance and the Commodities Trading Ordinance after an appeal by Mr Chim from an SFC decision. ", {"entities": [[4, 40, "ORGANIZATION"], [42, 46, "ORGANIZATION"], [78, 100, "PERSON"], [107, 111, "PERSON"], [260, 263, "ORGANIZATION"], [247, 251, "PERSON"]]}], ["On 8 January 1999, the SFC decided to suspend for 1 year Mr Chim's registrations owing to its findings about his role in his client's trading on 30 and 31 December 1996 in the shares of Renaissance Hotel Group, NV, (RHG) a company listed on the New York Stock Exchange. Mr Chim appealed against this decision.", {"entities": [[23, 26, "ORGANIZATION"], [60, 64, "PERSON"], [216, 219, "ORGANIZATION"], [273, 277, "PERSON"], [186, 213, "ORGANIZATION"], [245, 268, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["On appeal, the SFAP upheld the SFC's charge that, at a time when Mr Chim knew or should have known that his client's conduct was possibly illegal or improper, he counselled his client to open a nominee account to frustrate a US investigation into who was purchasing RHG shares. The SFAP stated that it regarded with \"considerable disquiet Mr Chim's conduct here as tantamount to an active attempt to assist in the frustration of a serious investigation.\"", {"entities": [[15, 19, "ORGANIZATION"], [31, 34, "ORGANIZATION"], [68, 72, "PERSON"], [266, 269, "ORGANIZATION"], [342, 346, "ORGANIZATION"], [282, 286, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFAP dismissed the SFC's findings in relation to two other charges.", {"entities": [[4, 8, "ORGANIZATION"], [23, 26, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["As a result, the SFAP decided to suspend Mr Chim's registrations for 6 months.", {"entities": [[17, 21, "ORGANIZATION"], [44, 48, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announces that it has decided to commence proceedings, for suspected market manipulation in the shares of China Ding Yi Feng Holdings Limited (China Ding Yi Feng), against a number of individuals including one or more officers of China Ding Yi Feng.", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [150, 185, "ORGANIZATION"], [187, 205, "ORGANIZATION"], [274, 292, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has also decided to lift the suspension of the trading in the company’s shares that was directed by the SFC on 8 March 2019.  Trading of the shares of China Ding Yi Feng will resume at 9 am on 23 January 2020 (Note 1). ", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [112, 115, "ORGANIZATION"], [159, 177, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC issued restriction notices to nine brokers on 20 March 2019 and on 25 June 2019 to freeze certain client securities accounts which are believed to be related to the suspected market manipulation in the shares of China Ding Yi Feng.  The restriction notices will remain in place following the resumption of trading.  These restriction notices cover 32.37% of the issued share capital of China Ding Yi Feng (Note 2).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [220, 238, "ORGANIZATION"], [394, 412, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC’s Policy Statement on Disclosure of Certain Information to the Public enables it to make an announcement in relation to an inquiry or investigation where, amongst other circumstances, it is desirable to protect members of the public and in order to maintain public confidence in the securities and futures market in Hong Kong (Note 3).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["This announcement of the SFC’s decision to commence proceedings for suspected market manipulation has been made in accordance with this policy.  The SFC considers that, following its confirmation that proceedings will be commenced, there is now sufficient information in the market to allow the suspension to be lifted (Note 4).", {"entities": [[25, 28, "ORGANIZATION"], [149, 152, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Shareholders and prospective investors should be aware that the price and trading turnover of China Ding Yi Feng shares may fluctuate substantially and should exercise extreme caution when dealing in the shares.  They are advised to take note of the latest publications of China Ding Yi Feng on the HKEX news website (http://www.hkexnews.hk) and its company website.", {"entities": [[94, 112, "ORGANIZATION"], [273, 291, "ORGANIZATION"], [299, 303, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had successfully prosecuted Ng Cheong Lam (Ng), a non-executive director of Gzitic Hualing Holdings Limited (Gzitic) and Wong Chung Pak Thomas (Wong), a director of Kwoon Chung Bus Holdings Limited (KCB) under the Securities (Disclosure of Interests) Ordinance (SDIO).", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [96, 109, "PERSON"], [111, 113, "PERSON"], [144, 175, "ORGANIZATION"], [177, 183, "ORGANIZATION"], [189, 210, "PERSON"], [212, 216, "PERSON"], [233, 265, "ORGANIZATION"], [267, 270, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Ng pleaded guilty to a total of 16 summonses. The summonses relate to Ng's failure to report to Gzitic and Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEx) purchases of 60,000 Gzitic shares and sales of 100,000 Gzitic shares and delayed reporting of up to 20 days in respect of additional sales of 4,568,000 Gzitic shares during the period 8 June 2001 to 17 August 2001.", {"entities": [[0, 2, "ORGANIZATION"], [70, 72, "PERSON"], [96, 102, "ORGANIZATION"], [107, 147, "ORGANIZATION"], [149, 153, "ORGANIZATION"], [175, 181, "ORGANIZATION"], [210, 216, "ORGANIZATION"], [307, 313, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Wong pleaded guilty to a total of 4 summonses. The summonses relate to Wong's failure to make a timely disclosure of his deemed interest in KCB shares via a corporate substantial shareholder of KCB, Wong Family Holdings Limited, which bought 22,000 and 800,000 KCB shares on 8 March 2000 and 12 May 2000 respectively. Wong had a duty to disclose in his capacity as a director and substantial shareholder of KCB but failed to make such disclosure to KCB and HKEx until around 27 and 28 August 2001 respectively, a delay of over 12 months.", {"entities": [[0, 4, "PERSON"], [71, 75, "PERSON"], [140, 143, "ORGANIZATION"], [194, 197, "ORGANIZATION"], [199, 227, "ORGANIZATION"], [261, 264, "ORGANIZATION"], [318, 322, "PERSON"], [407, 410, "ORGANIZATION"], [449, 452, "ORGANIZATION"], [457, 461, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Ms Polly Lo, a Magistrate at Western Magistracy, fined Ng and Wong $32,000 and $20,000, and ordered them to pay costs of $13,240 and $15,135 to the SFC, respectively.", {"entities": [[3, 11, "PERSON"], [29, 47, "ORGANIZATION"], [55, 57, "PERSON"], [62, 66, "PERSON"], [148, 151, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["An spokesman for the SFC said that directors and substantial shareholders of listed companies are reminded of their obligations to disclose their dealings in such listed securities within five business days to both the HKEx and the listed company. This is essential in order to preserve a fair and well-informed market in which investors have full confidence.", {"entities": [[21, 24, "ORGANIZATION"], [219, 223, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has suspended the licence of Mr Goh Chee Liong, former responsible officer of Hang Tung Securities Ltd, as a representative and the approval for him to act as a responsible officer for nine months (Note 1).", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [76, 90, "PERSON"], [122, 146, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The disciplinary action follows an SFC investigation which revealed that Goh:", {"entities": [[35, 38, "ORGANIZATION"], [73, 76, "PERSON"]]}], ["failed to put in place a proper accounting and settlement system in Hang Tung;", {"entities": [[68, 77, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["failed to properly supervise the settlement and accounting functions of Hang Tung; and", {"entities": [[72, 81, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["permitted the use of either third party cheques or other clients’ transactions/cash balance to settle the outstanding balance in the account of an account representative’s sister at Hang Tung.", {"entities": [[182, 191, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Between July 2000 and April 2007, an account representative accredited to Hang Tung used her sister’s account at Hang Tung to carry out personal trades in securities. She started incurring substantial trading losses in her sister’s account in February 2006 and losses in that account continued to rise thereafter.", {"entities": [[113, 122, "ORGANIZATION"], [74, 83, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Goh, as part of the senior management of Hang Tung, failed to ensure that Hang Tung’s internal system in relation to operational controls was adequate. This gave rise to the opportunity for the account executive to manipulate the settlement process to avoid paying for the losses. As a result, Hang Tung suffered a loss of $3.8 million.", {"entities": [[0, 3, "PERSON"], [41, 50, "ORGANIZATION"], [74, 83, "ORGANIZATION"], [294, 303, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Despite his role as responsible officer, Goh failed to properly supervise the operation of the Accounts and Settlement Department at Hang Tung. This facilitated the use of sale proceeds due to another client to settle the account of the account executive’s sister by an accountant. Goh also failed to spot the inaccurate internal reports which were relied upon by the accountant to compile Hang Tung’s financial returns (Note 2).", {"entities": [[41, 44, "PERSON"], [133, 142, "ORGANIZATION"], [282, 285, "PERSON"], [390, 399, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has successfully prosecuted South China Holdings Ltd, South China Industries (BVI) Ltd, South China Industries Ltd, Wah Shing International Holdings Ltd, and Man Wah Trading Ltd under Part XV of the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [36, 60, "ORGANIZATION"], [62, 94, "ORGANIZATION"], [96, 122, "ORGANIZATION"], [124, 160, "ORGANIZATION"], [166, 185, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The five companies today pleaded guilty to 14 summonses in relation to their failure to make proper disclosures to both Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited and Pricerite Group Ltd of (i) their initial 7.82% interests in Pricerite Group Ltd on commencement of the SFO on 1 April 2003, and (ii) the increase of their interests in the shares of Pricerite Group Ltd on 19 August 2003.", {"entities": [[120, 160, "ORGANIZATION"], [165, 184, "ORGANIZATION"], [225, 244, "ORGANIZATION"], [347, 366, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The relevant shares of Pricerite Group Ltd were held by Man Wah Trading Ltd while the other four companies were taken to be interested in those shares by virtue of their control over Man Wah Trading Ltd.", {"entities": [[23, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [56, 75, "ORGANIZATION"], [183, 202, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Mr Eddie Yip, a Magistrate at Eastern Magistracy, fined the five companies a total of $28,000 and ordered South China Holdings Ltd to pay investigation costs of $12,991 to the SFC.", {"entities": [[3, 12, "PERSON"], [30, 48, "ORGANIZATION"], [106, 130, "ORGANIZATION"], [176, 179, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had publicly reprimanded {X} who was, until 3 May 1999, registered both under the Securities Ordinance as a dealing director of I & P Securities Limited (I & P) and under the Commodities Trading Ordinance as a commodities dealer accredited to I & P Commodities Ltd.", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [93, 96, "PERSON"], [196, 220, "ORGANIZATION"], [222, 227, "ORGANIZATION"], [311, 332, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The reprimand stems from an investigation in which the SFC found that {X} had allowed an employee of another broker to", {"entities": [[55, 58, "ORGANIZATION"], [70, 73, "PERSON"]]}], ["a) operate an account in his own name with I & P from February 1994 until March 1995; and", {"entities": [[43, 48, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["without first having notified I & P or obtained consent from the other broker. Furthermore, {X} failed to follow correct account opening procedures in that he signed as a witness to account opening documentation when he had neither witnessed the signing of the account opening documentation nor met the account holder.", {"entities": [[30, 35, "ORGANIZATION"], [92, 95, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC regards {X}'s accommodations as deserving of severe censure because it denied I & P the opportunity to fulfill its obligations under the Code of Conduct for persons registered with the SFC and thereby denied the broker's employer the ability to perform an effective compliance function because it was unable to monitor the activities of its staff.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [16, 19, "PERSON"], [86, 91, "ORGANIZATION"], [193, 196, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In deciding on this course of action, the SFC has taken into consideration the fact that {X} was required to resign from both I & P and I & P Commodities Ltd with effect from 3 May 1999 and has been unemployed since this date. Accordingly, the SFC views this as effectively a two month period of suspension which it considers appropriate in the circumstances of the case.", {"entities": [[89, 92, "PERSON"], [126, 131, "ORGANIZATION"], [136, 157, "ORGANIZATION"], [244, 247, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has issued a reprimand to Ms Yan Yuk Hing Liza and fined her $30,000 (Note 1).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [37, 54, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC found that between 10 and 23 April 2003, Yan received orders on her mobile phone after office hours on eight occasions from a new margin client who, at the time, did not have an established track record of settlement. None of these orders were recorded in the telephone recording system of Emperor Securities Limited. Yan failed to keep sufficiently accurate and contemporaneous written record of the client’s original orders.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [49, 52, "PERSON"], [298, 324, "ORGANIZATION"], [326, 329, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC today publishes the February issue of the SFC Enforcement Reporter, summarising the SFC’s enforcement action in the month of January 2004 and discussing the compliance issues highlighted by recent cases.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [50, 53, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In January, the SFC successfully prosecuted three persons for failure to assist SFC investigations. One of them was sentenced to two weeks’ jail in the first custodial sentence for such offence.", {"entities": [[16, 19, "ORGANIZATION"], [80, 83, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC disciplined eight licensees during the month for various regulatory breaches including misrepresentation of licensed status, failure to observe the \"Know your client\" rule, inadequate supervision, internal control failings, and inadequate audit trails.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["To increase transparency, apart from statistics on successful prosecutions and disciplinary actions taken, we have also published figures on acquittals and disciplinary proceedings that have been concluded without sanction. Since 1 April 2003, the SFC has successfully prosecuted 50 entities and there have been no acquittals. The SFC has also disciplined 73 licensees for regulatory breaches. Disciplinary proceedings have been taken against 11 licensees which were eventually discontinued with no formal sanction imposed. Such proceedings were also commenced and discontinued against another seven deemed licensees who left their firms before the conclusion of the actions.", {"entities": [[248, 251, "ORGANIZATION"], [331, 334, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Copies of the February issue of the SFC Enforcement Reporter are available at the SFC office. All issues are also available on the SFC website under \"Press Releases, Publications & Speeches\" – \"Publications\".", {"entities": [[36, 39, "ORGANIZATION"], [82, 85, "ORGANIZATION"], [131, 134, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The public are welcome to subscribe to the newsletter by registering for the SFC Website Update Email Alert service on the SFC's homepage. They will then be able to receive the newsletter via email.", {"entities": [[77, 80, "ORGANIZATION"], [123, 126, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The public are also invited to provide feedback so we can improve the SFC Enforcement Reporter. Comments can be emailed to enfreporter@hksfc.org.hk.", {"entities": [[70, 73, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has banned Mr Wong Sze Yiu, a former account executive of Core Pacific-Yamaichi International (H.K.) Limited (CPYI), from re-entering the industry for six months from 26 October 2015 to 25 April 2016 for failures in relation to managing a client’s account on a discretionary basis (Note 1).", {"entities": [[58, 70, "PERSON"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [4, 36, "ORGANIZATION"], [102, 152, "ORGANIZATION"], [154, 158, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The disciplinary action follows an investigation by the SFC which found that, from around February or March 2012 until September 2014, Wong conducted discretionary trading in a client’s account without obtaining her written authorization, and without the knowledge and approval of his employer.", {"entities": [[135, 139, "PERSON"], [56, 59, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Although the client verbally authorized Wong to trade in her account on a discretionary basis, the absence of written authorization prevented monitoring and supervision by Wong’s employer. The SFC considers that Wong’s conduct resulted in non-compliance with the regulatory requirements on the authorization and operation of a discretionary account under the Code of Conduct (Note 2).", {"entities": [[172, 176, "PERSON"], [212, 216, "PERSON"], [193, 196, "ORGANIZATION"], [40, 44, "PERSON"]]}], ["In deciding the sanction, the SFC took into account that Wong’s misconduct lasted for two and a half years, his clean disciplinary record and his cooperation with the SFC.", {"entities": [[30, 33, "ORGANIZATION"], [57, 61, "PERSON"], [167, 170, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court of Appeal has dismissed an appeal by Moody’s Investors Service Hong Kong Limited (Moody’s) against the Securities and Futures Appeals Tribunal’s (SFAT) decision to uphold the Securities and Futures Commission’s (SFC) disciplinary action in relation to a special comment report published by Moody’s in 2011 (Notes 1, 2 & 3).  ", {"entities": [[4, 19, "ORGANIZATION"], [47, 90, "ORGANIZATION"], [92, 99, "ORGANIZATION"], [113, 152, "ORGANIZATION"], [156, 160, "ORGANIZATION"], [185, 218, "ORGANIZATION"], [222, 225, "ORGANIZATION"], [300, 307, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFAT had affirmed the SFC’s decision to reprimand and fine Moody’s for breaching the Code of Conduct in its preparation and publication of the report entitled “Red Flags for Emerging-Market Companies: A Focus on China” (the Report) (Notes 4 & 5). ", {"entities": [[4, 8, "ORGANIZATION"], [26, 29, "ORGANIZATION"], [63, 70, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFAT, which had determined that the fine should be $11 million, ruled that Moody’s was carrying on its regulated activity of providing credit rating services on the basis that the preparation and publication of the Report formed part and parcel of the credit rating services provided by Moody’s.", {"entities": [[4, 8, "ORGANIZATION"], [79, 86, "ORGANIZATION"], [291, 298, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In dismissing the appeal, the Court of Appeal upheld the decision of the SFAT that misconduct on the part of Moody’s can be established on the basis that the preparation and publication of the Report was part and parcel of the carrying on of the business of credit ratings by Moody’s, and hence reaffirmed the SFC’s jurisdiction over Moody’s in this matter. ", {"entities": [[30, 45, "ORGANIZATION"], [73, 77, "ORGANIZATION"], [109, 116, "ORGANIZATION"], [276, 283, "ORGANIZATION"], [310, 313, "ORGANIZATION"], [334, 341, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC’s Chief Executive Officer, Mr Ashley Alder, said: \"The SFC considers that responsible research, including that issued by credit rating agencies and research houses, can all contribute to the overall market quality and price discovery process and has no intention to suppress legitimate commentaries on listed companies, whether positive or negative.\"", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [38, 50, "PERSON"], [63, 66, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\"The Moody’s case is about substandard work by a licensed person who is required to comply with the provisions set out in the Code of Conduct and uphold high standards of competence.  The recent ruling by the Market Misconduct Tribunal (MMT) concerning Citron Research also makes it clear that any person, whether licensed or not, who makes serious allegations about listed companies should be reasonably prudent in making them,\" Mr Alder added (Note 6).", {"entities": [[5, 12, "ORGANIZATION"], [237, 240, "ORGANIZATION"], [209, 235, "ORGANIZATION"], [433, 438, "PERSON"], [253, 268, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (\"SFC\"] and The Stock Exchange of Hong Kong Limited (the \"Exchange\"] jointly announce today (Tuesday) that they have taken action against Grand Fortune Securities & Investment Company Limited (\"Grand Fortune\"], a registered securities dealer and a Member of the Exchange, and {X}, a registered dealer's representative and an Authorised Clerk of the Exchange.", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [40, 43, "ORGANIZATION"], [50, 89, "ORGANIZATION"], [96, 104, "ORGANIZATION"], [176, 229, "ORGANIZATION"], [232, 245, "ORGANIZATION"], [300, 308, "ORGANIZATION"], [314, 317, "PERSON"], [387, 395, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The action stems from an inquiry in which it was found that during November 1996, {X}, a former registered dealer's representative and Authorised Clerk of Grand Fortune, had failed to guard against a client illegally shortselling shares and had concealed error trades from his then employer, Grand Fortune. The inquiry also revealed that Grand Fortune had inadequate internal controls and management supervision to properly detect and deter trading malpractices and employee negligence.", {"entities": [[155, 168, "ORGANIZATION"], [82, 85, "PERSON"], [292, 305, "ORGANIZATION"], [338, 351, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has decided to publicly reprimand:", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Grand Fortune and", {"entities": [[0, 13, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["{X},", {"entities": [[0, 3, "PERSON"]]}], ["In addition, the Disciplinary Committee of the Exchange (the \"Disciplinary Committee\"] has decided to public censure Grand Fortune and {X}, and also fine Grand Fortune HK$20,000 and {X} HK$3,000.", {"entities": [[47, 55, "ORGANIZATION"], [117, 130, "ORGANIZATION"], [135, 138, "PERSON"], [182, 185, "PERSON"]]}], ["Mr Patrick Huen Wing Ming (\"Mr Huen\"], as Grand Fortune's Dealing Director, and Ms Florence Huen Lai Ping (\"Ms Huen\"], as Grand Fortune's dealing manager, have accepted responsibility for Grand Fortune's inadequacies and have made a written apology to the SFC in respect of this. They have also expressed regret for initially taking an unnecessarily hostile approach to the SFC's proposed course of action rather than cooperating constructively with the SFC.", {"entities": [[3, 25, "PERSON"], [31, 35, "PERSON"], [42, 55, "ORGANIZATION"], [83, 105, "PERSON"], [111, 115, "PERSON"], [122, 135, "ORGANIZATION"], [188, 201, "ORGANIZATION"], [256, 259, "ORGANIZATION"], [374, 377, "ORGANIZATION"], [454, 457, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In deciding upon this course of action, the SFC and the Disciplinary Committee noted that Mr Huen and Ms Huen had commissioned a leading accountancy firm to conduct a comprehensive review of the entire dealing system and the internal control system of Grand Fortune. The recommendations of this review have been implemented to tighten internal controls to prevent future abuses by their employees and to form a more efficient and manageable securities dealing business. The SFC and the Disciplinary Committee further noted that Grand Fortune has significantly improved its internal control system and management supervision since April 1997.", {"entities": [[44, 47, "ORGANIZATION"], [93, 97, "PERSON"], [105, 109, "PERSON"], [252, 265, "ORGANIZATION"], [474, 477, "ORGANIZATION"], [528, 541, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has banned Mr Wong Wing Fai Eric, a former licensed representative of Shun Loong Securities Company Limited, from re-entering the industry for five years until 9 January 2011 for conflicts of interest (Note 1). The penalty is the result of a settlement between Wong and the SFC.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [22, 40, "PERSON"], [78, 115, "ORGANIZATION"], [269, 273, "PERSON"], [282, 285, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC commenced an inquiry into Wong’s conduct after receiving a complaint from Shun Loong in May 2004. The SFC found that, from December 2003 to April 2004, Wong had put himself in a position of a conflict of interest by trading substantial amounts of securities which were the subject matter of the research reports he prepared for Shun Loong staff. Some of his trades were contrary to the recommendations in his research reports.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [34, 38, "PERSON"], [82, 92, "ORGANIZATION"], [110, 113, "ORGANIZATION"], [160, 164, "PERSON"], [336, 346, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC concludes that Wong has been guilty of misconduct and his fitness and properness has been called into question.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [23, 27, "PERSON"]]}], ["In deciding the penalty and coming into a settlement with Wong, the SFC has taken into account that:", {"entities": [[58, 62, "PERSON"], [68, 71, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["the penalty reflects the seriousness of Wong’s repeated misconduct;Wong frankly admitted his guilt; andWong co-operated with the SFC and accepted a resolution of the disciplinary action by settlement, which saved the SFC’s resources.", {"entities": [[129, 132, "ORGANIZATION"], [217, 220, "ORGANIZATION"], [40, 44, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC considers the settlement to be in the interest of the investing public and in the public interest.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “The market expects securities analysts to provide objective, independent and unbiased recommendations which accurately reflect the prospects of target companies. It is vital to the maintenance of investor confidence that analysts act with high standards of integrity when producing their reports.”", {"entities": [[3, 15, "PERSON"], [17, 20, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["“Paragraph 16 of the Code of Conduct regulating analyst conflicts of interest came into force on 1 April 2005. Analysts are reminded to comply with the trading restrictions imposed by paragraph 16. These include prohibitions on trading contrary to outstanding recommendations and on trading during the blackout period (Note 2). Firms that employ analysts are reminded that they must have in place internal control procedures to eliminate actual or potential conflicts of interest involving analysts. We are pleased to note that Shun Loong detected Wong’s misconduct and reported it to us. We encourage other firms to follow suit if they detect similar misconduct by their employees. The SFC will continue to take appropriate actions against analysts and their employers who fail to comply with the regulatory requirements,” Mr Linning added.", {"entities": [[528, 538, "ORGANIZATION"], [548, 552, "PERSON"], [687, 690, "ORGANIZATION"], [827, 834, "PERSON"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announces today that it has suspended the licence of Mr Lam Ting Ping (Lam), a representative licensed under the Leveraged Foreign Exchange Trading Ordinance (LFETO), for a period of three weeks.", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [100, 113, "PERSON"], [115, 118, "PERSON"], [157, 201, "ORGANIZATION"], [203, 208, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC’s action stemmed from an investigation into Lam’s trading activities, which had been conducted for a client on discretionary basis. Such activities contravened Lam’s licence condition which prohibits him from conducting discretionary account services for his clients.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [52, 55, "PERSON"], [168, 171, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC concluded that Lam, in breaching his licence condition, was guilty of misconduct as defined in section 12[7)(b) of the LFETO. In the SFC’s view, Lam’s misconduct cast doubt on his fitness and properness to remain licensed.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [23, 26, "PERSON"], [127, 132, "ORGANIZATION"], [141, 144, "ORGANIZATION"], [153, 156, "PERSON"]]}], ["In imposing a three-week suspension on Lam, the SFC took into account Lam’s:", {"entities": [[39, 42, "PERSON"], [48, 51, "ORGANIZATION"], [70, 73, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC wishes to reiterate that any breach of a licence condition constitutes misconduct and licensees found guilty of misconduct will be sanctioned accordingly.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) announced today that it had suspended the registration of Mr Ng Kei Choy, Stephen (Ng), a registered securities dealer under the Securities Ordinance (SO) accredited to Sun Growth Securities Limited as its dealing director, for a period of two weeks. ", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [105, 125, "PERSON"], [127, 129, "PERSON"], [213, 242, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC considers that the above matters impugned Ng's fitness and properness as a registered person and decided to suspend his registration. In deciding this course of action the SFC has taken into account that Ng has been very co-operative with the SFC's inquiry and these matters happened more than two years ago.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [50, 52, "PERSON"], [180, 183, "ORGANIZATION"], [212, 214, "PERSON"], [251, 254, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court of First Instance has allowed the Securities and Futures Commission’s (SFC) appeal against the acquittal of Mr Wong Hung of illegal short selling and ordered that the case be remitted back to the Magistrates’ Court for a re-trial.", {"entities": [[4, 27, "ORGANIZATION"], [81, 84, "ORGANIZATION"], [44, 77, "ORGANIZATION"], [121, 130, "PERSON"], [206, 224, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In May 2014, the Eastern Magistrates’ Court acquitted Wong on charges of illegal short selling in shares of five listed companies.  The Magistrate found that because Wong placed a lot of orders each day, the possibility of Wong being careless about whether he was selling or attempting to sell more shares than he held could not be excluded, and therefore the prosecution had not proved its case beyond reasonable doubt (Note 1).", {"entities": [[17, 43, "ORGANIZATION"], [54, 58, "PERSON"], [166, 170, "PERSON"], [223, 227, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC subsequently lodged an appeal to the Court of First Instance against the Magistrate’s decision.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [45, 68, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court of First Instance ruled in favour of the SFC, stating in a judgment that the Magistrate’s decision was perverse in that no reasonable magistrate, applying his mind to the proper considerations and giving himself the proper directions, would have reached the same conclusion.", {"entities": [[4, 27, "ORGANIZATION"], [51, 54, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Court also ordered that Wong’s case be remitted back to the Magistrates’ Court to be tried by a different magistrate.  No date has been set for the hearing at the Magistrates’ Court (Note 2).", {"entities": [[4, 9, "ORGANIZATION"], [28, 32, "PERSON"], [64, 82, "ORGANIZATION"], [167, 185, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC is studying the Court’s judgment.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [24, 29, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has reprimanded {X}, a dealer's representative of Phillip Securities (HK) Ltd registered under the Securities Ordinance.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [24, 27, "PERSON"], [58, 85, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC started an inquiry into {X}’s conduct after receiving a complaint from one of his clients. In or about October 2001, {X} made a proposal to the client to deposit $30,000 into the client's account with Phillip and to allow him to exercise discretion in buying and selling stock warrants in the account, which is contrary to Phillip’s internal policies. {X} did not ask the client to provide him with a written authorisation, thereby breaching the SFC’s Code of Conduct, although Phillip’s internal policies would not have allowed him to carry out discretionary trades even with the written authorisation.  Between October 2001 and February 2002, {X} had conducted more than 20 discretionary trades in the client’s account.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [32, 35, "PERSON"], [125, 128, "PERSON"], [209, 216, "ORGANIZATION"], [360, 363, "PERSON"], [331, 338, "ORGANIZATION"], [454, 457, "ORGANIZATION"], [486, 493, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["{X} has breached:", {"entities": [[0, 3, "PERSON"]]}], ["Phillip's internal policies which prohibited its staff from exercising discretion for clients. ", {"entities": [[0, 7, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC concludes that {X} is guilty of misconduct and his fitness and properness has been called into question. The SFC has therefore decided to publicly reprimand him.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [23, 26, "PERSON"], [117, 120, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Mr Alan Linning, SFC's Executive Director of Enforcement, said: “Registered persons must not operate a client's account on a discretionary basis without getting written authorisation from the client. Verbal authorisation is not acceptable and cannot provide sufficient protection to both the client and the registered person when disputes arise. The SFC will punish anyone who acts without written authority.”", {"entities": [[3, 15, "PERSON"], [17, 20, "ORGANIZATION"], [350, 353, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has suspended the licence of {X} as a representative for four months under the Securities and Futures Ordinance (SFO) for misconduct relating to hawking of futures contracts. {X} is suspended from 15 December 2004 to 14 April 2005 (Note 1).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [37, 40, "PERSON"], [183, 186, "PERSON"]]}], ["The suspension follows {X}’s conviction at the Eastern Magistracy of hawking of futures contracts contrary to the Commodities Trading Ordinance (Note 2).", {"entities": [[23, 26, "PERSON"], [47, 65, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["From around April 2001 to December 2002, {X} made unsolicited calls to prospective clients by way of telephone calls and visits in person to promote the trading of futures contracts on commodities exchanges in Japan. {X} gave the prospective clients promotional materials and recommendations to buy the futures contracts through his employer. {X} asked each of the clients to open an account with his employer to trade futures contracts.", {"entities": [[217, 220, "PERSON"], [343, 346, "PERSON"]]}], ["The SFC inquiry into the misconduct of {X} found that he failed to comply with relevant law and regulations. The SFC concludes that {X}’s fitness and properness has been called into question and decides to suspend him.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "PERSON"], [132, 135, "PERSON"], [113, 116, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["In determining {X}’s penalty, the SFC has taken into account of {X}’s co-operation and his genuine remorse for his misconduct. {X} received a shorter suspension than the SFC had originally proposed because he admitted that his actions were wrong.", {"entities": [[34, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [15, 18, "PERSON"], [64, 67, "PERSON"], [127, 130, "PERSON"], [170, 173, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["Mr Alan Linning, SFC’s Executive Director of Enforcement, said: \"Under the SFO, any call made not by express invitation of the person called upon with a view to inducing that person to enter into an agreement to purchase or sell regulated investment products is a criminal offence. It is important for a licensed representative to understand and recognise what constitutes an unsolicited call and to exercise due care to ensure that his or her marketing effort and strategies comply with the law.\"", {"entities": [[3, 15, "PERSON"], [17, 20, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has reprimanded Ms Winnie Pang Wai Yan and fined her $120,000 for negligence in handling a client’s trade orders (Note 1).", {"entities": [[4, 37, "ORGANIZATION"], [39, 42, "ORGANIZATION"], [63, 82, "PERSON"]]}], ["Pang was a client advisor assistant at UBS AG at the material time. In December 2009, a client at UBS AG wanted to sell his shares in a stock to an identified buyer at agreed amounts and prices through manual cross trades. Instead of placing cross trades as initially instructed by the client, Pang coordinated with the buyer to conduct a series of on-exchange matched trades between 3 and 8 December 2009 (Note 2).", {"entities": [[0, 4, "PERSON"], [39, 45, "ORGANIZATION"], [98, 104, "ORGANIZATION"], [294, 298, "PERSON"]]}], ["\t- report the matter to the Compliance Department of UBS AG; and", {"entities": [[53, 59, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC considers that Pang’s failures called into question her fitness and properness as a registered person.", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [23, 27, "PERSON"]]}], ["In deciding the disciplinary sanction, the SFC took into account:", {"entities": [[43, 46, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- Pang’s financial situation;", {"entities": [[3, 7, "PERSON"]]}], ["\t- that Pang did not make any personal benefit out of the transactions in question;", {"entities": [[8, 12, "PERSON"]]}], ["\t- that Pang co-operated with the SFC in resolving the disciplinary action; and", {"entities": [[8, 12, "PERSON"], [34, 37, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["\t- that Pang has an otherwise clean disciplinary record with the SFC.", {"entities": [[8, 12, "PERSON"], [65, 68, "ORGANIZATION"]]}], ["The SFC has prohibited Mr Chau Sik Ki from applying to be a licensed representative or seeking to act as a relevant individual for a registered institution for four months from 26 April 2006 to 25 August 2006 (Note 1).", {"entities": [[4, 7, "ORGANIZATION"], [26, 37, "PERSON"]]}], ["The disciplinary action follows Chau’s conviction after trial for making unsolicited calls inducing a person to enter into agreement to trade in futures contracts while acting as a 